<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: space miami | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/space-miami/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-10-03T02:17:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes you hit it.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/05/sometimes-you-hit-it/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T02:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/05/sometimes-you-hit-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ldw-4518.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn at Space'" ></p>

<p>Sometimes you nail it, sometimes you don't. You're not always going to score the perfect shot each and every time.</p>

<p>I think a lot of people who pick up a camera get hung up on that. While yes, you try to capture the best image you can at a given moment, sometimes you have to work with what is there.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And sometimes that has to be enough.</p>

<p>Nightlife and concert photography straddles a line between photojournalism and staged photo performance. You can have as much control or as little control as you want in a lot of cases.</p>

<p>Take the image above for example. It is one of the quintessential elements of the modern nightclub, the dancer. Jordyn here is one of the regular girls at Space these days. Through a combination of knowing how my images come out, and being expertly lit by Space's lighting designers, the image here straddles the line between a "spur of the moment" shot and a staged image. It is a spur-of-the-moment since I usually don't request specific lighting cues for the dancers at Space. I could, since I maintain a good rapport with Dennis, Gabriel, and Mike, but they have their "canvas" to work their art on and I'd feel like I was interfering if I constantly requested specific lighting cues. Their goal is to light Jordyn in the most flattering way possible, and they succeed, so I leave it at that. When her or any of the other girls get up on the box, I know they will be lit well. So, it is staged, yes, but staged without the interference of me coordinating the lighting.</p>

<p>Now, on occasion, I will ask for specifics from the techs, of course. If I'm assigned to capture a specific image of a performer or DJ, then we will plan ahead. Staging the image gets me paid, and makes for a happy client. However, it's certainly not photojournalism.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ldw-4573.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Reboot aka Frank at Space'" ></p>

<p>My preference is to work with what is there, usually. I like to document the scene as it is. For example, the image of Reboot (Frank) above. What you see is what was actually happening. Frank was lining up his tracks for the next mix as the sun was rising over the Terrace at Space. No fancy lighting tricks, as a matter of fact, Gabriel had left to go to the bathroom and the lighting console was temporarily unmanned. Aesthetically, the image comes together, even though there may be some technical failings. Some may argue there's a little too much noise in the image, or that the red light is a little too blotchy. However, the image was captured of one of the headliners of the morning doing his work on the decks, and the compelling nature comes from the overall composition of the image, with Frank being dominant, and the panopoly of gear adding to the atmosphere of the image, and of course, the teeming masses of people on the dancefloor below. A viewer would want to know more about what happened there, regardless of the noise or slight color issues. I documented what was there within the limits of my equipment, and I'd like to think I pulled it off. I didn't use a flash to blow out the scene, nor did I call on one of the techs to light the booth just for me, even though I will do that on occasion. However, that wasn't one of those occasions.</p>

<p>I worked with what I had on hand, and that was enough. At the end of the day, this presents the most accurate image of what a photographer sees. In an age of extensive photoshop work and manipulation, it's the least any of us can do. Everyone has their own ideas and tastes about what to do in a club or concert situation, it just so happens mine is to work with what I have, and take it from there. Anything else, in my mind, is distorting reality, and I'd like to think I'm here to document reality through my vision. And sometimes the reality is that the situation is staged, and sometimes it isn't. I think I'm safe in an ethical sense, since I'm documenting a staged situation, which usually isn't staged for my benefit. They are pointing high-powered LED fixtures at Jordyn for the benefit of the audience, not myself. I just take advantage of the situation and fire away. While with Frank, he is not specifically lit to an ideal, but what I had to work with there was enough, as it had to be.</p>

<p>Work with what is there, and sometimes it has to be enough.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fear of photography?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/21/a-fear-of-photography/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T12:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/21/a-fear-of-photography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ferrer-2724.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'I can seeeeee you!'" ></p>

<p>Local photojournalist and all-around good guy <a href="http://www.pixiq.com/contributors/248">Carlos Miller</a> got me thinking recently after the last <a href="http://www.pixiq.com/article/four-cop-cars-get-called-on-us">photo protest</a> he staged in front of the Miami Herald building.</p>

<p>A lot of people have a fear of photography. And I really can't figure out why. Sure, for some people I can see it. They're doing something they probably shouldn't be, and there's scads of photographic recording devices around them, which may or may not be recording their actions. I encounter it out in the clubs from time to time. I like to shoot wide, as you can see above, and I may inadvertently capture someone doing something (or someone, ba-dum-ching...) they shouldn't be.</p>

<p>It certainly isn't deliberate on my part though. Whatever transgressions you may be committing, that's your problem and not mine. I'm not out to ruin your life, since it appears that you're quite capable of doing that on your own. And no, I won't delete it. You are a noisy red smear at the bottom of the frame. And you probably shouldn't be cheating on your pretty wife in front of thousands of people and about that many cameras.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>But, that's just with crackheads in nightclubs, which, fortunately, form a small minority of our population.</p>

<p>The real head-scratcher is the people who get worked up over photography in public places. If you can see it from a public location, you can shoot it, it's that simple. I don't buy the national security bit or anything of that nature. If I take a photo of the refinery near Fort Lauderdale airport, the photo, other than a creative piece, tells me nothing. It's a collection of pipes. It won't aid a terrorist in planning to blow it up. And, if a terrorist wants to blow up the refinery, a photo isn't going to hinder or help him or her too much. It's not like in the movies where they can deduce where the 2-meter wide exhaust vent is from a cell phone photo.</p>

<p>Even more puzzling are the ordinary citizens who bring it upon themselves to get worked up over photos in public places. The photo protest I mentioned is a perfect example. In a nutshell, the ordinary citizen was a security guard, who took it upon himself to misquote the law, leading to the situation described in Carlos' blog entry. Now, a few words on that.</p>

<p>A security guard is an ordinary citizen. He doesn't have police powers. As a matter of fact, he's even more restricted from certain actions in the course of his job than an ordinary citizen is. The industry's slogan is "Observe and Report". That's about all they can do. Plus, from a pragmatic perspective, the pay scale isn't high enough to justify more than that. If I was working the front desk at the Herald, I'd either ignore it and get back to my Youtube viewing, or just kick it upstairs and let the bureaucrats in facilities deal with it. Yes, I'm being totally lazy and "not dedicated", but for $12/hr and no benefits, you're only going to get so much out of me. I'd rather spend my effort on something more meaningful, ya know?</p>

<p>Getting worked up about people shooting photos in public places is a complete waste of one's energy. There's so much more out there to expend effort on. Plus, if you think about it, the camera is ubiquitous now. If something is not recorded, that is an unusual set of circumstances indeed. In a society such as ours, there's at least one camera recording the scene at all times in any given public location. The ethics of such ubiquitous recording? Well, that's another debate entirely.</p>

<p>But such recording shouldn't be feared. If you don't want it recorded, don't put it in a public location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
