<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: miami | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/miami/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T20:39:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some of us are more than that guy with the camera.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/pete-5469.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn on the box at Space'" ></p>

<p>Sometimes when I think about what to put here too much, I'm at a loss. I can't force myself to write. Usually, when I drop an article in here, it's in relation to something I've done, read, or saw. This blog is very reactive and not proactive right now, I guess. This post is definitely reactive.</p>

<p>A few minutes ago, I read a blog entry by local shooter <a href="http://helloimscott.com/">Scott Alexander</a> on how he's burnt out on his primary subject, erotica and fetish, but not for the reasons you would think.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In the <a href="http://helloimscott.com/2012/09/adapting-new-battle-strategies/">blog post</a>, he sums it up eloquently:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>But it’s more than just being burnt out from this business. It’s so many different things. I tire of people looking at me sideways or making assumptions about me and my life. I tire of the judgement. I tire, when meeting someone new, that because someone else has said something to them, they’ve already made up in their mind what I’m all about and don’t even TALK to me with any kind of respect. I tire of not being taken seriously.</p><footer><strong>Scott Alexander</strong> <cite><a href='http://helloimscott.com/2012/09/adapting-new-battle-strategies/'>Adapting New Battle Strategies</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>In a nutshell (correct me if I'm wrong Scott), it seems he is tired of being judged as a smut-peddler, when there's so much more to what he does.</p>

<p>Now, to a lesser extent, I encounter this on occasion when I talk to people about what I do, regardless of whether I meet them inside or outside of the club environment. Without sounding pretentious I like to think that I put my own spin on the images I capture. Since I have the luxury (haha) of running my own site, I have complete freedom to capture the images how I want them. Of course, I have to make some concessions with the client (that is why you will see photos that look like "typical" club shots), but I do have the flexibility to shoot what I want as well.</p>

<p>Part of the reason I can do that is the amount of time I've been rattling around Miami's club scene, which, by my watch, is around 15 years at this point. That's an eternity. I've been around longer than almost every venue in town, and most promoters and DJs. I got started in this when the post of 'club photographer' was a rare thing. And since it was rare, I was able to set the tone for myself, i.e. I wasn't under the gun to shoot 100000 images of drunk girls, and as time went on, even the people who wanted me to do so, ended up conceding, or moving on to someone who would shoot 10000 images of drunk girls.</p>

<p>In a nutshell that explains why I'm not rich off of photography and have to do web-related odd jobs to pay for things. Making money from producing just the photos (or any art for that matter) you want is extremely challenging.</p>

<p>In this modern era, I would probably not be able to score a single club-related photo gig if I was starting out. Simply because there's too many people/sites willing to shoot 10000 drunk-girl images for cheap, and almost zero demand for any sort of artistry in the photos captured. Nightclubs just want photos for social network promotion. And hey, they're running a business, and it costs an obscene amount of money to run it. FYI, a large nightclub costs around $30,000 a night sans DJ fees just to operate! So yeah, they kind of need people to show up.</p>

<p>Fortunately, I've got work via my veteran status and longtime connects, but if I had to do it all over again today (with the same eye/mindset), I probably wouldn't do it at all.</p>

<p>However, many would and are doing it. They will shoot 10000 photos a night of drunk girls with their cameras on "P" or green mode. Fire away, give 'em the little card, and move on to the next target. And annoy the DJ while they are at it.</p>

<p>And unfortunately, since this type of photographer is ubiquitous to the club scene, I'm sometimes lumped into the same mold as they are. Much as Scott is probably lumped into the same mold as whomever does the shooting for Bangbus, even though their material is worlds apart.</p>

<p>I see it sometimes, when people ask me what I shoot, and I try my best to sugarcoat it. "Yes, I shoot special events, concerts, and nightlife...". Which basically means I spend time taking photos in loud, hot, smoky rooms filled to the gills with drunk people.</p>

<p>However, even in those loud, smoky, drunk rooms, there's ample opportunity to compose and capture aesthetically pleasing images. The image up top is one example.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ldw-4558.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn again - yes, I shoot her a lot'" ></p>

<p>This would be another. In my humble opinion, this isn't a side of nightlife that people normally notice. And I like to capture that, to show those rare moments when something visually amazing happens for a split second, in a place most people consider just a loud, hot, smoky, drunk room.</p>

<p>It's why I carry sample images on my iPhone of what I'm able to do. If I can hold someone's attention for five seconds before they run away, since they judge me as being "That guy with the camera in the club...", I usually show them just what I mean. Then their opinions change.</p>

<p>However, on occasion the whole issue does get tiring. Which is why I've branched out into shooting scenics recently. Now, it's not to force myself to shoot something I don't like. I really do like scenics. On occasion in the past I've shot some rather stunning ones. But nowadays, I've actually begun to market myself as being able to do that as well. The nice thing is, I'm able to spring that as a surprise on the unsuspecting critic.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<p>Plus it's pretty relaxing. I actually took this photo and then just sat down under the bridge for an hour afterwards.</p>

<p>This last piece has actually sold a few copies over on my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com">FAA page</a>. And when I show it to a critic who lumps me in with the likes of the unscrupulous run-and-gun shooters, they usually get quite embarrassed.</p>

<p>However, even if they do walk away, I don't mind. I still find enjoyment in shooting nightlife and events. The varied situations, the challenge of shooting in dark rooms, the dynamics, and getting to see some friends of mine all contribute to that, even after fifteen years. The burnout feeling comes and goes, but for the most part, it goes. Sometimes when I want to just stop, I'll find some glimmer (no kids, 'glimmer' is not the name of a new drug!) that keeps me going. Aside from the fact that I can't argue with the money, of course.</p>

<p>I'll be at Space tonight/tomorrow morning around 3 AM for one of the few good DJs left in the scene, Roger Sanchez. If anyone from here reads this and is there, come and say hello. I'll explain more in detail time permitting.</p>

<p>Scott, if you're reading, don't take any guff from those swine. You've got a great body of work, and it speaks for itself. If anything drop on them your collection from driving across the country and back on a scooter. That was amazing.</p>

<p>Sidebar: I drove across the country once. It was in a moving van equipped with an first-gen iPad 3G, 3 diverse smartphones, a cooler full of rations, and spares for everything. Halfway through I wanted to blow up the moving van and take my camera backpack, iPad, and some clothes and go buy a cheap scooter and finish the ride that way by going the scenic route. I'm gonna figure out how to make these sidebars on the side, soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You need to think fourth-dimensionally, Marty!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/you-need-to-think-fourth-dimensionally-marty/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T12:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/you-need-to-think-fourth-dimensionally-marty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/49508063" width="960" height="540" frameborder="1" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/49508063">• Season 8 Finals - Jive With The Band •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>I'm relearning the fine art of video editing. I learned on an analog system (real film!) though the concepts carry over. It's all about the story.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My current weapon of choice for editing is Final Cut Pro X. While the dyed-in-the-wool digital video types give it hell for being too much like iMovie and not a "real" pro product like it was, I find FCP-X suits my fancy for the basic video projects I'm doing myself at the moment. Like I've mentioned in the past, I usually just shoot, and pass my results off to someone with more editing and VFX skills like <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com/">Alex and his team over at Deepsleep</a>. However, even they use Final Cut Pro X for their final editing workflow.</p>

<p>In the end, an edit is an edit. You're trying to tell a story, and all the VFX goodies and title transitions in the world won't help if your timing and sequencing is off. That's actually something that takes years to master. I know in my head where I want to go with the story, I'm still just learning the modern tools of the trade. So yes, sometimes my edits are "off". It's a work in progress.</p>

<p>You have to think fourth-dimensionally. When shooting and when editing. You have to have an idea of what you want to shoot, and during the edit, what you have in your "bin". In an event like Jive, the regular repeat singers often perform twice throughout the night, once in the beginning, and once near the end to really knock the crowd out. I have to remember that sometimes I'll have "better" footage of say, Sir Diego, from later on in the night, even if his first performance knocked it out of the park. Sometimes it's the reverse actually. Either way, I have to keep in mind I have multiple takes. Keeping the bin coherent is key.</p>

<p>And this is just on the video side. The audio side is a whole other ball of wax. I record with a basic Sennheiser stereo mic, though I do want to progress to one of their wireless kits where I take a feed straight from the FOH mixer at the bar. That is a $600 investment though, and I'm currently not shooting enough live music events to justify the outlay. It's an amazing widget regardless, though.</p>

<p>Regardless, if you are a photographer getting into video, just remember to think fourth-dimensionally. You are composing a project that exists not only in space, but in time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When did the DJ become more important than the crowd?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/12/when-did-the-dj-become-more-important-than-the-crowd/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-12T11:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/12/when-did-the-dj-become-more-important-than-the-crowd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/pete-5312.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Thanks!'" ></p>

<p>A random blog post over at <a href="http://www.faithfanzine.com/?p=1590">Faith Fanzine</a> caught my eye today. One quote from the article summed it up:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>When did we start watching a DJ instead of dancing with our mates , why do we put up with idiotic people taking up the floor who are filming the DJ ,why is the best dance floors now being cut to ribbons to provide extra table space for naff VIP’s ( Pacha in Ibiza hang your head in shame ) ,people with more money than taste and who in some extreme situations in the US have had DJs thrown off the decks because they did not like the music .</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Yes, when did we stop dancing?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>I can't dance, that's a given. I pop around and do monkey moves, get embarrassed, and then I shuffle off to the side. But in the end, I'm still interacting with the crowd and my friends, and squeezing in a few photo ops as I mix and mingle. I take a few (OK a lot in some cases!) photos of the DJ, but I'm not in the middle of the dancefloor gawking at the booth the entire night.</p>

<p>It's actually part of the reason I prefer clubs to the current form of dance music experience, the festival/concert setup.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://seenightlife.com/photos/5595/original_MIA-6086.jpg" width="427" height="640"></p>

<p>In those setups, there is a stage, and a general admission "pit", much like a rock concert. The setup works well for rock concerts, since the whole point of a live musical act performing on stage is so you can see them work their instruments and sing. The act of a DJ mixing, no matter what tools they use, is generally a very passive act, and doesn't lend itself much to a rock-performance aesthetic, no matter how much jumping around and handwaving the DJ is doing. Anything more than that (I'm looking at you, Aoki), smacks of being too contrived and "trying too hard". Essentially the guy playing other people's music in the club has been placed in the center of a stage usually reserved for rockstars. And no matter how many pretty LED screens and image-mapped 3D renderings one throws up there, it comes down to that he's still up there playing back prerecorded sounds in a predetermined sequence. And a lot of DJs in concert situations don't even alter their playlists much from date to date. Zero musical flexibility. Might as well put an iPhone up there and play a prerecorded mix.</p>

<p>Plus, the shows are often at capacity, so there is actually zero room for dancing, and certainly no room for social interaction, since everyone is either focused on the guy pressing play on their laptop, or has their head buried in their phone, stroking their ego on Facebook.</p>

<p>I'm generally regarded as a borderline sociopathic personality. However, I do value social interaction when I'm out for a night of entertainment. It's why I value the few clubs left that actually encourage social discourse and interaction. Venues in town like Space, the Vagabond, and so forth, while they book DJ talent, don't rely on the DJ exclusively to drive their business. Some of my best nights out have been with the local guys on the decks, and I'm just there with my friends, having a good time. Some DJs still get it. <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/pete-tong-at-space">Pete Tong</a> is a great example. This past weekend, he took to the decks at Space. No grandstanding, no tricks, he just played a great soundtrack to a night/morning out, and the crowd responded in kind. People were dancing, socializing, and having a good time, but not buried in their phones or gawking at the booth for hours on end. So there's hope...</p>

<p>Let's save the rockstar setup for the rockstars.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wynwood Artwalk Too Hot To Handle?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T23:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/artwalk.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Artwalk Wynwood Artwalk Miami'" ></p>

<p>Though I guess I could be considered part of the Miami art community, I almost never go to Artwalk in Wynwood. I'm usually busy Saturday nights, or I consider my rare downtime more valuable than bouncing from gallery to gallery, most of which probably wouldn't exhibit anything I do. Photography is sort of underrepresented at Artwalk, but that's for another rant.</p>

<p>So anyways, the rare times I go to it are last-minute call-ups like I did earlier tonight.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I got a text from my good friend <strong>Emi Guerra</strong>, he wanted to go out and cruise Artwalk and meet some of the Miami art community to tell them about his forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>, the big music and art festival taking place on December 8th and 9th during Art Basel. The big announcement of the lineup is Monday, even though it has been leaked. So I won't post it here since you can find it <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/">elsewhere.</a>.</p>

<p>But anyways, he wanted to go out and see the artists and art people. Makes sense if you are throwing an art-oriented festival. And, since I'm kinda in touch with these people (am I?) he invited me along.</p>

<p>So, I jumped into the 210 and zipped on down Biscayne to Wynwood.</p>

<p>Once I got to the area, what a bloody mission. Traffic was at a gridlocked standstill, and there were throngs of people out and about, to the point where Northwest 2nd Avenue was a pedestrian thoroughfare. I was supposed to meet Emi and his UR1 team at Wynwood Walls, and I ended up having to park about seven blocks away. I'm a healthy boy now so it's no big deal, but it's the principle. And I will not valet. The 210 isn't an SLS or an E 63, but it's my baby and no one except me and the crew at <a href="http://masterclassauto.com/">Masterclass Auto</a> touches the steering wheel.</p>

<p>Some have called for the major streets of Wynwood to be closed off to automotive traffic during Artwalk. 100 percent, yes. Please. Do this. Commissioner Sarnoff, it's your district (for now), make it happen. The cops have their hands full pushing vehicular and pedestrian traffic around, and it's a complete cluster down there, and it actually hampers the enjoyment of Artwalk.</p>

<p>So yes, Artwalk has truly exploded into a Miami social phenomenon. We officially have an art scene here as far as I'm concerned. Go us.</p>

<p>However, I finally did get situated, and met Emi, along with UR1's Jackie Richie, Emi's assistant Andrea, Alex Martinez of <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Deepsleep</a>, and a few other scene people I know at Wynwood Walls, which was "at capacty" and had this weird dining area with a velvet rope and such set up.</p>

<p>They gotta update the artwork there. It's been the same since I last went to Artwalk (oddly enough with Emi's brother, Eddy) over two years ago. I'll paint a wall. It won't be anything "arty", but it will be something from my mind. I'll mention it here even.</p>

<p>As I mentioned earlier, everyone was out in force. Now, was everyone into the art? Hardly. Most people "Artwalking" couldn't tell you if that was a piece by Nagelbett or Britto. They are out for the social experience. Emi phrased it best when he said, "They are out for something to do, and it's cheap to go to Artwalk. Shit is expensive these days..."</p>

<p>He hit the nail on the head. Shit is expensive these days. Dinner for two will run you $100 or more. A night out at a club, even Space, will run you $100 per person (drinks, cover, and so on) or more if you VIP it. Having fun costs money!</p>

<p>But not at Artwalk. The galleries often have cash bars and/or free (albeit low-quality) booze on hand. They usually arrange a sponsorship or something. And the food trucks are out in force, and the food is cheap, though I wouldn't necessarily trust it. Yeah, the modern food trucks have all the amenities, but it's still a food truck, ya know? We called 'em the "roach coaches" back in Jersey. Note to food truck owners, I'm not saying that your food truck has roaches. If you're that concerned about what I said, you probably have something to hide. Be confident in your product and people talking shit, like me, won't affect your business. Let freedom ring.</p>

<p>But yes, anyways, people are out for Artwalk because it's cheap, interesting, and there's a good social dynamic. And the galleries and artists put up with it since it will get their works exposed to the five percent of the people who actually know their art and are in a position to do something about it.</p>

<p>And yes, please block off the streets. Artwalk is now truly a "phenomenon" and it needs to be handled properly. Our art scene is finally getting some worldwide respect, and it'd be a shame if logistical squabbles killed off a major component of it.</p>

<p>Maybe I should run for the City Commission and make Artwalk one of my campaign platforms...</p>

<p>Dan Vidal For District 2 Commissioner!</p>

<p>Sidebar: Yes, I'm aware the issues mentioned here are old. But these first few articles on my blog are kind of for SEO purposes, as well as stuff that is on my mind, regardless of when it happened. It's my blog, after all.</p>

<p>Sidebar 2: Yes, this devolved into a rant. In a nutshell, I did have fun at Artwalk. The food truck area is a great concept. Get 'em all in one place. Also, good seeing the <a href="http://car2go.com/">Miami Car2Go</a> people out...thanks for the T-shirt guys.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I guess I am becoming a car guy?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/31/i-guess-i-am-becoming-a-car-guy/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-31T15:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/31/i-guess-i-am-becoming-a-car-guy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/210hella960.jpg" width="960" height="360" title="'210 Hella'" ></p>

<p>I took my E320 "the 210" in for some service at the excellent locally-owned repair shop, <a href="http://masterclassauto.com/">Masterclass Automotive</a> this morning. I got the headlamp lenses swapped for spanking new Hellas and some odd DTC codes diagnosed.</p>

<p>A year or so ago, I didn't know what a DTC code was and I sure as hell didn't care. Am I becoming a 'car guy'?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Those who have known me for more than a few months know, that for the longest time, I was a dedicated bus rider/taxicab user. I had a monthly Metropass (superseded by the Easy Card) for over ten years. Not out of any sense of financial restriction (well OK at some points of time, yes...), but more out of a sense of convenience.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/thebus.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'The Bus'" ></p>

<p>However, during my temporary exile to Vegas, I was pretty much forced into getting a personal vehicle. Vegas has public transport, but it only covered about 30 percent of the valley, and even then only during daytime hours. Forget about nighttime buses.</p>

<p>At first, AMG was kind enough to provide me with a rental for the times I was actually on the ground in Vegas. It was a serviceable Ford Focus, and did the job as it were. But spending $2K+ a month to give me wheels didn't quite fit their budget, so after my Tiësto tour gig and prior to me running out the lease in Vegas, I had to acquire my own vehicle. A few options presented themselves, most notably of which was the vehicle I now own, the Mercedes E320.</p>

<p>Now, not being a car expert as it were, I had to call on some assistance to evaluate the purchase. So, I called on a friend of mine out there who owned a shop, to help me evaluate the Benz. In not so many words, it turned out to be a gem. It ran stable and was a good performer for the price, and he left it at "If you don't buy it, I will...". So, sold! I was suddenly a Mercedes owner.</p>

<p>However, as it is an older vehicle, I was advised to get it serviced and any minor repairs dealt with. I guess this is where my inherent geekiness kicked in. Whenever I purchase a new device, be it a camera, lens, phone, laptop, hard drive, or whatever, I research the hell out of it. I look for the obvious pros and cons, and also any tweaks, upgrades, hacks, and tricks to getting the most out of the device.</p>

<p>But, I guess I never considered a car as being a "device". Suddenly, this whole new world opened up to me. DTC codes, OBD-II ports, chassis numbers, ECU patches and upgrades, tire ratings, curb weights, bus voltages, optimal ranges for RPMs, fuel efficiency, horsepower, etc. It was like dissecting a computer component but there's moving parts and physics to call into account too. I guess I got hooked. And, from a pure tech perspective, it's great. I actually enjoy the research and the challenge of keeping the W210 up to spec and beyond.</p>

<p>Sidebar: Mercedes, like other manufacturers, typically assigns chassis numbers to certain classes of vehicles. For example, the W210 chassis encompasses the model years 1998-2002 and specifically the E320, E430, E300 turbodiesel, E55 AMG, and a few other models. Most enthusiasts of the brand refer to their cars by the chassis number in addition to the model number. Total geek thing.</p>

<p>But anyways, I guess my inherent need to break something down into it's components and see how it all works comes into play. I found out that the headlamp lenses could be replaced, for example. And yes, the more you know, the more you can save by doing things yourself or getting a good lead on what the mechanic will be doing. Each headlamp lens I had swapped in this morning was $85.00 as opposed to $300.00 for the entire housing if I just went with a dealer.</p>

<p>I also actually plan on getting an OBD-II dongle which interfaces with my iPhone. More stats and numbers to obsess over.</p>

<p>And I guess somewhere along the way I started becoming a "car guy". It's a fun diversion.</p>

<p>Now, of course I'm smart about it. I really only drive when I have to, and I still avail myself of public options when it's convenient or safe to do so, hence my retaining of my Easy Card and having a Car 2 Go membership. Keeping those options around (I switched my Easy Card to "refill when needed") doesn't cost any money unless you use it, so it's nice to have a "B" and "C" option, and a "too cheap to ride a cab and am going out for a drink or five" option too.</p>

<p>So, some of the "old Pod" still remains. Go figure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
