<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: miami | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/miami/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-11T12:55:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wynwood Artwalk Too Hot To Handle?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T23:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/artwalk.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Artwalk Wynwood Artwalk Miami'" ></p>

<p>Though I guess I could be considered part of the Miami art community, I almost never go to Artwalk in Wynwood. I'm usually busy Saturday nights, or I consider my rare downtime more valuable than bouncing from gallery to gallery, most of which probably wouldn't exhibit anything I do. Photography is sort of underrepresented at Artwalk, but that's for another rant.</p>

<p>So anyways, the rare times I go to it are last-minute call-ups like I did earlier tonight.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I got a text from my good friend <strong>Emi Guerra</strong>, he wanted to go out and cruise Artwalk and meet some of the Miami art community to tell them about his forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>, the big music and art festival taking place on December 8th and 9th during Art Basel. The big announcement of the lineup is Monday, even though it has been leaked. So I won't post it here since you can find it <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/">elsewhere.</a>.</p>

<p>But anyways, he wanted to go out and see the artists and art people. Makes sense if you are throwing an art-oriented festival. And, since I'm kinda in touch with these people (am I?) he invited me along.</p>

<p>So, I jumped into the 210 and zipped on down Biscayne to Wynwood.</p>

<p>Once I got to the area, what a bloody mission. Traffic was at a gridlocked standstill, and there were throngs of people out and about, to the point where Northwest 2nd Avenue was a pedestrian thoroughfare. I was supposed to meet Emi and his UR1 team at Wynwood Walls, and I ended up having to park about seven blocks away. I'm a healthy boy now so it's no big deal, but it's the principle. And I will not valet. The 210 isn't an SLS or an E 63, but it's my baby and no one except me and the crew at <a href="http://masterclassauto.com/">Masterclass Auto</a> touches the steering wheel.</p>

<p>Some have called for the major streets of Wynwood to be closed off to automotive traffic during Artwalk. 100 percent, yes. Please. Do this. Commissioner Sarnoff, it's your district (for now), make it happen. The cops have their hands full pushing vehicular and pedestrian traffic around, and it's a complete cluster down there, and it actually hampers the enjoyment of Artwalk.</p>

<p>So yes, Artwalk has truly exploded into a Miami social phenomenon. We officially have an art scene here as far as I'm concerned. Go us.</p>

<p>However, I finally did get situated, and met Emi, along with UR1's Jackie Richie, Emi's assistant Andrea, Alex Martinez of <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Deepsleep</a>, and a few other scene people I know at Wynwood Walls, which was "at capacty" and had this weird dining area with a velvet rope and such set up.</p>

<p>They gotta update the artwork there. It's been the same since I last went to Artwalk (oddly enough with Emi's brother, Eddy) over two years ago. I'll paint a wall. It won't be anything "arty", but it will be something from my mind. I'll mention it here even.</p>

<p>As I mentioned earlier, everyone was out in force. Now, was everyone into the art? Hardly. Most people "Artwalking" couldn't tell you if that was a piece by Nagelbett or Britto. They are out for the social experience. Emi phrased it best when he said, "They are out for something to do, and it's cheap to go to Artwalk. Shit is expensive these days..."</p>

<p>He hit the nail on the head. Shit is expensive these days. Dinner for two will run you $100 or more. A night out at a club, even Space, will run you $100 per person (drinks, cover, and so on) or more if you VIP it. Having fun costs money!</p>

<p>But not at Artwalk. The galleries often have cash bars and/or free (albeit low-quality) booze on hand. They usually arrange a sponsorship or something. And the food trucks are out in force, and the food is cheap, though I wouldn't necessarily trust it. Yeah, the modern food trucks have all the amenities, but it's still a food truck, ya know? We called 'em the "roach coaches" back in Jersey. Note to food truck owners, I'm not saying that your food truck has roaches. If you're that concerned about what I said, you probably have something to hide. Be confident in your product and people talking shit, like me, won't affect your business. Let freedom ring.</p>

<p>But yes, anyways, people are out for Artwalk because it's cheap, interesting, and there's a good social dynamic. And the galleries and artists put up with it since it will get their works exposed to the five percent of the people who actually know their art and are in a position to do something about it.</p>

<p>And yes, please block off the streets. Artwalk is now truly a "phenomenon" and it needs to be handled properly. Our art scene is finally getting some worldwide respect, and it'd be a shame if logistical squabbles killed off a major component of it.</p>

<p>Maybe I should run for the City Commission and make Artwalk one of my campaign platforms...</p>

<p>Dan Vidal For District 2 Commissioner!</p>

<p>Sidebar: Yes, I'm aware the issues mentioned here are old. But these first few articles on my blog are kind of for SEO purposes, as well as stuff that is on my mind, regardless of when it happened. It's my blog, after all.</p>

<p>Sidebar 2: Yes, this devolved into a rant. In a nutshell, I did have fun at Artwalk. The food truck area is a great concept. Get 'em all in one place. Also, good seeing the <a href="http://car2go.com/">Miami Car2Go</a> people out...thanks for the T-shirt guys.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I guess I am becoming a car guy?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/31/i-guess-i-am-becoming-a-car-guy/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-31T15:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/31/i-guess-i-am-becoming-a-car-guy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/210hella960.jpg" width="960" height="360" title="'210 Hella'" ></p>

<p>I took my E320 "the 210" in for some service at the excellent locally-owned repair shop, <a href="http://masterclassauto.com/">Masterclass Automotive</a> this morning. I got the headlamp lenses swapped for spanking new Hellas and some odd DTC codes diagnosed.</p>

<p>A year or so ago, I didn't know what a DTC code was and I sure as hell didn't care. Am I becoming a 'car guy'?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Those who have known me for more than a few months know, that for the longest time, I was a dedicated bus rider/taxicab user. I had a monthly Metropass (superseded by the Easy Card) for over ten years. Not out of any sense of financial restriction (well OK at some points of time, yes...), but more out of a sense of convenience.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/thebus.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'The Bus'" ></p>

<p>However, during my temporary exile to Vegas, I was pretty much forced into getting a personal vehicle. Vegas has public transport, but it only covered about 30 percent of the valley, and even then only during daytime hours. Forget about nighttime buses.</p>

<p>At first, AMG was kind enough to provide me with a rental for the times I was actually on the ground in Vegas. It was a serviceable Ford Focus, and did the job as it were. But spending $2K+ a month to give me wheels didn't quite fit their budget, so after my Tiësto tour gig and prior to me running out the lease in Vegas, I had to acquire my own vehicle. A few options presented themselves, most notably of which was the vehicle I now own, the Mercedes E320.</p>

<p>Now, not being a car expert as it were, I had to call on some assistance to evaluate the purchase. So, I called on a friend of mine out there who owned a shop, to help me evaluate the Benz. In not so many words, it turned out to be a gem. It ran stable and was a good performer for the price, and he left it at "If you don't buy it, I will...". So, sold! I was suddenly a Mercedes owner.</p>

<p>However, as it is an older vehicle, I was advised to get it serviced and any minor repairs dealt with. I guess this is where my inherent geekiness kicked in. Whenever I purchase a new device, be it a camera, lens, phone, laptop, hard drive, or whatever, I research the hell out of it. I look for the obvious pros and cons, and also any tweaks, upgrades, hacks, and tricks to getting the most out of the device.</p>

<p>But, I guess I never considered a car as being a "device". Suddenly, this whole new world opened up to me. DTC codes, OBD-II ports, chassis numbers, ECU patches and upgrades, tire ratings, curb weights, bus voltages, optimal ranges for RPMs, fuel efficiency, horsepower, etc. It was like dissecting a computer component but there's moving parts and physics to call into account too. I guess I got hooked. And, from a pure tech perspective, it's great. I actually enjoy the research and the challenge of keeping the W210 up to spec and beyond.</p>

<p>Sidebar: Mercedes, like other manufacturers, typically assigns chassis numbers to certain classes of vehicles. For example, the W210 chassis encompasses the model years 1998-2002 and specifically the E320, E430, E300 turbodiesel, E55 AMG, and a few other models. Most enthusiasts of the brand refer to their cars by the chassis number in addition to the model number. Total geek thing.</p>

<p>But anyways, I guess my inherent need to break something down into it's components and see how it all works comes into play. I found out that the headlamp lenses could be replaced, for example. And yes, the more you know, the more you can save by doing things yourself or getting a good lead on what the mechanic will be doing. Each headlamp lens I had swapped in this morning was $85.00 as opposed to $300.00 for the entire housing if I just went with a dealer.</p>

<p>I also actually plan on getting an OBD-II dongle which interfaces with my iPhone. More stats and numbers to obsess over.</p>

<p>And I guess somewhere along the way I started becoming a "car guy". It's a fun diversion.</p>

<p>Now, of course I'm smart about it. I really only drive when I have to, and I still avail myself of public options when it's convenient or safe to do so, hence my retaining of my Easy Card and having a Car 2 Go membership. Keeping those options around (I switched my Easy Card to "refill when needed") doesn't cost any money unless you use it, so it's nice to have a "B" and "C" option, and a "too cheap to ride a cab and am going out for a drink or five" option too.</p>

<p>So, some of the "old Pod" still remains. Go figure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So much for Isaac.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/28/so-much-for-isaac/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T00:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/28/so-much-for-isaac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/isaacgram.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Isaac Weekend'" ></p>

<p>I think this past weekend was a good example of what I've heard some people refer to as a "South Florida Snow Day"...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As I alluded to in the last post, Tropical Storm (and potential future hurricane) Isaac popped up on the South Florida cultural radar this past week. The usual cautionary tales ensued, with speculation turning to preparation on Thursday and Friday. Friday, the rain started to show up, with Saturday becoming a complete washout.</p>

<p>By Saturday night though, it appeared Isaac would only be a low-grade tropical storm, and the worst of it was to miss South Florida entirely, and veer through the Keys and out into the Gulf. But, the machinery of closures was already in motion. It definitely reminded me of the snow days growing up...</p>

<p>I grew up in the Northeast. As such, we had snow days when I was in school. If a storm happened, often the roads would be rendered dangerous, and as we were a walking/drive-your-kids-to-and-from-school district (only the special needs kids got buses), it was considered a liability to have kids out and about going to and from school in the event of a snow emergency. So, early in the morning of the day of the storm, the powers that be over at the school district HQ, would decide to declare a snow day, or not. They sometimes erred on the side of caution, choosing to close the district even if the accumulation wasn't that bad. So, there'd be three inches of snow on the ground (a laughable amount), and school would be closed.</p>

<p>Much like yesterday (Monday) with regards to Isaac. I woke up Monday morning, and was surprised to see the sun was out. However, the day prior, Sunday, was a complete rain event, as they say, and the governments and major businesses had already called off their Monday operations. I guess in the case of government, it's hard to recall a shutdown. However, it did rain a lot Monday afternoon, and I think it was a much-needed day off for a lot of people, personally. Though with remote work capabilities and telecommuting, the economy probably didn't suffer too much.</p>

<p>I think it was as close to a perfect situation in terms of disruption as you can get though. Enough rain came around to cause government and big business to shut down, but not so much as to engender widespread devastation and chaos. In practical matters, people got time off, and South Florida's party machine kicked into action over the weekend. It was "slow", of course, but most bars and nightclubs had enough business to justify staying open. I wonder what that says for society when we'll go through hell and high water to get drunk? Probably that we spend too much time at work, personally. But, that's another blog rant.</p>

<p>The party machine around was definitely active, with the events I attended at Chalk on South Beach, and of course Space in Downtown Miami, being heavily attended.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/classics-3797.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Space Classics'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/fuji-3505.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Chalk'" ></p>

<p>I've been through a few rain events and hurricanes, and despite the threat of damage and destruction, I've always kind of liked the atmosphere at hurricane parties. Plus, nothing beats exiting a venue and realizing, rather dimly, that you probably should get home and see about getting things situated in case the storm really does come. I remember when Hurricane Wilma, the last storm of any significance to come through South Florida directly, came through in October of 2005. I was living on Normandy Isle in the northern part of Miami Beach at the time in a fairly rattletrap (Sorry Su, it's true...but we had fun!) apartment building, and I got around via public transport or taxis. I had shot an event with Sander Kleinenberg at Space earlier, and made my usual late exit from the venue that Sunday morning. Of course, I had heard reports that this pesky storm might just come for us, but didn't give it much thought. I had gotten home, checked a few reports, most of which centered on "Yes, it's coming for Miami, but at what strength we don't know...", and passed out to sleep. I woke up about eight hours later to the sounds of my roommate and his friend stocking up for the storm. Apparently it was close, as we lost power a few hours later. Fortunately we had enough random provisions to get through the next few days, but for a minute it was kind of tense as we had no "real" food.</p>

<p>I'm a little more responsible nowadays, I think. I have a few gallons of water on hand and a FIVESTAR account with hotels.com. And I keep an eye on my iPhone during potential hurricane periods. If things look ugly, I'll prebook a hotel inland and north and get out of town. Might not be the most entertaining course of action, but fortunately I'm mobile. I can fit everything important to me (gear, data, and some clothes) into my trunk. And if the storm is a non-event, I can come back home.</p>

<p>It might not work for you though. Don't blame me if it doesn't.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fear of photography?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/21/a-fear-of-photography/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T12:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/21/a-fear-of-photography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ferrer-2724.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'I can seeeeee you!'" ></p>

<p>Local photojournalist and all-around good guy <a href="http://www.pixiq.com/contributors/248">Carlos Miller</a> got me thinking recently after the last <a href="http://www.pixiq.com/article/four-cop-cars-get-called-on-us">photo protest</a> he staged in front of the Miami Herald building.</p>

<p>A lot of people have a fear of photography. And I really can't figure out why. Sure, for some people I can see it. They're doing something they probably shouldn't be, and there's scads of photographic recording devices around them, which may or may not be recording their actions. I encounter it out in the clubs from time to time. I like to shoot wide, as you can see above, and I may inadvertently capture someone doing something (or someone, ba-dum-ching...) they shouldn't be.</p>

<p>It certainly isn't deliberate on my part though. Whatever transgressions you may be committing, that's your problem and not mine. I'm not out to ruin your life, since it appears that you're quite capable of doing that on your own. And no, I won't delete it. You are a noisy red smear at the bottom of the frame. And you probably shouldn't be cheating on your pretty wife in front of thousands of people and about that many cameras.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>But, that's just with crackheads in nightclubs, which, fortunately, form a small minority of our population.</p>

<p>The real head-scratcher is the people who get worked up over photography in public places. If you can see it from a public location, you can shoot it, it's that simple. I don't buy the national security bit or anything of that nature. If I take a photo of the refinery near Fort Lauderdale airport, the photo, other than a creative piece, tells me nothing. It's a collection of pipes. It won't aid a terrorist in planning to blow it up. And, if a terrorist wants to blow up the refinery, a photo isn't going to hinder or help him or her too much. It's not like in the movies where they can deduce where the 2-meter wide exhaust vent is from a cell phone photo.</p>

<p>Even more puzzling are the ordinary citizens who bring it upon themselves to get worked up over photos in public places. The photo protest I mentioned is a perfect example. In a nutshell, the ordinary citizen was a security guard, who took it upon himself to misquote the law, leading to the situation described in Carlos' blog entry. Now, a few words on that.</p>

<p>A security guard is an ordinary citizen. He doesn't have police powers. As a matter of fact, he's even more restricted from certain actions in the course of his job than an ordinary citizen is. The industry's slogan is "Observe and Report". That's about all they can do. Plus, from a pragmatic perspective, the pay scale isn't high enough to justify more than that. If I was working the front desk at the Herald, I'd either ignore it and get back to my Youtube viewing, or just kick it upstairs and let the bureaucrats in facilities deal with it. Yes, I'm being totally lazy and "not dedicated", but for $12/hr and no benefits, you're only going to get so much out of me. I'd rather spend my effort on something more meaningful, ya know?</p>

<p>Getting worked up about people shooting photos in public places is a complete waste of one's energy. There's so much more out there to expend effort on. Plus, if you think about it, the camera is ubiquitous now. If something is not recorded, that is an unusual set of circumstances indeed. In a society such as ours, there's at least one camera recording the scene at all times in any given public location. The ethics of such ubiquitous recording? Well, that's another debate entirely.</p>

<p>But such recording shouldn't be feared. If you don't want it recorded, don't put it in a public location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My first inbound link.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/17/my-first-inbound-link/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T16:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/17/my-first-inbound-link</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/car2go.png" width="512" height="369" title="'car 2 go'" ></p>

<p>Looks like Car 2 Go heard the noise I was making...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I don't do advertorial or paid postings, it defeats the purpose of this blog, in my mind. Anything I talk about or endorse here is based on personal experience and not because someone paid me off. If I think something is useful or quality, I'll post about it here. <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car 2 Go</a> is definitely a great service and worth what I pay for it. Keep up the good work guys.</p>

<p>I've been through the advertorial wringer before. It's fun for a few minutes while you get paid, but after awhile, if you are posing as a legitimate news source, it does get tiring after awhile if you have any sort of humanity.</p>

<p>The sad thing is, advertisers and companies have come to expect advertorial as a standard practice these days. I've been around plenty of people and corporations when the question of the media and coverage for their product/brand/event comes up, and a notable amount of the discussion does center on the advertorial side of things. What's even worse, is when you see what appear to be respectable news outlets going along for the advertorial ride.</p>

<p>Listen, as far as pure journalism goes, it's a tough world out there now. Ad sales have dried up, and obviously it costs money to operate and maintain a decent news outlet. However, there are ways to cut costs and still maintain standards of ethical and journalistic integrity. A lot of "fat" can be cut on the infrastructure side of things, for example. This very blog is an example. While I don't have it configured for true high-availability, I know I could scale it up as such where having this blog as an HA app wouldn't break the bank. A little knowledge goes a long way.</p>

<p>I think, at the end of the day, journalists and news organizations should embrace being a bit multi-talented, enabling them to continue delivering unbiased news, without having to resort to deceptive advertorial processes.</p>

<p>And yes, I know the guilty parties in the advertorial game. Let's just say it's not too surprising. I'll keep my own counsel for now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
