<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: miami | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/miami/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-22T14:23:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy US Thanksgiving To My Small Readership!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/22/happy-us-thanksgiving-to-my-small-readership/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/22/happy-us-thanksgiving-to-my-small-readership</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/mpd-5409.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'MPD'" ></p>

<p>Happy Thanksgiving to my small and dedicated loyal readership. Keep it down out there, otherwise the guys above might have to move their cruisers off the grass and they usually don't like doing that...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And with that, the holiday season begins.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bayfront-6921.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Challenger Monument'" ></p>

<p>The mad rush to the malls, 'Cyber Monday' as it were, and all the other associated commercial activity. Since I'll most likely be lazy and not blog about it on the day of, this weekend also features <a href="http://www.miamiherald.com/2012/11/21/3107988/small-business-saturday-the-anti.html">Small Business Saturday.</a></p>

<p>I can dig it. I like sorting out people I know. Plus, I'm all about the small and agile ethos. It's easier and more fun if you think about it.</p>

<p>And, in the spirt of Small Business Saturday and also the holidays, why not support a local small business (me), and purchase for yourself, or as a gift, one of my fine scenic pieces? I just recently put the above photo, 'Challenger Monument' up for sale. You can purchase a copy in any number of sizes, finishes, and mounting options (including canvas gallery wraps) by <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com">by clicking here</a>. I'll even knock 20 percent off the price. Just put the code 'ZESNLP' into the box at checkout, and the discount will be applied. Other prints available for purchase include popular images like...</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<center>_Islamorada Crossing_</center>


<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648.jpg" width="960" height="1440" title="'Fire away'" ></p>

<center>_Indian Key Channel_</center>


<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/outwhere_rev-8882.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'US 27 Northbound Broward County'" ></p>

<center>_Out Where The Buses Don't Run_</center>


<p>...and quite a few more.</p>

<p><a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com">Click on over to my print store to purchase</a>. Don't forget code 'ZESNLP' at checkout for the 20 percent discount. Shipping times are reasonable but may back up a bit closer to the end of December.</p>

<p>Yes, this is me being a little commercial.</p>

<p>Go pig out and spend time with your family and friends. They miss you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Back, I Wonder How I Did It...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/20/looking-back/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/20/looking-back</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tmb-7087.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'TMB'" ></p>

<p>This past weekend, The Martinez Brothers took to the decks at Space. They've got the youthful energy and enthusiasm in spades. Playing for well over ten hours, they kept the dancefloor moving until the afternoon...</p>

<p>I'm not ancient, by any measure, but by the time I left at 9, I was completely drained...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And the kids were still rocking it like they just woke up...</p>

<p>Objectively, I'm actually healthier than I've been in a long time. I try to eat right, and take care of myself. I still have a drink or five when I'm at the club (no one trusts you if you are without a drink in a nightclub...just nod and agree with me on this one) and I will be smart and pace myself. However, sometimes I'm just completely drained, even going into Monday. Is it all mental? Or has a decade and change in-scene finally started to catch up with me?</p>

<p>When I was The Brothers' age, I could do a 9-10 hour "shift" standing on my head, and still bounce back for whatever I had to do on Monday. I could even go out multiple nights a week till 5 AM. Now, I don't go to a club unless there's decent money involved. I'd rather relax with friends or just stay home and read/write/edit. Or go out and shoot scenics.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bayfront-6921.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Challenger Monument'" ></p>

<p>Maybe I am "getting old", who knows? I still enjoy the nightlife, but yeah, it does take a lot out of you, regardless of your health.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/11/20//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/SPS2IbAgGT/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage11.s3.amazonaws.com/e452ccb632cf11e2a4461231381b6557_7.jpg' alt='Adventures with @themartinezbros @clubspacemiami @jhartlein @n0t0r10us @frannypanny @zhantra http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/the-martinez-brothers-return-to-space-2' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784642914,-80.19313766'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784642914,-80.19313766&markers=25.784642914,-80.19313766&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='328564182553330067_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>For my younger readers - this will happen to you. I can guarantee it. Trick is, pace yourself, but even then...</p>

<p>Maybe a vacation is in order.</p>

<p>Thoughts?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Work with the light tech...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/13/work-with-the-light-tech-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T01:04:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/13/work-with-the-light-tech-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/mark-6094.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Mark Knight at Space November 2012 with light tech Dennis Perez'" ></p>

<p>One of my favorite DJ/Producers, <a href="http://www.djmarkknight.com/">Mark Knight</a>, stopped in at Space this past weekend for a little eight-hour set on the decks. He's got the idea of being a DJ down pat. He mixes in his own material and edits, with a good dose of anything that will make the crowd move. Throughout the night I heard everything from classic Underworld to even an INXS-inspired white label track. And he's always down for a wacky photo or two, like the one above. And, of course, I get asked 'how did I do that'?</p>

<p>In this case, it wasn't just a random happenstance of the lighting and the photo coming together...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it...</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Generally that is how I work. I wait for things to happen, as I've explained before, then I document it. However, in club life, an interesting 'counter' to my little tagline happens, in that the friendly local lighting techs will set up a specific cue, so I can capture the moment. So, I have to wonder, am I waiting for the world to fall in line if someone kind of knows what I would like to see?</p>

<p>I do appreciate the help, obviously, and it is actually not a hard feat for anyone to accomplish if they are out shooting nightlife. The trick here is, to get to know your light techs and the equipment they employ on a nightly basis.</p>

<p>When I first got started in this, I used to be a part-time light tech for my friend John's sound company. John and I, at the time, were both students over at UM, and to make ends meet, and also for the learning experience (his major was audio engineering), John ran a small sound and lighting company on the side. And I was his unofficial-official light tech, due to my experience with lighting in general, and also no one else in our crew knew the concepts. We didn't get paid much, but at the time, half the fun was just being able to get out there and do shows. We mostly did rock shows, but we also did a few dance-oriented events here and there. Nonetheless, I got to learn the basics of stage and nightclub lighting. As time went on, even after John moved back to Aspen to kick off his <a href="http://alchemyavcs.com/">massive production company</a>, I would stay current and always converse and on occasion, fill in as a tech for a lot of the local guys when they were sick, away or "otherwise indisposed". At this time (early to mid 2000s), lighting was moving from a "dedicated console" world, to a PC-driven sort of affair, especially in the nightclub industry. A $300 PC and $700 USB-DMX widget could take the place of a $20000 console in a nightclub setting. The most popular product was <a href="http://martinpro.com/product/product.asp?product=lightjockey">LightJockey</a> by Martin. In a nutshell, after you installed and connected all your fixtures, you used this piece of software and supplied USB-DMX widget, and could program and control your lightshow from any commodity PC. It is all very graphical.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/LJ.jpg" width="600" height="474" title="'Lightjockey 2.0'" ></p>

<p>There's several competing software packages out there nowadays, but Lightjockey is the most common one. The concepts are the same though.</p>

<p>And then, obviously, beyond the controller, is the entire world of the lighting fixtures themselves. Common manufacturers include <a href="http://martinpro.com/">Martin</a>, <a href="http://www.highend.com/">Highend</a>, <a href="http://www.elationlighting.com/">Elation</a>, <a href="http://claypaky.com/">Clay Paky</a>, and many more.</p>

<p>Entire blogs and sites are devoted to lighting. Obviously this one isn't. But, you don't have to be a light tech to speak the basics. The key, I've found, is to know what the fixtures are (spots, washes, scanners, strobes - all kind of self-explanatory), and the right terms for what the fixtures do (If you say 'CTO' you'll usually be taken a little bit more seriously) and what the colors and filters are, and also the basics of how a lighting scene is constructed. Also, if you don't know the tech, get to know him or her (yes, her - one of the best in the biz <a href="https://www.facebook.com/miss.allegra"> is a girl</a>.) and develop a rapport. If it's early in the night, the tech is usually just running through the motions, and will probably be up for a break in the routine. Use the opening DJ as a "practice target", and get some cues set up for yourself.</p>

<p>Now, this all kind of reeks of cheating. And, maybe it is. However, the way I can ethically justify it is now, in a lot of places, the tech will actually bring up "my" cues, without me even asking. At Space, I don't think I've asked Dennis or Gabriel for a specific cue in months. It just all falls into place. They know what will make for a great image, and more importantly, when to deploy those cues, for maximum effect on both the crowd and my image capture. We work together on it.</p>

<p>Plus, a good tech will know the flow and rhythm to the music and crowd, and having specific cues becomes less and less necessary, since the lighting will just happen. When a song peaks, you know there will be a sizable amount of strobing, for example. Or when there is a lull in the track, it could go dark, or a nice blue wash from the Platinum Beams will kick in.</p>

<p>Of course, the assumption being made here is that you are shooting in a venue that is equipped with a decent lighting rig, and, beyond that, a dedicated lighting technician. Some smaller venues still run their lighting systems on autopilot, or according to a preset schedule (Lightjockey allows for scheduled cues based on the time of day, even), depending on the needs of the venue. That being said, most places of that nature actually have a lot of practical lighting, or a good dose of ambient light. There's a lot of light out there if you know where to find it.</p>

<p>But, if the situation allows for it, definitely get to know and work with the light techs in a venue, the resultant images will be much more "meaningful" than your usual run-of-the-mill flash-and-dash captures.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm a social media sceptic and I have a blog...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/09/im-a-social-media-sceptic-and-i-have-a-blog-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-09T11:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/09/im-a-social-media-sceptic-and-i-have-a-blog-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/blog-5407.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'OCP'" ></p>

<p>This morning, when I woke up, a post on Facebook by <a href="http://helloimscott.com/">Scott Alexander</a> caught my eye.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>A good article for photographers and artists of any medium, really. While you're on Edin's site reading this, I highly recommend checking out the rest of his site. Great photographer with a superb eye.</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>Scott Alexander</strong> <cite>A Facebook Post</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The post linked to <a href="http://www.edinchavez.com/blog/why-should-i-start-a-blog/">an article by local photographer Edin Chavez</a>, on why a photographer should have a blog. The reasons are pretty obvious, ranging from showcasing your work to SEO, and, most importantly, <em>control</em>.</p>

<p>Now, maybe it sounds a little obsessive, but at the end of the day, having a slice of web property you control from top to bottom is important, especially if you are in the creative field. And, unfortunately, there's quite a large amount of creative types who don't have a web property that they explicitly have ownership of. I know more than a few working photographers who only use social media to showcase their works, for example. This can be dangerous.</p>

<p>I'm a "social media sceptic". I've been on the internet in one way or another since 1992, around the time the World Wide Web was born. And yes, there was an <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was/">internet before then</a>. My dad was/is a network engineer, so we always had some form of basic online access. In general, we passed on the walled-garden online services of the day like AOL, Compu$erve, and so on. I actually preferred local dialup BBSes, which, in a way, were primitive social networks.</p>

<p>You could post up content, chat with other users, and transfer files around. It was basically a text-mode Facebook, if you think about it. However, after a few years, the era of the BBS faded, replaced by easy internet access and the rise of consumer usage of the WWW. Once people got situated and used to "dot com", soon after came the rise of user-provided content, i.e. the first blogs. Blogging was around before the term was coined (a lot of personal websites had a running journal of the owner's thoughts...), but with the advent of primitive <a href="http://www.movabletype.org/">CMS</a> systems, publishing content became a trivial point and shoot exercise. Then, of course, that was extended into social networking as we know it. Friendster kicked off the craze, then MySpace, then proceeding on to Twitter and Facebook, with of course Google constantly on the move to be "the" internet.</p>

<p>However, through all those trends and sea changes, the ability to host and publish your own content on your own web property has remained. I know a few "social media managers" (the title is largely meaningless), and their biggest challenge is keeping up with the trends in services and platforms. Today it is Facebook, tomorrow it could (hopefully) be <a href="http://join.app.net/">app.net</a>, or a move to the <a href="https://joindiaspora.com/">Diaspora</a> model of community-run distributed social networking. Nonetheless, it's a lot to digest and keep up with. It's the nature of the beast, as it were.</p>

<p>And therein lies the problem. I see a lot of people who rely and base their businesses on a specific form of social media. A few years ago, I knew people who made businesses based on doing MySpace profile templates, and they acted as if it was their gateway to untold riches. Now, you have companies building applications around Facebook, acting in much the same way. With the cyclical trendy nature of social media, most of these companies are destined to fail, or disappear, due to their reliance on someone else's platform for their business. It's akin to relying on General Motors cars exclusively for your delivery business, rather than any operational vehicle.</p>

<p>Now, one could drive themselves crazy keeping up with these social media trends. Every so often, you have to convert and repost your content. One bulwark against that, (to bring it all home!), is having your own web property. Now, <a href="http://www.edinchavez.com/blog/why-should-i-start-a-blog/">Edin espouses Wordpress and/or Blogger</a> as a publishing platform, and I of course champion <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, but that battle is more of a technical one than a political one.</p>

<p>The key is, hosting your content on your own systems, and using social media to drive people to those systems. I know with Octopress it will be a trivial matter to write a plug-in to support broadcasting to any future social network, due to it's open-source nature. And even though Wordpress is rather closed in comparison, some enterprising developer will link WP with whichever future social network becomes ascendent. But, at the end of the day, with having your own domain, own hosting, and own content, one can make themselves immune from the often-flaky, trendy, and chaotic world of social media.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your obligatory post-election post...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/07/your-obligatory-post-election-post-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-07T01:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/07/your-obligatory-post-election-post-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/IMG_6714.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The rest of the country'" ></p>

<p>As of right now, President Barack Obama has secured his spot for a second term as President of these United States. To most observers, it wasn't entirely unexpected, but his challenger, Mitt Romney, did put up a good fight, appealing to the "rest of America", as it were, rather than focusing on the urban centers in the states with high electoral votes, as Obama did. In essence, it created the same split the US had four years ago. The map looks much the same, with the coasts being "blue" and the interior of the country being "red"...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In my travels I've visited each and every state in the Lower 48. At the base level, life will go on for each and every citizen of the US, much as it has had for them over the course of their lives. Whether there's a Democrat or a Republican in the White House, their lives will go on. They will grow up, get jobs, maybe get married, maybe kick out a few kids, get old, and pass on, regardless of their location or political affiliation. Sure, economic conditions and the overall mood of the country do change (we are, as a lot, more miserable now than twenty years ago), but the overall lifestyle and conditions have remained pretty steady. Most of us have a roof over our heads and food on the table, which means we're ahead of most of the world by a fair margin.</p>

<p>If we want to effect true change in our lives and political system, we can't rely on just electing a different face of the same system every four years. Politicians may enter the world of politics with the best of ideals, but once in, they are either corrupted by power, or beaten down by the depth of the problems with our system, and they do the government equivalent of collecting a paycheck and just go through the motions.</p>

<p>To effect these changes, some have looked to the "third parties" in the US political system. Ranging from serious politicians such as ex-Republican governor of New Mexico <a href="http://garyjohnson2012.com/">Gary Johnson</a> of the <a href="http://lp.org/">Libertarian Party</a>, to publicity hounds like Roseanne Barr, the world of third-party politics is a diverse and wild one. Unfortunately, as it stands, no one has yet to make a serious dent in the two-party system. Johnson may or may not have come close, but as of this writing, it's hard to find out whether he crossed the "magic" threshold of getting 5 percent of the popular vote. This threshold, if crossed, would permit the Libertarian Party to qualify for matching campaign funds from the government in the next election cycle, a major bonus.</p>

<p>Now, I tend to focus on the Libertarians a lot, mainly because that is my registered party affiliation. It isn't a big secret that I have a distaste for big central government. I see big central government much like I see a big corporation. The government (corporation) only holds itself up to it's biggest shareholders (the corporations in this case!) and disregards the interests of the individual citizen. What the Libertarian platform seeks to accomplish is to scale back government to the bare minimums needed to maintain a cohesive nation, and decentralize a lot of functions that are currently central, allowing for a more responsive form of government. Note, for the record, Libertarians aren't anarchists or corporatists. The philosophy at it's root level actually allows for debate and discussion on the form of government itself, actually. Some who identify as Libertarians are borderline anarchists, sure, but most are just decent citizens looking to live their lives with a minimum of active government interference, but also expecting that the government should be there to discharge it's prescribed duties, whatever those may be at a given moment.</p>

<p>For example, the Libertarian take on war is that it is generally a bad thing. A Libertarian government shouldn't conduct offensive campaigns, only defensive. Thus, the government is responsible for the safety of it's taxpayers from external threats. This also obviously extends to basic police functions as well. I'm actually of the same bent. If I'm paying taxes, even if they are minimal, I would want the body I'm paying taxes into, to be able to take care of me and keep me safe. Sure, I'm pro-Second Amendment. When seconds count, the cops are minutes away, after all, but if you step it up a level, a Walther PPS isn't really going to matter much against a full-on army. I would expect a government to provide a small standing force to do that for me.</p>

<p>Much along the same lines, and where I kind of split with the general party line (again, the party generally welcomes dissent and debate), is that the government should provide a basic form of emergency health care, covered by taxes. With the abolition of many government agencies, basic healthcare could be provided, even at a lower tax rate. After all, if I'm healthy, I'm able to work and pay taxes into the system. If I'm sick or infirm, I'm not able to work.</p>

<p>Beyond making sure the citizens are safe and healthy, the government should be hands-off. However, under the current system, that just isn't possible. There is an entire industry built around a two-party strong central government system. Lobbyists, contractors, bureaucrats, and so many others depend on this very system for their livelihood. The system in place isn't interested in the welfare of it's citizens, it is only interested in safeguarding it's existence in perpetuity. Much like the fictional "Matrix", some people are so plugged in and dependent, they'll stop at nothing to ensure the survival of their system.</p>

<p>Thus, beyond the change in government, we need a sea change in society for true progress to be made. Less and less, we should look to big government to solve all our ills, or big business for that matter. People need to get off of their social media and reality show addictions and get involved in the political process, before their right to do so is gradually usurped. The right to keep and bear arms could be revoked tomorrow and only a few NRA lobbyists would raise a fuss, but if someone set off an EMP weapon in each Facebook data center, there would be a mass insurrection. Bread and circuses keep the masses in check. People bitch about their privacy rights all the time, but they'll share every bowel movement on Facebook, like it matters. That's a personal pet peeve of mine. Fact is, even if I like you, I don't care. Spare me the mundane. Let me know when you do something interesting. Checking in at your cubicle is not interesting. Oops, nearly went off track there.</p>

<p>Also, we need to reawaken the spirit of "Do It Yourself" in this country. Now, I'm not suggesting we all become aircraft mechanics and architects and build our own personal planes and buildings, but at the same time, I'm shocked at the lack of general knowledge of the way things work in some of the people around me. Now, grant it, I'm certainly deficient in some of these areas (until recently, cars were a 'stomp-on-gas-pedal-and-go-that-way' affair to me), but I'm actually amazed at the overall level of ignorance I encounter. I think a spirit of "DIY" would encourage more government participation by the citizens.</p>

<p>Now, this could be a double-edged sword. People may not always think about what is best for the community, but what is best for them. For example, outlawing abortion might suit the family down the street just fine, but might not ring true for the struggling single mom-to-be down the street. Where people definitely need to mind their own business is in matters of the body, so to speak. My body, my rules. As long as my mistakes only harm me, I should be allowed to make them without penalty or interference. Abortion, drug use, even assisted suicide, aka "death with dignity" should be decisions left to the individual, not others. At the end of the day, the Libertarian ideal is about individual freedom. Right now, there is a severe lack of it in this country. Sure, there's a lot we can do, but at the same time, there is a lot we cannot do, that we should be able to do, especially when it comes to ourselves.</p>

<p>I didn't mean for this to turn into a pro-Libertarian rant, OK, maybe I did, but nonetheless, the issues are still staring us in the face, even though our everyday life continues unabated, and even though at a basic level, for most of us, it isn't that bad.</p>

<p>But, it could be better. My ideas and concepts could actually make accomplishing that quite easy. And, of course, if you just choose to kick back and figure out things as you go along, that's alright too. It is your right as a human being to do the amount of work you think is necessary to be happy. For some this involves 16-hour days festering under fluorescent tubes. For others, this involves being outdoors and building things. For others, it kind of involves a lot of random things. It's your life, neither the government, your friends, parents, families, talking heads on TV, self-help gurus, priests, rabbis, imams, or swamis need to be in the business of telling you how to live it.</p>

<p>Now, with the current federal election over, Obama has four more years to deliver on his promises. Being human, he won't deliver on them all, but the American people just granted him an extension. While I hope he delivers on some, and misses the ball on others, I do know it's up to us to keep an eye on him and the government as a whole, and gradually try to effect the sea change I spoke about earlier. Revolutions don't happen overnight, even in this day and age. Patience is key.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
