<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: miami | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/miami/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-01T03:13:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Communities and Conduct...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/01/on-communities-and-conduct-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T02:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/01/on-communities-and-conduct-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/appnet.png" width="781" height="446" title="'alpha dot app dot net slash pod'" ></p>

<p>I've recently jumped onto a new social networking service called <a href="http://join.app.net/">app.net</a>. Founded by <a href="http://daltoncaldwell.com/">Dalton Caldwell</a>, app.net is, at a basic level, an ad-free version of Twitter. You basically pay $5 a month or $36 a year to join, and from there it's pretty smooth sailing. Like any new service online, there's a small fanatical userbase laying the groundwork for the new community, including the "tone"...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A few years ago, when <a href="http://www.technogeno.us/">Ryan</a> and I were kicking off <a href="http://talknightlife.com/">TNL</a>, one of the things we thought about was setting the standard for discourse in the community. The initial way we did this was via an invite system. We basically told people we knew and liked about the new site, gave them the gateway password, and told them to have at it while we built it. We invited people we knew were capable of intelligent discourse, as well as deliberately inviting a few "disruptive" elements, just to see if our little idea of the community setting the tone worked. For the most part, it did. Where our previous community frequently walked the line with porn, spam, and some pretty vicious personal battles, the TNL experiment proved to be mild in comparison. (Yes, mild...I wish we exported the blue site DB before we got shown the door, there were some real gems in there!) However, in general, it seemed to prove a point that an online community, especially a niche one, is capable of being largely self-regulating.</p>

<p>But, if a community grows to be amazingly large, can it self-police? It's hard to say. Look at Facebook. Even if you have a limited friend list, you are still subject to the content they post, and they generally take influence from their friends, and so on. So, Facebook has devolved into a mindless mash of memes, chain letters, tabloid news, and general idiocy. However, objectively, sometimes general idiocy can be fun. I'll gladly admit to laughing at the latest meme. I love "Me Gusta" ragefaces and the "Because 'Fuck You', That's Why!" meme actually kind of sums up how I feel about most things I do. However, the general tone of Facebook is one of a shopping mall with disinterested mall cops who only do what they have to do, in order to keep their jobs. And the self-policing actions are generally arbitrary. People will laugh at a video of a guy getting hit by a train, but not if it originated from someone they have a problem with. Then it's game on, they're clicking "hide/report" for all it's worth.</p>

<p>Twitter isn't much better off. Due to it's nature it is limited to short messages, but now that they have to make money, they are injecting ads into every available nook and cranny of the service. Which, since it's a free service, they have every right to. It's basically the mall, but you can only say things in short sentences. Very chaotic, and of course prone to brain-dropping syndrome.</p>

<p>Now, app.net is far smaller than both Facebook and Twitter. As of last count, they have less than 30,000 users. Which isn't bad for a service that is not owned by a major corporation, and explicitly asks you to pay money for access, in exchange for providing a clean and friendly environment. It is the VIP lounge of the social networking scene. Well, back when VIP lounges actually were VIP anyhow.</p>

<p>The virtue of this small paywall is that it tends to keep the casual user out. When you have an open social network or community site, basically anyone with something to say can come by. Now, I'm all about giving people the freedom to express themselves, but on the internet, the price of that freedom is spam and a lower quality of conduct. On a free network, that is. Spammers aren't going to pay to access a small community of individuals who have no interest in their products, and anyone with a "casual" opinion or an insult isn't going to pay money just to rattle someone's cage. With app.net, it has led to a general atmosphere of camaraderie and educated discourse. While the language itself is as "free" as any other site, it's generally used in context, and not just for the sake of saying "fuck" every third word. And the feeling is generally virulent. The user feels he or she needs to be at the level of the community in order to engage them. I post on there a few times a day, and I'm usually pretty cautious about how I phrase myself. Now, one of the virtues of app.net is an open API. You pay a little extra for access, but it allows for a whole host of third-party applications and tie-ins. Today, I started using an <a href="http://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a>recipe to link my Instagram feed to app.net. While something like this is encouraged as it makes app.net more appealing, I almost feel that I should maybe de-link it, since some of my Instagrams are a bit low-brow for the community.</p>

<p>However, it seems app.net, with it's spirit of dissatisfaction against the status quo of monolithic and exploitative social networks like Facebook and Twitter, is proving on a larger scale, that the early adopters can and do set the tone and unwritten code of conduct for a web community and social network. It will be an interesting experiment to watch, especially if it catches fire in a major way. How will advertisers approach a community that has no love for their techniques, but still uses their products anyways? How will they advertise in a place with no advertising mechanism? Will app.net cancel the accounts of spammers? Those questions do remain. I can see "guerrilla marketers" and so-called "social media consultants" signing up at the least. Those types of people lose sleep over the fact that somewhere in the world, there's a social media service they aren't a part of. God forbid their already-rigged metrics slip half a percentage point. Wait till they find out there's services in China with half-a-billion members who conduct their daily discourse entirely in Mandarin. They'll be running down to the mall kiosks to buy Rosetta Stone - Mandarin Edition.</p>

<p>Thankfully app.net has a very prominent blocking feature.</p>

<p>The way I see it developing is much like TV networks such as HBO did. People specifically pay money to access HBO, not only for it's quality unfiltered content, but because there are no obvious ads. I say 'obvious' since I do consider the little half-hour bits about stuff on HBO produced by HBO to be a form of advertising designed to keep you subscribed. Which is fine. It is the service merely preserving itself. I guess the app.net staff does the same thing, since Dalton actively participates in the community and keeps people informed on "what's next..."</p>

<p>Personally, I think it's the future. I think social media is going to go more "boutique", and less "mall", and people will have to adjust their thinking accordingly. The open internet will and should always still be there, but more and more, I see paid-for and niche social and community sites becoming the norm as people tire of the constant bombardment of advertisers on the large free services like Facebook and Twitter.</p>

<p>They aren't destined for failure either. I can actually see them adopting a two-tiered approach in the classic web fashion. Free access with ads, or pay a small monthly fee to remove them. They'll take a page from the small innovators like app.net and call it their own. However, to truly compete, they need more effective filters. An ad-free experience means nothing if there's still guerrilla marketers vying for your attention. "Hey Pod, haven't seen you in awhile, how's life? Oh really? Cool, well, ya know, I can get you 10,000 followers in a month if you act right now!".</p>

<p>But that's for another rant.</p>

<p>I think I'm going to go post some cat photos on Facebook and say the word 'fuck' a few times in succession. Then off to app.net and make recommendations on camera equipment.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoPro has had a busy week...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/17/gopro-has-had-a-busy-week-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-17T10:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/17/gopro-has-had-a-busy-week-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51601636?title=1&amp;byline=1&amp;portrait=1" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51601636">• GoPro Hero 2 Protune Test - Nighttime Drive •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>The fine folks at GoPro have had a busy week. For existing owners of the Hero2, they released a new firmware set, which included a new set of shooting modes collectively grouped under the name 'Protune'. Protune basically doubles the bitrate of the GoPro's recorded files to 35 Mbps, and produces a more 'flat' file with no in-camera color corrections or sharpening. And, in bigger news, they rolled the GoPro Hero 3 last night, which adds built-in WiFi, 4K video recording (albeit at 15 FPS), all packaged in a smaller-profile body...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, the Hero 3 just went on sale for pre-order, so I obviously don't have one on hand yet. I was this "&lt;>" close to buying a Hero 2, but fortunately I didn't. I have the wedding of my great friends and neighbors Tal and Erick to shoot this weekend up in North Carolina, and I wanted to strap a GoPro next to the "altar" and record the vows portion from an alternate angle, so I was going to pull the trigger and buy a Hero 2. Fortunately, time kind of ran out on me, so I had to make do with borrowing <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis'</a> Hero 2. I told him I'd upgrade it to the Protune firmware while I was at it.</p>

<p>So, with that in mind, I figured I'd take Protune for a spin.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/16//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q3gj9EggEx/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/a2921adc180511e2a46d1231381b4837_7.jpg' alt='A #protune test of @gopro !' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='303854708114719025_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I strapped the Hero 2 to the front left bumper of the 210, and proceeded to record my drive down to Blue Martini in Brickell for my "Tuesday Tradition" shooting session over at Jive With The Band.</p>

<p>You can see the results above, and judge for yourself. I did some basic color correction and exposure adjustment in Final Cut Pro X, and exported this to Vimeo via Compressor 4 using the standard Vimeo preset.</p>

<p>The unaltered video out of the camera is very noisy. This was to be expected, since Protune deactivates all in-camera processing, including noise reduction. It's about as close to RAW video as you are likely to get out of something in the class of the GoPro. Colors were very neutral and flat. The dynamic range was increased, due to the "flat" nature of the file. At first glance, it actually appeared to be worse than the previous firmware output.</p>

<p>However, this was the expected result. Ideally, if you can't get true RAW output out of your camera, you want a file that is as untouched and as uncompressed as possible, to allow for these adjustments to be made with more precise tools present on your laptop. Which is exactly what Protune accommodates, as much as possible. Also, it does reveal the limitations of the tiny sensor in the camera. It's a noisy mess, and GoPro is definitely to be commended for developing decent in-camera noise reduction and sharpening techniques for their standard firmware. FYI, you can turn Protune off and go back to the standard modes at any time.</p>

<p>That being said, for anyone remotely interested in video, I don't recommend it. You can really make the output of the GoPro shine with Protune, using your choice of post-production software, whether it's Final Cut Pro X, or GoPro's own Cineform. Once you understand the purpose of Protune, it is definitely a winner. It gets the camera's ideas about things out of the way of your workflow, and lets you make the decisions on color correction, sharpening, noise, and so on.</p>

<p>For a $300 unit, the GoPro Hero 2 with Protune is a winner in my book. I'll be doing some daylight tests today and tomorrow, which I will post about soon thereafter.</p>

<p>As for the Hero 3? That will most likely make it into my bag in short order. GoPro, if you pick this up, I'm always game to beat around a demo unit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It is like my version of Mr Sparkle.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/my-version-of-mr-sparkle/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T18:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/my-version-of-mr-sparkle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/niceday-1479.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Mirinda'" ></p>

<p>It was a positively stunning day here in South Florida, so I jumped in the 210 and went out for a bit.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I made my usual Saturday stop at Whole Foods, this time the South Beach one. The Aventura one has better wraps, but the Beach one is closer, and I wanted to shoot some random stuff on the Beach anyways.</p>

<p>After my tuna wrap, I proceeded up Collins to the Ocean Terrace around 74th Street. I figured I'd try to get some shallow DOF shots out on the sand. I was experimenting with trying to capture one breaking wave, when an orange can thumped into my foot.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/niceday-1476.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Mirinda'" ></p>

<p>"Mirinda?" I thought, "What the hell is Mirinda?"</p>

<p>It's a girl's name in some quarters, but I never saw it applied to a beverage. So, curious, I picked up the can. It was unopened, and aside from the Mirinda logo, it lacked the usual nutritional value grid, and also the volume was listed as 330 mL only. No Imperial measurements. My god, it's a can from the future!</p>

<p>It was totally my Mr Sparkle moment.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dnaLRbbc-54" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>But, my momentary flashback to a Simpsons episode faded, and it turns out Mirinda is a product of Pepsi, primarily distributed in Asia. The can actually said "Distributed by Pepsi Singapore" on the side.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QvBo3qggAv/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/e3132586156e11e283e622000a1fb86d_7.jpg' alt='This must have fallen off of a ship. #mirinda #singapore @norahlovesmakeup_mua idea? This is in Miami Beach.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/hudson'>Hudson</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.86046311,-80.1200069'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.86046311,-80.1200069&markers=25.86046311,-80.1200069&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Maracas Place' /></a><br/>Taken at Maracas Place</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301466906651656239_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I'm guessing it probably fell off of a passing cargo freighter, which most likely took on provisions in the port of Singapore. There's an ever so slight chance it washed up from further away, but most likely it is the boring explanation.</p>

<p>This was totally my Mr Sparkle moment though.</p>

<p>Now, the can is still sealed, so in theory the beverage should be consumable. It's in my fridge right now. I don't drink soda anymore though...</p>

<p>Oh, and I'm totally loving how things look at 1.2 during broad daylight. Very surreal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone summed it up eloquently...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T03:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jordyn-6643.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'It fell in line...'" ></p>

<p>While some tell me my strength lies in capturing images, I also have been told I can write well. However, in terms of writing, I do tend to ramble. Hence, this blog's tagline having the words "general ramblings"...</p>

<p>So, when someone asks for me to summarize something, it's nigh-impossible for me to do. So, if you asked me to sum up my own body of photographic work, I'd be at a loss to condense it to a sentence or two. I cringe at committing grammar crimes when I have to post to Twitter. The art of summary is lost to me.</p>

<p>However, someone summarized what I do so well for me just a few minutes ago...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it...</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And <em>boom</em>, that sums it up.</p>

<p>I could sit here for hours expounding on noise levels, a-to-d conversions, electric fields emanating from poorly-shielded cabling, the native ISO of a given sensor, and don't-point-your-lens-at-a-10-watt-laser-you-fool type of things and it wouldn't be a summary of how I manage to pull off a shot. It'd be the Book of Pod so to speak. Which, some people like, and some people don't.</p>

<p>It actually speaks volumes about having an outside opinion.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QtZ7SrAgIA/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4906bc4c14f011e2bacf123138179cfe_7.jpg' alt='You can see the guy about to jump out.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.82752892,-80.187165969'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.82752892,-80.187165969&markers=25.82752892,-80.187165969&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='55th Street Station' /></a><br/>Taken at 55th Street Station</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301010775764500992_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I had just come back from a nighttime run (yes Ryan, I do run around this neighborhood at 1 AM) and I picked up a text conversation where I had left it off earlier. My friend Adriana had just moved from the construction mess called Brickell, to a cozy new joint on Collins Avenue in "Condo Canyon" with her boyfriend. She was inviting me over for a little housewarming thing tomorrow, and she mentioned the last thing she had picked up from her old apt was a piece of mine that she purchased back in 2009:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/frances_2008.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Frances at Space - 2008'" ></p>

<p>I had done an exhibit of some of my "dancer photos" at the first <a href="http://lifeisart.org">Life Is Art</a> exhibit in Wynwood. Life is Art, by <a href="http://soulofmiami.org">Soul of Miami</a> founder James Echols, is a local organization that supports up-and-coming artists of all stripes. Since that first open show in 2009, they've come a long way and are quite renowned in the art community, especially amongst artists who may not be "hip" enough to warrant the attention of some of the more corporate art organizations in town. Adriana, at the time, was their treasurer, and had expressed an interest in obtaining a print of one of my images, specifically the one above. So, her mom took it upon herself to pull me aside and purchase it from me for her. As my exhibit was digital (I didn't have the budget to produce 20 prints of size), I took the "order" and contacted my print provider to generate a canvas-framed print for me of this piece. A few weeks later, it was delivered to Adriana, to much acclaim. Oddly enough it's the only "dancer" piece I have ever sold. Either I just haven't marketed them properly or people don't go for half-naked girls in smoky nightclubs as <em>objets d'art</em>.</p>

<p>Fast-forward to today. As pieces of art are often delicate, they are usually transported separately from other items in a moving adventure. Anyways, in a conversation about that piece tonight, Adriana was asking me about how I capture moments like that, and I did have a hard time summarizing it up. So, she put it into words that had previously escaped me:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it...</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And yes, that's it. Minus the technical details, which, if anyone asks, I'll gladly explain, that's pretty much it. I see the image in my head, and I wait for the world to fall in line. Whether it's in a club or below a deserted bridge in Key West, that's it. If I had to sum it up into a Twitter-friendly sentence, that is it.</p>

<p>Now, if I can summarize this post, it would be, "A different perspective always helps..."</p>

<p>Oh, and Ade, thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting video wide open.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T12:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51143544" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51143544">• 50 1.2 L video test wide open at 1.2 •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>Shooting video using the 50 1.2 L is an interesting experience, to say the least...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>One of the biggest things cinematographers and videographers, such as <a href="http://watcha3.com/">Buster</a> over at A3, have conveyed to me, is the desire to shoot at the lowest ISO possible when shooting video, preferably below ISO 1000, though I have gotten great results at ISO 1600, and I'll go beyond that, if I know the video is going to be laden with effects in post.</p>

<p>That being said, the obvious requirement to shoot at a low ISO is, lots of light. And "lots of light" in the video world, means something a bit different than in the world of still photography, for a few reasons.</p>

<p>First off, due to the nature of video, you are limited to a shutter speed, at the low end, of 1/30 second. Though, for the best results, most videographers, including <a href="http://blog.vincentlaforet.com">Vincent Laforet</a>, recommend a shutter speed of 1/50 second, to mesh better with common monitor refresh rates. So, almost by default, you are limited in your light gathering ability, when shooting video.</p>

<p>At that point, your options are, crank the ISO, open up as fast as your lens can go, or dump a lot of light on the scene. Or any combination thereof.</p>

<p>As an experiment, I chose to shoot the sequence above at ISO 320, 1/50 second shutter speed, all wide open at f1.2. As you can see, Caroline drifts in and out of the zone of critical focus on numerous occasions. However, the video quality is amazing. At ISO 320, the 5D MK II generates superb results. In reality I could have stopped down a bit, since the lighting tech at Blue Martini was kind enough to have the system running at maximum intensity at the time.</p>

<p>I can definitely recommend the 50 1.2 L for video work. It's a very versatile prime, and the image quality is amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
