<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gopro | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/gopro/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-28T01:50:15-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say, that's a nice camera...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/gearhead.jpg" width="960" height="203" title="'Go Pro on W210'" ></p>

<p>One of the most common questions that anyone in the photo or video industry gets asked, is, "<em>What sort of gear do you use?</em>"</p>

<p>Well, it's a reasonable question. The general public and professionals alike like to know that sort of thing, and it's a good conversation starter with anyone in the visual arts.</p>

<p>Me? What do I use?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My primary rig is a Canon 5D MK II full-frame DSLR for both still and video applications. Lenswise I have a 16-35 2.8 L, a 50 1.2 L, and a 70-200 2.8 L, all by Canon. And on the lighting end, a 580 EX flashgun (it goes pop and lights up things) and an ST-E2 wireless controller for the flash (so I can change the angle of light, etc...). And that's it, not counting a backup body. And of course some Macs for editing and heavy lifting.</p>

<p>It's a small assortment of gear, by no means a huge arsenal. Plus, when are in a more freeform situation such as an event or nightclub shoot, working with what you have on hand in a small satchel makes it far more interesting. This ethos is actually more and more common amongst professional photographers and videographers. Lenses and camera bodies aren't cheap, and it doesn't make sense to carry gear you don't use that often. So, a lot of pros on a budget and a lot who aren't, they simply rent.</p>

<p>The rise of photo gear rental house over the past decade has been phenomenal. All major cities have photo and video gear rental houses, such as <a href="http://aperturepro.com/"><strong>Aperture</strong></a> here in Miami, and online outlets such as <a href="http://lensrentals.com/"><strong>Lensrentals.com</strong></a> can ship just about any type of lens, camera body, lighting instrument, or accessory to your location overnight, and the rental rates are fiercely competitive. You can rent a $10,000 lens for a few hundred dollars a week. It's perfect for the one gig that requires it, or just plain old experimentation. I occasionally rent specialized lenses outside of my work just for experimentation. Sometimes I find a commercial use for it and end up purchasing it, as I did with the 50 1.2 L. I rented it repeatedly, and I ended up purchasing it as part of my permanent arsenal. It's also obviously a great way to audition gear you intend to buy.</p>

<p>And in the end, especially in these days when it's harder and harder for photographers and video pros to get a reasonable paycheck, every dollar saved counts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
