<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-08-17T16:33:08-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My first inbound link.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/17/my-first-inbound-link/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T16:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/17/my-first-inbound-link</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/car2go.png" width="512" height="369" title="'car 2 go'" ></p>

<p>Looks like Car 2 Go heard the noise I was making&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I don&#8217;t do advertorial or paid postings, it defeats the purpose of this blog, in my mind. Anything I talk about or endorse here is based on personal experience and not because someone paid me off. If I think something is useful or quality, I&#8217;ll post about it here. <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car 2 Go</a> is definitely a great service and worth what I pay for it. Keep up the good work guys.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been through the advertorial wringer before. It&#8217;s fun for a few minutes while you get paid, but after awhile, if you are posing as a legitimate news source, it does get tiring after awhile if you have any sort of humanity.</p>

<p>The sad thing is, advertisers and companies have come to expect advertorial as a standard practice these days. I&#8217;ve been around plenty of people and corporations when the question of the media and coverage for their product/brand/event comes up, and a notable amount of the discussion does center on the advertorial side of things. What&#8217;s even worse, is when you see what appear to be respectable news outlets going along for the advertorial ride.</p>

<p>Listen, as far as pure journalism goes, it&#8217;s a tough world out there now. Ad sales have dried up, and obviously it costs money to operate and maintain a decent news outlet. However, there are ways to cut costs and still maintain standards of ethical and journalistic integrity. A lot of &#8220;fat&#8221; can be cut on the infrastructure side of things, for example. This very blog is an example. While I don&#8217;t have it configured for true high-availability, I know I could scale it up as such where having this blog as an HA app wouldn&#8217;t break the bank. A little knowledge goes a long way.</p>

<p>I think, at the end of the day, journalists and news organizations should embrace being a bit multi-talented, enabling them to continue delivering unbiased news, without having to resort to deceptive advertorial processes.</p>

<p>And yes, I know the guilty parties in the advertorial game. Let&#8217;s just say it&#8217;s not too surprising. I&#8217;ll keep my own counsel for now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digging in the crates.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/digging-in-the-crates/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T17:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/digging-in-the-crates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://seenightlife.com/photos/15591/original_mixreunion-chilloutroom-mix.jpg" width="640" height="427" title="'The Mix'" ></p>

<p>I was doing a little digging today, and happened upon this little gem from when I was just getting started in my club shooting days.</p>

<p>Shot on film at South Beach&#8217;s then-notorious afterhours, called The Mix, I took it for a <em>class project</em> at UM no less.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I shot this frame on a roll of store-bought Fujicolor Xperia 400 film for my Intro to Color Photography and Printmaking (ART 3xx?) at UM in late 1999. We had to develop our own film, and then print it out on a very disagreeable Kreonite RA4 paper processor.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.dphoto.us/classifieds/data/5/6103promate1-large.jpg" width="672" height="504" title="'Kreonite'" ></p>

<p>Often offline, or out of service entirely, the printer, similar to the above, was a hotly-contested piece of hardware over in the photo lab at UM. The irony being of course the amount of money it cost to go to UM, and we were saddled with a creaky processor.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m sure nowadays, time has improved the department somewhat (sidebar, if anyone from the UM photo department reads this, I&#8217;d love to do a guest spot!), and the learning path is almost entirely digital.</p>

<p>Which begs the question, in the photo world, is it possible to effectively learn the fundamentals when you can immediately see the results?</p>

<p>In the real world, there are plenty of shooters out there who make a living of it, and have never touched film or learned the formalities. They shoot via the Golden BB method, hoping that if they spray enough projectiles in the air, one will hit the target. Personally, it seems like a waste, even in the digital realm. Plus I feel you don&#8217;t really learn if you depend on getting that one lucky photo in a session. I would much rather analyze the situation, set up accordingly, and push the shutter button once. I guess, in military terms, I&#8217;d be a sniper. One shot, one kill. I&#8217;m not in a hurry.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://seenightlife.com/photos/2008/original_dannyhowells001.jpg" width="640" height="427" title="'Danny Howells at Space'" ></p>

<p>Photos like the above weren&#8217;t composed with the Golden BB method. You only had a finite amount of frames to work with, and none could be deleted and reused. Each shot had to count, for the most part.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a more efficient and elegant workflow anyhow. Each image counts, rather than just one throwaway amongst many.</p>

<p>The benefits of digital technology on photography have been enormous, with digital sensors objectively outperforming film in almost all aspects. However, along the way, certain techniques and refinements have been lost. The Golden BB method is sadly prevalent, unfortunately.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best camera is the one you have on you.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/the-best-camera-is-the-one-you-have-on-you/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T02:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/the-best-camera-is-the-one-you-have-on-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://gallery.photo.net/photo/1232337-md.jpg" width="766" height="504" title="'Miami 2000'" ></p>

<p>The above is one of my favorite images that I&#8217;ve taken. The gear used consisted of a $200 Pentax ZX-5n film SLR, a roll of $8 Fuji 400 film I bought in a drugstore, and an $80 chunk of Sigma glass with no special features other than a macro function. It shows the Metromover tracks near the original location of Club Space, looking south towards Brickell. This was prior to the AA Arena, the &#8220;Biscayne Wall&#8221; of condos such as Ten Museum Park, 900 Biscayne, The Everglades, and so on, as well as more recent additions like The Marquis. Almost a Miami of old at this point.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, I managed to capture the subtle tones of the sunrise and the remnants of the evening mixed with the street and track lighting. Kind of an early attempt at my current fascination with scenics, I guess.</p>

<p>Without my description, most would have guessed I captured this with a decent digital SLR, or if they had an eye for Miami and the time depicted, a fairly top-of-the-range film body and lens. The reality is, I grabbed this frame with less than $300 worth of equipment. On film. Most club photographers have never touched film. I still have to take action on this, but one of these weekends, I&#8217;m going to shoot a few rolls of film at Space for the hell of it.</p>

<p>A lot of photographers, professional and otherwise, are victims of gear lust. Sure, I am too, but since I got started, I always tried to hold true to the ethic of &#8220;The best camera is the one you have on you&#8221;.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s akin to what is taught in military academies around the country, &#8220;You go to war with the army you have, not the one you want&#8221;. You are basically limited by your situation and your budget. Budget, obviously, because not every working professional can justify or afford a 1-series Canon body or a Nikon D4. And situationally, since it isn&#8217;t always practical to carry around a large digital SLR and several lenses everywhere you go.</p>

<p>For the longest time, I shot with crop-frame mid-range digital SLRs. My work level and situation made stepping up to a full-frame body like the 5D MK II an unrealistic proposition. Maybe not so unrealistic, but more of me being cautious. My existing camera bodies generated superb images in my hands, and there was no pressing need to upgrade. I only finally upgraded to the 5D MK II when it made sense for me to do so, since several clients were asking for video work, and the 5D MK II made the most sense for my shooting style. And even then, the 5D MK II was a three year-old piece of hardware, which still generated superb images in the hands of an experienced shooter.</p>

<p>But regardless, due to the situation I was in at the time, I lacked independent transport. I took the bus everywhere. And I bought my SLR kit with me, out of necessity, since I&#8217;d often be on my way to or from a shoot. Even if I wasn&#8217;t specifically shooting something, I always feared I&#8217;d get a call-up to shoot something right away, and my gear would be several bus rides or an expensive cab journey away, if I didn&#8217;t have it on me. Very cumbersome way of conducting business. Obviously when I acquired my own independent transport, this became less of a problem as I could stow my gear in my trunk (a scary proposition in some areas), or keep it at home, but still be able to buzz back to base and snag it if the need arose.</p>

<p>However, the news or &#8220;that specific situation&#8221; doesn&#8217;t always wait for me to rocket down I-95 at 100 MPH and skid over to my apartment to pick up my gear. So, the camera I may have on me at that moment is my iPhone 4s. The cameras inside phones have come a long way. The 4s is still, as of this writing, the undisputed champ in my mind, especially when coupled with decent photo apps from the App Store. One of my favorites is <a href="http://www.awesomize.com/"> Camera Awesome</a>. Developed by Smugmug, Camera Awesome has an ingenious system for focusing, exposure, as well as a basic suite of post-production tools, enabling you to crank out an acceptable JPEG in a hurry if the need arises. It also integrates with Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, and standard email.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ca.png" width="640" height="960" title="'Camera Awesome'" ></p>

<p>I&#8217;ve cranked out plenty of what I consider decent images using this little app. Several more exist, such as Hipstamatic and so forth, but Camera Awesome seems to be more geared towards those with a modicum of photo knowledge.</p>

<p>With this in mind, I actually don&#8217;t freak out as much when I leave my MK II behind, like if I am going out to a purely social occasion somewhere and it&#8217;s impractical or impolite to be carrying a giant bag of gear around, and maybe not the best idea in the world to leave it in the trunk of your vehicle. Since, I know I have my iPhone with a decent app close at hand, and know how to work with and around it&#8217;s limitations. I won&#8217;t be generating prize-winning work anytime soon with my iPhone, but I&#8217;m actually pretty impressed with the results. I work with the camera I have on me when the situation arises, I don&#8217;t muck about wishing I bought my full-size rig. Though that being said, 95 percent of the time I do have my equipment within ten feet of me. It&#8217;s the 5 percent of the rest of the time I&#8217;ve learned to calm down about and not worry about it. I know I can pop off a decent iPhone photo at any time if the situation demands it.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m of course not suggesting everyone ditch their SLRs for iPhones, but at the same time, don&#8217;t be susceptible to gear lust. Sometimes you just need to make do with what you have. And actually, when you work with what you have, a lot of the time, the end results will surprise you.</p>

<p>FYI, if anyone is interested in seeing my attempts at iPhone photography, check out my Instacanvas gallery (prints of my Instagrams) at <a href="http://instacanv.as/pod_gram">instacanv.as/pod_gram</a>. It&#8217;s cheap!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We can't make art from air.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T22:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage8.instagram.com/5ba9a3d8e32611e1a4431231381407ca_7.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Gear and girl'" ></p>

<p>I got into a discussion just now over on <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=6&t=19857">Talk Nightlife</a> with James, founder of <a href="http://soulofmiami.org/">Soul of Miami</a> about some of the trials and tribulations of the photographers and photo editors in the Olympics. I linked on over to a <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/photographers-blog/2012/08/10/click-edit-crop-or-drop/">blog post on Reuters</a> about the workflow of their on-site photo team. James&#8217; comment was that it was fascinating, but essentially <strong>&#8220;It really does not seem like they could possibly be getting paid enough for that.&#8221;</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
Sadly, that is the truth. However, most of us whom are into the photo and video industries aren&#8217;t into it for a big payday. Sure, income is nice, but at the end of the day, a photo career is a lot of hard work, and is often times frustrating, and the income rarely is there.</p>

<p>Sure, every guy and girl behind the lens has fantasies of one day making that &#8216;big score&#8217;, and not having to work again, but in most cases, that never happens. They might make what would be equivalent to mid-to-high five figures on average per year, but most of that money gets eaten up in taxes, reinvesting in the business, and general expenses associated with running said business. It&#8217;s why if you see a photographer with a bunch of fancy non-photo-related toys, chances are that he or she probably has a second source of money, whether it&#8217;s a &#8220;real job&#8221;, another business that pays real money, or comes from money and happens to have a &#8220;hobby&#8221;. And yes, there&#8217;s always the slight chance that they scored and are living quite well off of their photo incomes.</p>

<p>Since the digital revolution, the intrinsic monetary value of photography has gone down enormously. A lot of shooters struggle to stay afloat and often have to make concessions and do other things to make ends meet. I&#8217;m a perfect example. I earn money from photography and video, but I have to tinker with websites and take on odd tasks related to the web to make ends meet. I&#8217;m very frugal but things still cost money. Also, it is a bit more costly to obtain basic health insurance on your own, than it is if you are part of a standard corporate entity.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s actually why I&#8217;ve come around a bit on the whole government-provided healthcare issue actually. I&#8217;m for small government, but I do think one of the duties of the government is to take care of it&#8217;s taxpayers. I think that if we&#8217;re taken care of on a basic level by state health insurance, that would actually free us, as a people, up to take more risks in business and our personal lives. I know a lot of people with big ideas and dreams, who don&#8217;t want to leave their corporate gigs, because said gigs provide the benefit of health insurance. And, obviously those corporate gigs demand a fair share of one&#8217;s time and energy. But the healthcare rant is another post entirely. Hey, it&#8217;s my blog, I don&#8217;t have to necessarily adhere to standard editorial guidelines.</p>

<p>But anyways, society as a whole has come to devalue the work of photographers. Now, at no point has a photography career ever been a sure path to untold riches or success. Whether the workflow was analog or digital, it&#8217;s always been the rare person who made their millions off of photography. And if they did make their millions off of it, chances are they are dead or pretty close to it, and the value of their work has increased by virtue of that. Suffice to say, the quickest way to increase the value of your photography is to die, preferably in a dramatic fashion.</p>

<p>All jokes aside though, the value, and the respect of the art has been diminished somewhat over the past decade. And it has been a two-pronged assault, from without, and from within. From without, it&#8217;s been clients seeking the cheap way out. Even the most professional organizations expect to be able to pay only a pittance for work. A campaign that might cost thousands on the part of the photographer to execute, the client might only be willing to pay a few hundred dollars for. Of course everyone wants to spend as little as possible, but there is a point where the client base does need to remember that &#8216;they get what they pay for&#8217;. You only pay a few hundred dollars, well, that is about all the work you will get. Someone recently offered me $50 and a bucket of booze to shoot a party. I blew them off, it wasn&#8217;t even worth a response. Everyone knows I like to have a drink or two, but I won&#8217;t work for that sort of thing. I have bills to pay. And $50 would not cover my own nightly expenses, as the gig was on South Beach (no Car2Go), and of course my time in post and editing.
If you want to pay me $50, I&#8217;d expect a chauffeured ride to and from the venue, and I&#8217;ll probably take three photos, steal your girlfriend, and not bother delivering the edit (1 photo) until sometime in 2025.</p>

<p>And that&#8217;s just the problem from without. The problem from within is almost as bad. The digital revolution has put quality imaging tools into the hands of all. For $400 or less (say, a used Drebel kit), one can obtain a quality digital SLR with a basic lens. Under decent lighting conditions, this kit can objectively shoot great images, even in the hands of an amateur. And said images could conceivably be used for commercial purposes with the right editing and post production. So, now, businesses can hire &#8220;some guy they know&#8221;, or &#8220;do it in-house&#8221; (though there&#8217;s nothing wrong with an staff shooter in some instances, as long as rights and releases are fair), and attempt to save a buck or two, and have &#8220;some guy they know&#8221; fix any of the problems later, or leave the fixing to some beleaguered designer at a graphic design firm somewhere. Sidebar: graphic designers hate that.</p>

<p>When confronted, the businesses and the shooters themselves will often plead ignorance, or claim that &#8220;this is the way things are now, deal with it&#8221;.
Understandably, the dynamics of the digital economy have changed things, but photographers and other visual professionals do need to have an income to survive and keep providing these services to clients. If all photography was cheap and/or free, eventually there would be no photographers to generate the images clients require and need. And computer rendering of realistic scenes is far more expensive (to do right) than booking the services of a photographer, so don&#8217;t try to get me there!</p>

<p>What&#8217;s even worse is the lack of understanding of licensing and rights, as well. Very few businesses understand this. They treat all photographic work for them as work-for-hire, with unlimited use. To them, once the photo is taken, it is theirs. It doesn&#8217;t work that way. Licensing and sale is one of the only ways a photographer can stand a chance of making a reasonable living nowadays, especially in the situations I&#8217;ve described above. And very few photographers understand it as well as they should. It took me awhile to get a handle on it, but once one understands the ins and outs of it, it&#8217;s easy to figure out.
In this case, Google is your friend. Search for &#8220;editorial photography rate guidelines&#8221; and go from there. I&#8217;m not being lazy, there is just a huge amount of information on pricing your work accordingly. FYI, it&#8217;s why a decent-sized print of mine will run you a few hundred dollars or more at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> page.</p>

<p>Again, we&#8217;re in this because we love to do it, not because we&#8217;re seeking a route to glorious riches and untold glory. All anyone behind the lens asks for is just compensation to cover the costs of doing business, and enjoy life while we&#8217;re at it. I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s many photographers out there whom are greedy and driven by dollar signs. Even we like to put the camera down sometimes and take a little vacation somewhere. With a smaller camera of course, we might see something interesting along the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Car2Go Cheaper Than a Cab.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/car2go-cheaper-than-a-cab/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T13:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/car2go-cheaper-than-a-cab</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/210smart.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'210 and Smart'" ></p>

<p>I love my current car. The W210 Mercedes-Benz E320 is a solid performer. A cruiser if you will, it&#8217;s built for cruising the highways at speed. I&#8217;m not gonna beat an SLS off the line in acceleration, but I can easily cruise at 85+ MPH in the express lanes on I-95 without difficulty.</p>

<p>That being said, when I go out to shoot at a nightclub, I&#8217;m hesitant to take it out. Parking in a safe area is costly, and of course presents several safety concerns. No matter how &#8216;secure&#8217; a lot is, there&#8217;s still a fair amount of unmonitored traffic shuffling in and out of a lot during the course of a night, any of them whom could be a potential vandal or thief, looking for a score. Or even someone who just isn&#8217;t looking where they are going and decides that it&#8217;s time to bump into my vehicle.</p>

<p>So, when I go out to shoot, I usually take the cab, or the bus. Living just off of Biscayne Boulevard makes both options doable.</p>

<p>Both those options have negatives though.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p><strong>The Cab</strong> - The cab costs money. From my place to say, <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space</a>, for example, is $11 plus tip (you do remember to tip your driver, don&#8217;t you?) on average. Also, cabs may not be immediately available during peak times, whether you stand outside or dial 305-888-8888.</p>

<p><strong>The Bus</strong> - The 3 bus, while cheap, only runs once a hour after 11 PM. And, the arrival time at your stop, though listed at say, 1:35 AM, can vary up to 20 minutes. Not fun when it&#8217;s warm out and there&#8217;s some of the local characters coming out of the Motel South Pacific. I&#8217;m not threatened by them, of course, but it can give one pause.</p>

<p>Those were my only two options aside from driving, until about a few weeks ago.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car 2 Go</a>. A brand of Daimler (Mercedes), Car 2 Go is a car-share service that&#8217;s been successful in Europe for a few years now. They recently launched in Miami, dropping around 240 blue-and-white Smart Fortwos around town. Finding some previous press and a handy promo code, I decided to sign up. Since you only pay for what you use, just having the membership costs nothing. Other share services have monthly fees, apparently. Also, Car 2 Go is a &#8220;one way&#8221; service, you don&#8217;t have to return the car to a lot, you can just leave it at any City of Miami-run parking meter.</p>

<p>So, with this in mind, I decided to try a little experiment.</p>

<p>I was schedule to shoot at Space this past Saturday, much like every other Saturday for the past decade or so. Usually, I would take a cab or the bus for the reasons I mentioned above. However, this time, I decided to try out my new C2G membership for a real task rather than just an excuse to test a Smart car out. Using C2G&#8217;s handy iOS app, I found a car about a block from my apartment.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/c2g.png" width="640" height="960" title="'iOS Car 2 Go'" ></p>

<p>Yes, it was 3:40 in the morning. I had a friend&#8217;s going-away party prior, so sue me.</p>

<p>As you can see, there was one 90 meters and change away from me. So, I slung my goodie bag onto my back, and walked to the vehicle.</p>

<p>After I boarded, I did the usual login procedures, and checked the time.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage0.instagram.com/6bd181b4e45111e1ae7122000a1e86bb_7.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Onboard Insta'" ></p>

<p>I drove down Biscayne Boulevard at a reasonable speed and arrived at an empty City parking spot a block from Space around 7 minutes later.</p>

<p>Car 2 Go charges you 38 cents a minute to drive. There&#8217;s no membership fee or paying for parking or gas. If you need gas there&#8217;s a Wright Fleet fuel card inside. I think they give you credits if you have to stop and put gas in, even. So, .38 x 7 = 2.66, give or take a minute or so.</p>

<p>A cab, like I mentioned, is $11.00 plus tip. The bus is $2.00 flat but you have to kind of estimate when it&#8217;s going to show up.</p>

<p>So, for this situation, Car 2 Go was a clear winner.</p>

<p>Of course, this only works if you live in the City of Miami, and there&#8217;s a vehicle near you. Also, for me it was a 1-way trip, since I left Space around 9 AM, and I had had a few drinks. Obviously with C2G, you have to obey all the normal rules of the road! A kind friend who works at Space was nice enough to drive me home, so my total transport bill for the evening was $2.66. Even if I took a cab home, I would have still come out ahead.</p>

<p>I can definitely recommend Car 2 Go. Besides, even though the Smart drives like an angry golf cart, it&#8217;s kind of fun to drive when you flip it over to manual.</p>

<p>Check &#8216;em out at <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">car2go.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Redrock Micro.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T12:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/redrock.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Redrock'" ></p>

<p>Yesterday, I had the fortunate opportunity to work with <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Alex Martinez</a> and <a href="http://michaelraveney.com/">Michael Raveney</a> on the next spot for the upcoming <a href="http://ur1festival.com/">UR1 Festival</a>.</p>

<p>Alex, as some of my fans know, provides excellent graphic design work (including my own logo), and Michael is a prominent fashion and editorial photographer here in Miami.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>The project we were all working on was a spot for the forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>. Produced by <strong>Emi Guerra</strong> and <strong>Alex Omes</strong>, the UR1 Festival takes place during Art Basel and will combine all genres of music and art into one helluva massive party. Count me in. I should &#8220;lean&#8221; on my good friend Emi and get some of my pieces featured therein.</p>

<p>But anyways, we were all tasked to film an upcoming piece promoting the festival. Alex and Michael conceptualized it, and my task was to be the &#8220;fly on the wall&#8221; and document the making of said piece. I was the documentarian. Excellent. However, I didn&#8217;t relish the thought of hours of holding my MK II at arms length.</p>

<p>For all the pluses of using a DSLR for video, the one major flaw is that that the DSLR form factor is entirely wrong for shooting video. Holding a front-heavy body at arms length results in very unsteady compositions. So, on the way up to Michael&#8217;s studio, I popped into <a href="http://aperturepro.com">Aperture</a>. After a brief consultation, I rented a <a href="http://redrockmicro.com/">Redrock Micro</a> mount for my MK II.</p>

<p>Without getting too much into the particulars, this definitely made my life easier. The weight distribution matched that of a traditional video camera, and made my handheld jitters that much more stable. I could glide my shots through the space with ease, and not worry about having to deal with stabilization in post.</p>

<p>Some may blanch at the pricing on Redrock&#8217;s equipment though. From $350 to well over $1000 depending on the options, it&#8217;s not cheap. Some suggest using the Chinese knock-off versions on eBay for $150 or less, but in my experience, the Chinese knockoffs are just that, knockoffs, and are prone to falling apart at the wrong time. Live a little, and spend for the Redrock. I know I will.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be posting some of the results after we complete the edit of the video for UR1. We gotta keep it on the down-low, you know.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts1.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts2.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say, that's a nice camera...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/gearhead.jpg" width="960" height="203" title="'Go Pro on W210'" ></p>

<p>One of the most common questions that anyone in the photo or video industry gets asked, is, &#8221;<em>What sort of gear do you use?</em>&#8221;</p>

<p>Well, it&#8217;s a reasonable question. The general public and professionals alike like to know that sort of thing, and it&#8217;s a good conversation starter with anyone in the visual arts.</p>

<p>Me? What do I use?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My primary rig is a Canon 5D MK II full-frame DSLR for both still and video applications. Lenswise I have a 16-35 2.8 L, a 50 1.2 L, and a 70-200 2.8 L, all by Canon. And on the lighting end, a 580 EX flashgun (it goes pop and lights up things) and an ST-E2 wireless controller for the flash (so I can change the angle of light, etc&#8230;). And that&#8217;s it, not counting a backup body. And of course some Macs for editing and heavy lifting.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a small assortment of gear, by no means a huge arsenal. Plus, when are in a more freeform situation such as an event or nightclub shoot, working with what you have on hand in a small satchel makes it far more interesting. This ethos is actually more and more common amongst professional photographers and videographers. Lenses and camera bodies aren&#8217;t cheap, and it doesn&#8217;t make sense to carry gear you don&#8217;t use that often. So, a lot of pros on a budget and a lot who aren&#8217;t, they simply rent.</p>

<p>The rise of photo gear rental house over the past decade has been phenomenal. All major cities have photo and video gear rental houses, such as <a href="http://aperturepro.com/"><strong>Aperture</strong></a> here in Miami, and online outlets such as <a href="http://lensrentals.com/"><strong>Lensrentals.com</strong></a> can ship just about any type of lens, camera body, lighting instrument, or accessory to your location overnight, and the rental rates are fiercely competitive. You can rent a $10,000 lens for a few hundred dollars a week. It&#8217;s perfect for the one gig that requires it, or just plain old experimentation. I occasionally rent specialized lenses outside of my work just for experimentation. Sometimes I find a commercial use for it and end up purchasing it, as I did with the 50 1.2 L. I rented it repeatedly, and I ended up purchasing it as part of my permanent arsenal. It&#8217;s also obviously a great way to audition gear you intend to buy.</p>

<p>And in the end, especially in these days when it&#8217;s harder and harder for photographers and video pros to get a reasonable paycheck, every dollar saved counts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the audacity of scooter riders.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/on-the-audacity-of-scooter-riders/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T16:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/on-the-audacity-of-scooter-riders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/scoot2.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Scoot'" ></p>

<p>One of my pet peeves since moving here ages ago has been the scooter rider.</p>

<p>Now, I recognize the utility of the scooter. It&#8217;s light, efficient, and you can stow it almost
anywhere when not in use. Plus, you don&#8217;t need insurance, and LEOs tend to leave you be.</p>

<p>It is probably the last one which makes scooter riders so obnoxious&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Before I acquired my current mode of personal transport, I would either take public transit, or on occasion, have
the use of a friend&#8217;s scooter. They&#8217;re fun to ride, and useful for getting around the Beach and the Downtown area.
However, being that there&#8217;s nothing between you and the road but your clothes, I tended to ride cautiously, knowing that
I&#8217;m not as visible as I would be in a car or truck. It was up to me to watch where I was going.</p>

<p>However, most scooter riders do not. They ride like they own the road, and expect other motorists to watch out for them.
Now, realistically, that is fair since they have the lighter and less powerful vehicle. But fair only if they are obeying the
same rules of the road the rest of us try to do. For the most part, scooter riders around here tend to weave in and out of traffic
with abandon, often in packs. You see the &#8216;pack&#8217; phenomenon on Memorial Day Weekend, when herds of tourists rent every available
scooter on the Beach and troll Washington Avenue in packs of twenty or more, as if they were some sort of mentally-challenged
chapter of the Hell&#8217;s Angels.</p>

<p>Worse yet, your average scooter rider will blame you for any of their indiscretions on the road.</p>

<p>Case in point. Yesterday, I was leaving the Publix complex on Fifth and Alton. As I eased on to Lenox Avenue into the flow of traffic,
a kid, dare I say a <em>chmak</em>, on a Vespa was closing in on me rather fast. Now, the light ahead of me was red, so myself and the drivers in front of me clearly could not
move. The scooter rider, rather than stop and join the flow of traffic as he would have been required to do, swerved to the <em>right</em> of me and
the rest of the cars in the lane, choosing to wedge his noisy lawn-mower-sounding contraption between all of us and the sidewalk. My outraged
fellow car drivers honked in protest as he wedged through, only to be met by a stream of incoherent curses and curiously random gestures which
may have passed for obscene in some far-flung nation on the other side of the world. I suppose flailing your arms about and screaming could
be considered an obscene gesture, somewhere. There&#8217;s a lot of people on this planet. All the while, this kid&#8217;s conveyance was still in forward
motion.</p>

<p>Someone less kind than me could have taken exception to that, actually. This is Miami, after all. The kid on the Vespa is damn lucky in that
regard.</p>

<p>Scooter riders, scoot all you want, but realize it&#8217;s a two-way street. You&#8217;re on a motor vehicle too. It&#8217;s a scooter, not a Hayabusa.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A year back in Miami.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/a-year-back-in-miami/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T14:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/a-year-back-in-miami</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/skyline-7023_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Downtown Miami'" ></p>

<p><b>Support this site! Buy a print of the Miami Skyline pictured above over at my <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/downtown-miami-2012-dan-vidal.html">FAA Gallery</a>.</b></p>

<p>It&#8217;s been a year since I&#8217;ve gotten back to Miami. I beat to death the <a href="http://dvdigital.tumblr.com/post/9305311687/miami-versus-vegas-since-ive-been-back-people">differences between Miami and Vegas</a>
over on my old Tumblr, so I won&#8217;t get into it here all over again.</p>

<p>In a nutshell though, absence made the heart grow fonder, and despite the faults of Miami, I&#8217;m still glad I came back.</p>

<p>A lot of people rain on Miami&#8217;s parade at any opportunity. The &#8220;lack of culture&#8221; and the lack of &#8220;real&#8221; opportunities outside of the world of
hospitality and tourism usually factor into most people&#8217;s discussions about the downsides of living in this area.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>However, if you look closer, Miami is a very young city. Founded in 1896, it is the oldest municipality in South Florida. The area was settled prior to that, but no real development occurred until then. So, as it were, the city, and the area in general, have a scant 150 years of history to support it. Cultural meccas like Boston and New York have centuries of cultural development. Nonetheless, even with the relative age of our society here, certain things considered &#8220;cultural&#8221; have definitely taken hold. Gatherings and events like Art Walk and of course the almighty Art Basel Miami exemplify this. Along with our crop of homegrown musical talent, which spans way beyond the stereotypical &#8220;Latin&#8221; sound. Groups like ArtOfficial and Spam All-Stars are in the global music scene representing the 305, as it were.</p>

<p>Now, on the subject of opportunity. A lot of people bemoan the lack of &#8220;real&#8221; companies having branches or operations here. The fact is, they do. Most major corporations, ranging from heavyweights like Xerox and Canon, to more specialized outfits like Diageo (liquor) have their Latin American headquarters here. Along the same lines, the major South American banks are headquartered here for reasons of safety and stability, and proximity to their home countries. However, it&#8217;s the lack of &#8220;corporatism&#8221; in where Miami can shine. A city like Miami is ripe for the spirit of self-employment and entrepreneurship. Even educated people who choose to locate here, often start their own business in any number of fields, including &#8220;Miami typical&#8221; ones like hospitality, entertainment, the arts, and music, or even unexpected fields like software development and engineering. I personally know several local talented software developers who work from home or small office spaces on projects that are headquartered around the globe.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s actually people like these who represent the future of doing things. I see cities like Miami becoming immensely popular as a living location as self-employment and telecommuting become more and more accepted and popular. And why not? Most common tasks in any business environment don&#8217;t require much more than a computer with an internet connection, with the office space being a mere formality and comforter for employers. Of course, for such things to take hold, a sea change in our attitudes towards work and employment need to happen. I&#8217;ll leave that for another rant entirely.</p>

<p>However, it&#8217;s this unconventional environment which drew me here, and drew me back home after my absence. The travel opportunities were fun, but there&#8217;s definitely no place like home.</p>

<p>Besides, being unconventional is fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond nightlife...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/beyond-nightlife-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/beyond-nightlife-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<p>I venture outside of the world of nightlife in my shooting when possible. While challenging as it is to shoot in that sort of environment &#8220;my way&#8221;, even more of a challenge is to take something rather common, the landscape photograph, and put my own spin on it.</p>

<p>What I like to find is a mix of the works of humans with the works of nature. So, on a drive to Key West one evening, I had it in my mind to try to capture a sunset off of one of the islands on the way down to Key West.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>One of the frustrations of that, is that it isn&#8217;t always possible to get that ideal angle, simply due to the traffic situation on the way down. Unless you plan way in advance (which I should have), you have to deal with the vagaries of only having one main road the entire way. Thus you can find yourself stuck behind some slow-movers, just as that magic hour hits.</p>

<p>I was gauging an ideal destination based on an earlier trip I had made a few weeks prior. I didn&#8217;t make it all the way down to Key West, but I had dropped a few pins on my iPhone&#8217;s map utility, to mark a few places. The one I had in mind was close, but traffic wasn&#8217;t cooperating. So, when the ideal time hit, I took a gamble and pulled over next to this bridge.</p>

<p>The wind was whipping about like crazy, to the point where I had to fight to stabilize both myself and my camera, despite a heavy-duty Manfrotto tripod. Eventually, I settled into the scene, and ended up composing the above. Much like an expert sniper, I knew I &#8220;had it&#8221; even before the RAW data worked it&#8217;s way through my MK II&#8217;s processors and appeared on the screen. Initially a little underexposed to preserve the sky detail (you can always adjust your exposure upwards later, it&#8217;s much harder to adjust downwards and bring out detail, even in RAW), I could still see the end result in my head, which is represented above.</p>

<p>While I&#8217;m fairly new to landscape photography, I can definitely appreciate the skill it takes to get the image, both from a technical and a logistical perspective. Preparation helps, but sometimes you just have to be ready for the moment to hit.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be posting more images in this theme as time goes on, both from my back catalog, and new works as I produce them.</p>

<p>And now a word from our sponsor&#8230;me.</p>

<p><i>Enjoy &#8216;Islamorada Crossing&#8217;? Why not purchase a quality printed copy of it for yourself or someone special? Point your browsers over to my <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/islamorada-crossing-dan-vidal.html">print provider (click/tap!)</a> and get your copy today. Available in a whole range of sizes and finishes. Use discount code &#8216;GZTFYJ&#8217; to get 20 percent off your final order price. I definitely appreciate the business!</i></p>

<p>Yes, even I have to eat on occasion.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with the GoPro]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/i-fell-in-love-with-the-gopro/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T17:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/i-fell-in-love-with-the-gopro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I borrowed a Go Pro from my friend <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis Rogers</a> after I saw him using one at <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space.</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/46475090" width="960" height="540" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/46475090">GoPro Test</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>I wasn&#8217;t really interested in it as a club tool, though I could see it being useful as a B-camera for some in-the-booth shots. Where I found the most thrill though, was mounting it to the bumper of my car, and driving around Miami. In the video above, you can see some of the results. I&#8217;m not the sharpest editor yet, but the footage speaks for itself, I think. The GoPro is great for what it costs, and will be even better when they roll the new &#8220;ProTune&#8221; firmware any day now and really pump the bitrate.</p>

<p>And yes, this is a blatant excuse to see if Vimeo embedding works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some words on my style]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/some-words-on-my-style/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T15:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/some-words-on-my-style</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tort-9921.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn Hartlein on the box at Space'" ></p>

<p>A lot of people ask me why I shoot like I do, when it comes to nightlife and concerts. Well, there&#8217;s many reasons.</p>


<p>Nowadays, with the ubiquity of the &#8216;nightlife photographer&#8217;, or &#8216;the guy with the blog&#8217; (yes, I&#8217;m well aware that I&#8217;m writing this on a blog platform), one has to strive to differentiate themselves in order to be unique, stand out, and get work. Even if your end goal isn&#8217;t necessarily financially-oriented (and it shouldn&#8217;t be, you aren&#8217;t going to get rich shooting concerts and clubs, it&#8217;s something you have to like to do), your job or vision is easier to pull off if you can develop a coherent style to call your own.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&#8217;ve been working in clubs for about fifteen years now. I started by helping my friend John, now the owner of <a href="http://alchemyavcs.com/">Alchemy Audio Visual Systems</a> with lugging around his nascent rig of EAW speaker cabinets and Crown amplifiers, and doing double duty as his light tech. We provided reinforcement for local punk bands and some DJ shows as well. I was also majoring in motion picture production and fine art photography at the <a href="http://miami.edu/">University of Miami</a>, and working for their IT department as well.</p>

<p>Anyways, I managed to work my nighttime activities into legitimate coursework for my photography classes. I would shoot some of the bands and our lighting setups, when time permitted. Early on, one of the biggest &#8220;rules&#8221; of most venues, if they were cool with me shooting at all, was that flash photography was frowned upon or genuinely prohibited around the performers of the evening. Totally understandable, for two reasons. First off, if you are DJing or playing an instrument, a flash blowing off in your field of vision can be distracting, or even dangerous, if you are the sort of performer who tends to be very dynamic. Also, and this forms the basis of my style, the performers are usually well-lit, or can be at request.</p>

<p>Basically, there&#8217;s a lot of light around if you know how to use it. Nightclubs and concert halls are generally regarded as being dark and dingy, but there is a lot of light within them. LED screens, flat panel displays, swirling intelligent lights, the glow from POS terminals, even candlelight. It can all be used to pull off an effective photo, while not having to resort to using flash photography. Now, there is nothing inherently wrong with flash photography. Used properly, it can provide a wonderful balance to a scene. Used improperly, the results can be substandard, and the act of taking the photo itself can be distracting. One of the keys to successful concert and nightclub photography in my mind is to blend in with the scenery. People tend to be themselves if they think you are one of the crowd, and not some guy with an SLR looking for attention, free entry, and cheap laughs. We all know that guy, he&#8217;s not nice.</p>

<p>Of course, working with the light that is there presents some challenges. Invariably you are operating at a very shallow depth-of-field, a slow shutter speed, a high ISO, or all three. I won&#8217;t get into it in this post, but all three can be compensated for, especially high ISO. High ISO is the easiest to compensate for, actually. Flat out accept the noise. It&#8217;s there, use it and move on. ISO 6400 on a modern DSLR is actually more usable than ISO 1600 on a roll of Fujicolor from the 1990s, even without noise reduction.</p>

<p>So basically, my style is the result of the environment I generally shoot in, and my ethos of blending in with the crowd rather than being the focus of it.
<img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tort-9712.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Work it.'" ></p>

<p>Use the light that&#8217;s there, you might surprise yourself.</p>

<p>(Oh, and this is only a test - I&#8217;ll add photos in a bit)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress might be what the doctor ordered]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/octopress-might-be-what-the-doctor-ordered/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T02:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/octopress-might-be-what-the-doctor-ordered</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first post. There will be many more like it. Hopefully this works. I don&#8217;t want to use a canned blog engine.</p>


<!-- more -->


<p>Then they click and come here and see the full post.</p>


<p><img src="http://gentle-sierra-7932.herokuapp.com/img/tort-9921.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/logo270.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
