<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T16:40:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram And Their New Terms And Conditions...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/18/instagram-and-their-new-terms-and-conditions-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T16:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/18/instagram-and-their-new-terms-and-conditions-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/18//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/TY8Z9BggGq/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage2.s3.amazonaws.com/bfbdd036494911e2b23022000a1f9ad5_7.jpg' alt='Some @zhantra action @lisichka1805 @clubspacemiami #igersmiami #miami #305 #dancer #dj' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784654534,-80.193132211'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784654534,-80.193132211&markers=25.784654534,-80.193132211&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='349294637422346666_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Over the past few days, there&#8217;s been a bit of a furor over the changed Terms &amp; Conditions over at <a href="http://instagram.com/">Instagram</a>. As an avid user of the service, hell, it&#8217;s pretty much the only major social media service I don&#8217;t have a huge dislike for, I was, of course, a little concerned&#8230;</p>

<!--more -->




<blockquote><p>You agree that a business or other entity may pay us to display your username, likeness, photos (along with any associated metadata), and/or actions you take, in connection with paid or sponsored content or promotions, without any compensation to you.</p></blockquote>


<p>This little damning bit of text sent the Instagram community into a tailspin. People cried foul, many cried &#8220;copryright!&#8221;, and more than a few threatened to walk away&#8230;but from where I sit today, Instagram is still there, and material is still flowing to it, unabated.</p>

<p>Instagram is a free service. Recently acquired by Facebook, Instagram allows you, the user, to post photos onto their service without charge, and you can even advertise your services and goods through those photos, for free, and Instagram doesn&#8217;t see a dime of any income you might earn from that advertising. Now, on Instagram you cannot tap on hyperlinks to go to an external website, so in other words, for any external action to be completed, the text must be copied and pasted to your browser. It&#8217;s not an ideal system. However, considering it&#8217;s free and easy, it&#8217;s not to be entirely disregarded. Just don&#8217;t expect large-scale results from it.</p>

<p>And now, because it is free, Instagram does reserve the right to do whatever they want with the content you post to it, including reselling it. Instagram was purchased by Facebook for a shade under 1 billion US Dollars. That&#8217;s right, a billion with a <em>b</em>. So, Facebook has to make their money back somehow. One way is by placing ads within the Instagram stream. That&#8217;s coming soon. Don&#8217;t be surprised if targeted ads, probably similar to Pandora, make their way into your Instagram feed sometime over the next few months. Also, Instagram will probably be taking photos from their servers, photos that you uploaded, and attempting to resell them on the open market. Fair is fair. Something for something.</p>

<p>And yes, a lot of people are mad about this.</p>

<p>I sure was.</p>

<p>But then I realized a few key things:</p>

<blockquote><p>Images on Instagram are compressed by the app locally on your phone and uploaded to IG&#8217;s servers at 612 x 612 pixels, and a fair amount of compression is applied.</p></blockquote>




<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/18//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/TZE207ggNs/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage4.s3.amazonaws.com/10ba0f9a495411e2b7d622000a1f968a_7.jpg' alt='They can try to use this if they want. #igersmiami #miami #305 
#5dmkii' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='349331805968663404_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>This image is one I posted to Instagram just now. It&#8217;s 612 x 612 at 72 PPI. At print resolution that&#8217;s maybe 2 inches by 2 inches. Less since I&#8217;ve letterboxed it. Also the image has been clipped and compressed and watermarked. I couldn&#8217;t see using this for any meaningful print use. This specific copy belongs to Instagram, possibly. And this is as good as it&#8217;s gonna get off of Instagram.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/vanjee-2031.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Little Car Big Bus'" ></p>

<p>This image is the &#8220;web original&#8221;. It&#8217;s 960 x 640 at 72 PPI. 3 inches by 2 inches or thereabouts at print resolution. It is compressed as little as possible. However it is watermarked, and it is hosted here, so out and out this &#8220;high-quality&#8221; version belongs to me. If someone wants to use it or a higher-resolution copy of it, then they need to talk to me (dan at dan dash vidal dot com - if you are of a mind) in order to use it.</p>

<blockquote><p>Instagram users assume people are interested in their images in order to use them for financial gain.</p></blockquote>


<p>Fact is, no. To think so is thinking that your content is somehow going to stand out from the billions of images Instagram now plays host to. Even if you are like me, and import your images from a high-quality source, no one with any money to spend on photography or photo licensing is going to care. They know that whatever terms Instagram sets for licensing images will not be in their favor, and also that the quality from Instagram is barely suitable for web use, much less print or any other high-resolution media. 612 x 612 isn&#8217;t much. Look at it on your monitor. Even if you are on a laptop, the square probably takes up about 1/4th of your screen. Not very meaningful from a compositional perspective. Plus, most IG images are straight from a phone camera and are noisy, overly-contrasted, mushy, and compressed like crazy. Certainly not suitable for reuse or reproduction. Instagram themselves may get some traction out of it, but they are going to find few buyers in the open market for cell phone photos of food.</p>

<p>Sam Biddle over at Gizmodo put it best today:</p>

<blockquote><p>This means that Instagram can sell the pictures you take of pineapple upside down cake, latte swirls, and your dumb dog, if some company wants to pay for these photos. They can then do whatever the hell they want with them, including putting the photos in advertisements for shoes or cars or whatever.</p><footer><strong>Sam Biddle</strong> <cite><a href='http://gizmodo.com/5969221/stop-whining-about-your-personal-data-on-instagram-you-little-whiny-baby'>Stop Whining About Your Personal Data on Instagram You Whiny Little Baby</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>And yes, they can and they will try. So be it. And if Instagram can find traction in selling 612 x 612 images, well, good for them. And if it&#8217;s images I uploaded, well, then I guess there&#8217;s a market for my images that I post on Instagram. If that&#8217;s the case I&#8217;ll be more cautious as to what I post to Instagram, and see about selling 612 x 612 images myself.</p>

<p>A lot of the complainers are making the erroneous assumption that people care what they post. Fact is, most people don&#8217;t, otherwise they would follow you if they did. Outside of celebrities, most of the world doesn&#8217;t care about your <em>pineapple upside down cake, latte swirls, and your dumb dog</em> (thanks Sam, that&#8217;s golden!) or any other aspect of your life. I sure as hell don&#8217;t. And if I want photos of  pineapple upside down cake, latte swirls, and your dumb dog, I&#8217;ll take the photos myself of pineapple upside down cake, latte swirls, and your dumb dog.</p>

<p>Keep on Instagramming, I know I will. It&#8217;s fun, and it&#8217;s free, and they can only learn about you what you choose to share. Now yes, the theory behind it isn&#8217;t very good, but in practice there is little actual harm being done. Your Instagram photos are ephemeral snippets of time, not the next iteration of the works of Cartier-Bresson. And if Henri was alive today, he&#8217;d have an iPhone (of course) and he&#8217;d be Instagramming away with the rest of us. If you don&#8217;t take Instagram seriously, they won&#8217;t take you seriously.</p>

<p>But, if you insist, here&#8217;s a few ways to make your images &#8220;unusable&#8221;.</p>

<ul>
<li>Collage Apps</li>
Collage apps allow you to place multiple images into one Instagram image. My favorite is <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/instacollage-pro-pic-frame/id530957474?mt=8">Instacollage Pro</a>. You can post multiple images per Instagram using this, or have one image &#8220;broken up&#8221; with obnoxious lines going through it. The image up at the top of this article was chopped up in Instacollage Pro.
<li>Use an app like Filterstorm to render the image smaller than the Instagram Square.</li>
The app <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/filterstorm/id363449020?mt=8">Filterstorm is bascially a mini-Photoshop for iOS. You can do basic adjustments and gradings to JPEG images, and there&#8217;s a handy function called &#8220;Make Square&#8221; which places a white border around a non-square image, to make it into a square, conveniently in the proportions Instagram needs. This allows a user to display their entire image as intended, and also it makes the image even smaller than 612 x 612, rendering it nigh-unusable for anything but Instagram.
<li>Watermark in Photoshop or Lightroom Right Through The Center</li>
My friend Seth with his company <a href="http://worldredeye.com/">World Red Eye</a> does this with all of his images anyways. It destroys their worth to anyone looking to steal them, regardless of the medium. This is probably the best way of going about it.
</ul>


<p>So yeah, I think I&#8217;ll keep on Instagramming. I know how to mess up my images just enough to render them useless to anyone looking to use them from Instagram, and also anything I shoot directly with my phone has no significant monetary value.</p>

<p>Follow me at <a href="http://instagram.com/pod_gram">instagram.com/pod_gram</a> - haha!</p>

<p>And yes, I&#8217;m aware of the irony of me, the anti-Facebook guy, using Instagram, a Facebook division. There&#8217;s alternatives out there I&#8217;m exploring, don&#8217;t worry.</p>

<p>Oh, and happy holidays to my readership. The blog has been a fun adventure over the past few months!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Around Wynwood For Art Basel 2012...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/08/around-wynwood-for-art-basel-2012-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T21:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/08/around-wynwood-for-art-basel-2012-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood960.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>Proprietor of <a href="http://thevagabondmiami.com/" target="_blank">The Vagabond</a> and friend of mine, Carmel Ophir, had this to say about Basel&#8230;</p>

<blockquote><p>Take a walk, alone&#8230; Go into the small random galleries, warehouses, and storefronts. Pick any art fair and not worry about paying the admission fee. Walk around, and take in some of the most incredible creative works in the world. Don&#8217;t fret about where your friends are and what they may be doing, or what&#8217;s the cool/hip place to be.<br/>We are so lucky to have such a collection and gathering of the art world at our doorstep. Enjoy it&#8230;Immerse yourself in it.</p><footer><strong>Carmel Ophir</strong> <cite><a href='https://www.facebook.com/carmelophir/posts/10152329760025065'>On Art Basel Miami</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>So, with that in mind, I set out late this afternoon&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I had some shopping to do, so on the way home, I figured I&#8217;d pop into Wynwood, park somewhere, and just cruise.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9575.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>Finding a spot just west of Wynwood, I set out on foot from my parking spot and headed east to NW 2nd Avenue, which is the heart of the Wynwood scene. Upon my arrival at 5:30, it was already a traffic horror show. If not during Art Walk, at least during Art Basel, the city needs to block off from NW 27th to NW 20th Street and restrict it to pedestrian traffic only. It&#8217;s a madhouse.</p>

<p>However, the scene was already in full swing. The artists were out decorating their buildings, and the numerous local bars and restaurants that have sprung up over the past few years were open for business, and crowded. Wynwood has &#8220;arrived&#8221;. It&#8217;s not the &#8216;next big thing&#8217;, it has arrived. South Beach is history and falling apart, the Design District is in it&#8217;s cruise phase, Wynwood has just touched down. If you plan on establishing a presence there, it&#8217;s going to be expensive. Just go west by I-95. It&#8217;s cheap and on the way up.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9581.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9596.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>As it was dusk, I was capturing a great juxtaposition of a very colorful sky, with the bold schemes of the galleries in the neigborhood. Magic hour, as they say. I kept it wide and just concentrated on the photo and not wondering if I should switch to my 50 1.2, due to the decreasing light levels.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9609.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9614.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Car2Go Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>Along with the artists, galleries, and their work, the usual suspects turned up for branding opportunities. Heineken was very much in attendance, and I was glad to see Car2Go making a statement as well. I&#8217;m normally ambivalent to product launches and &#8220;activations&#8221;, but if it&#8217;s someone I can get behind like C2G, then go for it. Yes, I&#8217;m very petty and subjective. But at least I admit it.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9641.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9663.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9743.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>Of course, the usual party cruisers were out. I guess they are here to stay, and Art Basel Miami wouldn&#8217;t be where it is today if it weren&#8217;t for the hordes of people jumping from one booze-soaked hangout to another. But again, I wish they&#8217;d just be honest.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9752.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9687.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>And, of course, there were plenty of street performers as well. I was glad to see Miami PD left them alone, and not pulling the Beach antics of hassling everyone for a permit and a fee. South Beach wonders why it&#8217;s fading into generic obscurity, and part of that is the culture is being taxed to death by the government and the profiteering property owners who seemingly triple the rent at random.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9711.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Asif's Guns Wynwood'" ></p>

<p>I did my part, and checked out a lot of random little galleries and one-off events. My favorite by far was <a href="http://www.primaryprojectspace.com/artbasel/asifsguns" target="blank">Asif&#8217;s Guns</a>. In a nutshell, Asif produced accurate cardboard models of popular firearms, including Walther, GLOCK, H&amp;K, and the ubiquitous AK-47. It was a riff on US gun culture, and a parody of a US gun store. While I might not see eye-to-eye with him on his gun politics (he calls for more controls, whereas I advocate better enforcement of existing statutes), it was really the highlight of my little run through Wynwood. A 400-square foot setup off to the side somewhere. Carmel&#8217;s advice paid off. I even bought a T-shirt. I&#8217;m sure it will be a hit tomorrow morning&#8230;</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/08//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S_1kyNAgL9/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/492092a241a011e2984522000a1f8ad9_7.jpg' alt='New shirt #asifsguns #armedbasel #artbasel #igersmiami #instagood' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.800851,-80.19829'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.800851,-80.19829&markers=25.800851,-80.19829&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Asif's Guns' /></a><br/>Taken at Asif&#8217;s Guns</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='342227720975024893_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obligatory Art Basel Miami Post...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/07/obligatory-art-basel-miami-post-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T23:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/07/obligatory-art-basel-miami-post-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood.jpg" width="960" height="1280" title="'Wynwood this past Thursday'" ></p>

<p>It&#8217;s the first week of December, and the Miami edition of Art Basel is in full swing. The official sister festival to the world-famous Art Basel that takes place in (duh!)Basel, Switzerland, Art Basel Miami (that&#8217;s a lot of Basels in a row, sorry grammarians!) is currently in it&#8217;s tenth year of operation. It&#8217;s done wonders for the standing of Miami&#8217;s art world, but like anything Miami-related, there&#8217;s a huge layer of bullshit built in&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As a note of clarification, what most people consider &#8220;Art Basel&#8221; actually consists of the official <a href="http://artbasel.com/">Art Basel</a> fair at the Miami Beach Convention Center, along with several unrelated satellite fairs such as Design Miami, and the numerous galleries in the Design District and Wynwood neighborhoods in the City of Miami hosting their own affairs. Art Basel Miami basically spawned a whole ecosystem of unaffiliated satellite events, much like Winter Music Conference did. However, unlike WMC, Art Basel is not fighting a rearguard action (sorry Bill, it&#8217;s true&#8230;) with regards to these events. Art Basel basically ignores them and does what they want.</p>

<p>However, most people don&#8217;t distinguish the individual events per se and just say &#8220;Art Basel&#8221;.</p>

<p>This year, 2012, has proven to be the biggest Basel yet. It&#8217;s Friday night and I&#8217;ve already noticed a huge amount of traffic on all the Beach-bound bridges and causeways, and the Wynwood neighborhood is a complete traffic disaster. One would guess that after ten years of practice, the various municipalities would have managing this down to a science. At least close the streets to vehicle traffic in Wynwood.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/05//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S3xzCpggF2/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage6.s3.amazonaws.com/acbccdda3f2a11e2b12d22000a9e295b_7.jpg' alt='Arty. #artbasel #305 #igersmiami #instagood #miami #wynwood' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.810598384,-80.19685341'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.810598384,-80.19685341&markers=25.810598384,-80.19685341&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='LMNT Gallery' /></a><br/>Taken at LMNT Gallery</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='339959308705988982_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>And the source of that traffic is the crowds, of course. Most of which have no real interest or idea about the art on display, or the art world in general. For the record, I&#8217;m not a huge participant in the Miami art scene, even though I&#8217;ve sold a few pieces. I should get out more, to be blunt. However, it isn&#8217;t too difficult to see that you have the masses of people who are just out for the see-and-be-seen scene, and of course the copious amounts of free booze. Then they can tweet to their friends that they are &#8220;Baseling&#8221;, of course.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/baseling.png" width="322" height="446" title="'Twitter-Baseling'" ></p>

<p>I don&#8217;t decry anyone making a lifestyle of it, I know several people whose social scene in general consists of cruising sponsored events, but for the art scene in particular, it can be problematic. Artists local and global have to deal with the &#8220;freeloaders&#8221; in order to get to the 2 percent of the people who may want to purchase their art. The official Art Basel fair actually recognizes this issue and the first two days of the fair are closed to the public and only accessible to well-heeled collectors who can afford a ticket or have the industry cred (i.e. they own a gallery, etc&#8230;) to actually be there to conduct business&#8230;</p>

<p>But the unfortunate side effect, the bullshit, is that the art generally plays second-fiddle to the social scene. The art is the excuse to go out and get banged up. Hey, if I want to get banged up, I can do that with little to no justification. I do feel though for the local Miami artists, who have to deal with this extraordinary amount of bullshit just to get their work out there. Miami struggles to be recognized as an &#8220;arts&#8221; city, and when Basel comes, it&#8217;s all laid bare that 90 percent of the crowd is just treating it as a hipster version of Spring Break in December. With celebrities, who actually don&#8217;t purchase any of the art, anywhere.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/05//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S4RWiGggER/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/318a60f63f5111e2a2ab22000a1fb84b_7.jpg' alt='Watching @keprock compose his latest #artbasel  #miami #igersmiami #305' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.799291,-80.207293'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.799291,-80.207293&markers=25.799291,-80.207293&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='GTC (ClubFlyers.com)' /></a><br/>Taken at GTC (ClubFlyers.com)</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='340098087102054673_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I feel for friends of mine, like KEPROCK, whose work is Instagrammed above, who struggle to produce great pieces, and they have to struggle further just to get heard.</p>

<p>Have I voluntarily recused myself from Basel? As a potential exhibitor? Yes. I&#8217;ve had &#8220;real life&#8221; happening, and haven&#8217;t had the time to curate and produce my own exhibit. However, discussions have happened. I&#8217;m hoping to do something next year.</p>

<p>As someone going out to check out the scene? No. I&#8217;ve been out, just bouncing around basically. I&#8217;ve avoided the big-ticket fairs, the celebrity events, and the Beachside quagmire. I have scant desire to be crammed into any venue which is flush with people doing Instagram self-portraits (har har) and checking in so all their friends get to see how &#8216;cultured&#8217; they are. So far I&#8217;ve done a few Wynwood runs, ended up at <a href="http://www.thecornermiami.com/">The Corner</a> three times in one night, and somehow ended up at the Vagabond. Oddly enough in these travels, I&#8217;ve seen more genuine art-related goings on than in any &#8220;art&#8221; themed event.</p>

<p>If you are here for Basel, welcome. Just don&#8217;t bullshit a bullshitter, and be honest. You&#8217;re only here for the (free) beer.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wood.jpg" width="960" height="208" title="'Wood iPhone Pano'" ></p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S7NTA8AgJ6/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage10.s3.amazonaws.com/9e5bfee8403611e2a23c22000a1f9d66_7.jpg' alt='Max that sensor. Because fuck you that's why. #artbasel I don't do art and I do more art than art. #waltherp99 #armedbasel' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.801305255,-80.198858322'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.801305255,-80.198858322&markers=25.801305255,-80.198858322&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Wood Tavern' /></a><br/>Taken at Wood Tavern</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='340924678078071418_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>




<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S7Vb2EggN3/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/8d7aa23c404011e2b55e22000a9f09fb_7.jpg' alt='I shoulda learned to play them drums #artbasel #miami #igersmiami #instawtf' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.788130302,-80.193521976'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.788130302,-80.193521976&markers=25.788130302,-80.193521976&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='The Vagabond' /></a><br/>Taken at The Vagabond</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='340960469256897399_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>




<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S7bPqqggAU/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage8.s3.amazonaws.com/a5017424404711e2925f22000a1fb71a_7.jpg' alt='Hahah at The Corner @stephencutrone' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784647698,-80.193843842'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784647698,-80.193843842&markers=25.784647698,-80.193843842&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='The Corner' /></a><br/>Taken at The Corner</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='340986020654874644_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Oh and yes, all the prior images were shot with my iPhone. It&#8217;s a fun challenge maxing out the sensor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And I Think I Was Right...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/27/and-i-think-i-was-right-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-27T01:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/27/and-i-think-i-was-right-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/juno-8223.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'By The Pale Moonlight - Available Soon For Print'" ></p>

<p>I think I was right, the creative endeavor cannot be forced.</p>

<p>This past evening, I took the 210 out for a small check ride&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Every few months or so, it&#8217;s a good idea to run fuel system cleaner through your car. Most car nuts agree the only kind worth a damn is <a href="http://techron.com/">Techron.</a> Yes, I know there&#8217;s <a href="http://www.basf.com/group/corporate/en/brand/KEROPUR">Keropur</a> from BASF, but good luck getting that in anything besides a 55-gallon drum. You can go to any European car dealer, and they should have it, but they&#8217;ll usually try to rope you in for &#8220;service&#8221; and flat out not sell you a bottle. And the indie mechanics don&#8217;t have it since demand is low. So, Techron it is. Daimler actually approves of it, so it&#8217;s OK.</p>

<p>Anyways, to use a fuel system cleaner, you run your tank low, and then dump a bottle into your tank, and then put 10-15 gallons of gas over that. So, on the way back from the beach today, I swung by the <a href="http://advanceautoparts.com/">Advance Auto Parts</a> shop on Alton, and picked up two bottles. Two because they&#8217;re running a special - buy one at the normal price, get another for a dollar.</p>

<p>So, I went home, sorted out a few last-minute edits from the weekend, and drove out the last little bit of old gas. I dumped a bottle in, gassed up at the Chevron, and took off for the Turnpike. Why? Well, it might be a bit of a superstition, but M-B enthusiasts over at <a href="http://benzworld.org">Benzworld</a> generally suggest you give your car an &#8220;Italian Tuneup&#8221; after putting in Techron. Basically an Italian Tuneup is where you find a highway, and just go fast for a bit. Some suggest redlining even, but I&#8217;m not going to take that chance. I figured a nice cruise at autobahn speeds would suffice.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/26//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/ShC4zLggH0/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/a95b1cf6383a11e28a2c22000a9f15d9_7.jpg' alt='Field harmonics check. #nofilter #turnpike #florida #131kmh #w210' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=26.164295902,-80.225495204'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=26.164295902,-80.225495204&markers=26.164295902,-80.225495204&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Ali's Roti Shop' /></a><br/>Taken at Ali&#8217;s Roti Shop</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='333560546739749364_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>So, I got out to the pike and turned it up to around 140 km/h and set the 210 for cruise. That&#8217;s about 85-90 MPH. Yes, I&#8217;m using metric. Just because. It&#8217;s my blog.</p>

<p>The cruise was great. I had my choice of music on, there was zero traffic, and the flow was smooth. No anomalies.</p>

<p>Eventually, I ended up somewhere near Indiantown Road in Palm Beach County.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/26//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/ShJHFzggN4/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage4.s3.amazonaws.com/42236888384211e2a95722000a9f09e9_7.jpg' alt='System check #w210 in some deserted parking lot. #florida #jupiter #moonlight #instagood #picoftheday #palmbeach' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=26.940890065,-80.194418032'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=26.940890065,-80.194418032&markers=26.940890065,-80.194418032&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Calvary Chapel Jupiter' /></a><br/>Taken at Calvary Chapel Jupiter</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='333587917089932152_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>After pulling over in a random Publix parking lot and sorting through some emails, I noticed there was a near-full Moon out. I had all my gear on me, so I figured, why not look for some shooting opportunities?</p>

<p>With that in mind, I meandered my way over to Juno Beach proper and onto A1A. The Moon was bright and the cloud cover was breaking up. I didn&#8217;t intend on shooting anything, but the opportunity was presenting itself. The world fell in line, I may as well capture the results. So, I went out to the beach itself, and captured the wave action by the light of the Moon itself.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/juno-8225.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'By The Pale Moonlight Vertical - Available Soon For Print'" ></p>

<p>Autofocus and even accurate manual focus via the viewfinder was nigh-impossible. What I did was boosted the ISO to 12800, flipped on Live View, and focused on some waves manually in the distance. And then dropped down to a more reasonable ISO 640 for the actual exposure. The boost in Live View essentially allowed me to have &#8220;pseudo-night-vision&#8221; and I could gauge the focus on a wave. It worked. The image itself almost appears to be a painting.</p>

<p>Plus, it made me a fan of that specific stretch of Juno Beach. I should get a place up there. It&#8217;s quiet, and has that sleepy beach-town feeling that I tend to get a kick out of. I like my beach towns to be well, beach towns. South Beach is so not that. It&#8217;s so bourgeoise (so says the Benz addict, haha!) and overrun with tourists and chain stores. What unique charm it had left ages ago. I could have a bungalow in Juno Beach (or any other quiet beach town in South Florida - they still exist!) and my apt here in Miami. Hmm&#8230;</p>

<p>Nonetheless, I&#8217;m actually liking what I did tonight. And I didn&#8217;t even intend on shooting anything. I didn&#8217;t force the creative process. The world got in line and I captured it&#8230;I should stick to my own supposed tagline.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve got some fine-tuning to do, but the two images featured in this post will be available for sale soon. In the meantime, why not <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">click here</a> and browse through what is currently for sale? It&#8217;s the holidays, someone in your family will need a gift. And you can do a good deed and support my efforts&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can you force the creative endeavor?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/26/can-you-force-the-creative-endeavor/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T16:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/26/can-you-force-the-creative-endeavor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jor-7970.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Platinum Beams and Jordyn at Space Miami'" ></p>

<p>Well, it appears I survived the holiday weekend. I&#8217;m not one for Black Friday shopping or massive crowds, so I spent Friday itself laying low. I wanted to get out there and &#8220;produce&#8221; rather than consume, but, nothing major came out of my drivetime adventures either on Friday or Sunday. Which begs the question, can the creative process be forced?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&#8217;m not necessarily talking about paid assignments or tasks, either. When you have a specific framework or set of requirements in mind, it&#8217;s easy. Take a photo of Bayfront Park for a brochure. We need stock photos of police cruisers lined up. We need a photo of a dog destroying a rug. However, when I set out with a task in mind, such as capturing a nighttime landscape image, occasionally it does lead to a lot of driving around with nothing to show for it. But then, when I least expect it, I&#8217;ll &#8220;land&#8221; a great image that I&#8217;m proud to show around.</p>

<p>It kind of happened this weekend. I drove around Friday, and Sunday, and didn&#8217;t generate much in the way of what I considered quality photographic content. Perhaps it was holiday malaise, the phases of the moon, I couldn&#8217;t really put my finger on it.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/25//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/SeSwHmAgLd/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage9.s3.amazonaws.com/a6f73fc6376311e2b2f422000a9f1255_7.jpg' alt='Doing something civil #broward #drivetime #954' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=26.021867551,-80.11507505'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=26.021867551,-80.11507505&markers=26.021867551,-80.11507505&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Hollywood Beach Garfield Park' /></a><br/>Taken at Hollywood Beach Garfield Park</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='332785893997937373_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Though I did enjoy the exercise at least.</p>

<p>However, in my Saturday club travels, I landed two images which I personally consider presentable material. The first was of Jordyn at Space, as seen above, and the second was of my friend Jane, over at the Vagabond, where I stopped in for <a href="http://djoscarg.net/">Oscar G&#8217;s</a> and Ralph Falcon&#8217;s birthday party. Murk boys in effect.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jane-7808.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Hi Jane'" ></p>

<p>Both images, are obviously &#8220;club&#8221; images. One of my fortés happens to be nightlife photography, obviously, but as of late, I&#8217;ve been trying to expand my horizons and get away from the familiar pattern of colorfully-lit dancing girls, DJs, fog effects, and crowds. It&#8217;s fun and I really enjoy it, but I have been trying to expand my repertoire a little bit, i.e. with my landscapes and scenic nighttime photography.</p>

<p>Which begs the question, can the creative process be forced? My two &#8220;score&#8221; images were generated off-the-cuff, with little technical thought to them. Lights are at <em>x</em>, so shutter speed at <em>y</em>, aperture at <em>z</em>, and ISO at <em>alpha</em>, and press the shutter button. The one of Jane actually had a little more thought to it since I saw the light on the wall and had to position her accordingly, but it wasn&#8217;t a &#8220;planned&#8221; image in the sense that I spent time driving around and looking for it. Ms Jane wanted an image, and I gladly provided.</p>

<p>So maybe sometimes &#8220;don&#8217;t think, just shoot&#8221; can lead to results as well. I&#8217;m definitely digging the end results. Even in the familiar territory of nightlife, I can still pull off a unique composition. And the process wasn&#8217;t forced. I &#8220;had a vision and waited for the world to fall in line&#8230;&#8221;. Maybe trying to force the world to fall in line doesn&#8217;t work?</p>

<p>And of course having willing subjects helps enormously. Thanks to Jane, and Jordyn as well for participating in my lens antics this weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy US Thanksgiving To My Small Readership!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/22/happy-us-thanksgiving-to-my-small-readership/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/22/happy-us-thanksgiving-to-my-small-readership</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/mpd-5409.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'MPD'" ></p>

<p>Happy Thanksgiving to my small and dedicated loyal readership. Keep it down out there, otherwise the guys above might have to move their cruisers off the grass and they usually don&#8217;t like doing that&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And with that, the holiday season begins.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bayfront-6921.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Challenger Monument'" ></p>

<p>The mad rush to the malls, &#8216;Cyber Monday&#8217; as it were, and all the other associated commercial activity. Since I&#8217;ll most likely be lazy and not blog about it on the day of, this weekend also features <a href="http://www.miamiherald.com/2012/11/21/3107988/small-business-saturday-the-anti.html">Small Business Saturday.</a></p>

<p>I can dig it. I like sorting out people I know. Plus, I&#8217;m all about the small and agile ethos. It&#8217;s easier and more fun if you think about it.</p>

<p>And, in the spirt of Small Business Saturday and also the holidays, why not support a local small business (me), and purchase for yourself, or as a gift, one of my fine scenic pieces? I just recently put the above photo, &#8216;Challenger Monument&#8217; up for sale. You can purchase a copy in any number of sizes, finishes, and mounting options (including canvas gallery wraps) by <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com">by clicking here</a>. I&#8217;ll even knock 20 percent off the price. Just put the code &#8216;ZESNLP&#8217; into the box at checkout, and the discount will be applied. Other prints available for purchase include popular images like&#8230;</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<center><i>Islamorada Crossing</i></center>


<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648.jpg" width="960" height="1440" title="'Fire away'" ></p>

<center><i>Indian Key Channel</i></center>


<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/outwhere_rev-8882.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'US 27 Northbound Broward County'" ></p>

<center><i>Out Where The Buses Don&#8217;t Run</i></center>


<p>&#8230;and quite a few more.</p>

<p><a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com">Click on over to my print store to purchase</a>. Don&#8217;t forget code &#8216;ZESNLP&#8217; at checkout for the 20 percent discount. Shipping times are reasonable but may back up a bit closer to the end of December, and specialty orders like gallery wraps take an extra day or so to prepare&#8230;</p>

<p>Yes, this is me being a little commercial.</p>

<p>Go pig out and spend time with your family and friends. They miss you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Back, I Wonder How I Did It...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/20/looking-back/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/20/looking-back</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tmb-7087.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'TMB'" ></p>

<p>This past weekend, The Martinez Brothers took to the decks at Space. They&#8217;ve got the youthful energy and enthusiasm in spades. Playing for well over ten hours, they kept the dancefloor moving until the afternoon&#8230;</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not ancient, by any measure, but by the time I left at 9, I was completely drained&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And the kids were still rocking it like they just woke up&#8230;</p>

<p>Objectively, I&#8217;m actually healthier than I&#8217;ve been in a long time. I try to eat right, and take care of myself. I still have a drink or five when I&#8217;m at the club (no one trusts you if you are without a drink in a nightclub&#8230;just nod and agree with me on this one) and I will be smart and pace myself. However, sometimes I&#8217;m just completely drained, even going into Monday. Is it all mental? Or has a decade and change in-scene finally started to catch up with me?</p>

<p>When I was The Brothers&#8217; age, I could do a 9-10 hour &#8220;shift&#8221; standing on my head, and still bounce back for whatever I had to do on Monday. I could even go out multiple nights a week till 5 AM. Now, I don&#8217;t go to a club unless there&#8217;s decent money involved. I&#8217;d rather relax with friends or just stay home and read/write/edit. Or go out and shoot scenics.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bayfront-6921.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Challenger Monument'" ></p>

<p>Maybe I am &#8220;getting old&#8221;, who knows? I still enjoy the nightlife, but yeah, it does take a lot out of you, regardless of your health.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/20//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/SPS2IbAgGT/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage11.s3.amazonaws.com/e452ccb632cf11e2a4461231381b6557_7.jpg' alt='Adventures with @themartinezbros @clubspacemiami @jhartlein @n0t0r10us @frannypanny @zhantra http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/the-martinez-brothers-return-to-space-2' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784642914,-80.19313766'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784642914,-80.19313766&markers=25.784642914,-80.19313766&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='328564182553330067_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>For my younger readers - this will happen to you. I can guarantee it. Trick is, pace yourself, but even then&#8230;</p>

<p>Maybe a vacation is in order.</p>

<p>Thoughts?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Work with the light tech...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/13/work-with-the-light-tech-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T01:04:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/13/work-with-the-light-tech-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/mark-6094.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Mark Knight at Space November 2012 with light tech Dennis Perez'" ></p>

<p>One of my favorite DJ/Producers, <a href="http://www.djmarkknight.com/">Mark Knight</a>, stopped in at Space this past weekend for a little eight-hour set on the decks. He&#8217;s got the idea of being a DJ down pat. He mixes in his own material and edits, with a good dose of anything that will make the crowd move. Throughout the night I heard everything from classic Underworld to even an INXS-inspired white label track. And he&#8217;s always down for a wacky photo or two, like the one above. And, of course, I get asked &#8216;how did I do that&#8217;?</p>

<p>In this case, it wasn&#8217;t just a random happenstance of the lighting and the photo coming together&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->




<blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it&#8230;</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Generally that is how I work. I wait for things to happen, as I&#8217;ve explained before, then I document it. However, in club life, an interesting &#8216;counter&#8217; to my little tagline happens, in that the friendly local lighting techs will set up a specific cue, so I can capture the moment. So, I have to wonder, am I waiting for the world to fall in line if someone kind of knows what I would like to see?</p>

<p>I do appreciate the help, obviously, and it is actually not a hard feat for anyone to accomplish if they are out shooting nightlife. The trick here is, to get to know your light techs and the equipment they employ on a nightly basis.</p>

<p>When I first got started in this, I used to be a part-time light tech for my friend John&#8217;s sound company. John and I, at the time, were both students over at UM, and to make ends meet, and also for the learning experience (his major was audio engineering), John ran a small sound and lighting company on the side. And I was his unofficial-official light tech, due to my experience with lighting in general, and also no one else in our crew knew the concepts. We didn&#8217;t get paid much, but at the time, half the fun was just being able to get out there and do shows. We mostly did rock shows, but we also did a few dance-oriented events here and there. Nonetheless, I got to learn the basics of stage and nightclub lighting. As time went on, even after John moved back to Aspen to kick off his <a href="http://alchemyavcs.com/">massive production company</a>, I would stay current and always converse and on occasion, fill in as a tech for a lot of the local guys when they were sick, away or &#8220;otherwise indisposed&#8221;. At this time (early to mid 2000s), lighting was moving from a &#8220;dedicated console&#8221; world, to a PC-driven sort of affair, especially in the nightclub industry. A $300 PC and $700 USB-DMX widget could take the place of a $20000 console in a nightclub setting. The most popular product was <a href="http://martinpro.com/product/product.asp?product=lightjockey">LightJockey</a> by Martin. In a nutshell, after you installed and connected all your fixtures, you used this piece of software and supplied USB-DMX widget, and could program and control your lightshow from any commodity PC. It is all very graphical.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/LJ.jpg" width="600" height="474" title="'Lightjockey 2.0'" ></p>

<p>There&#8217;s several competing software packages out there nowadays, but Lightjockey is the most common one. The concepts are the same though.</p>

<p>And then, obviously, beyond the controller, is the entire world of the lighting fixtures themselves. Common manufacturers include <a href="http://martinpro.com/">Martin</a>, <a href="http://www.highend.com/">Highend</a>, <a href="http://www.elationlighting.com/">Elation</a>, <a href="http://claypaky.com/">Clay Paky</a>, and many more.</p>

<p>Entire blogs and sites are devoted to lighting. Obviously this one isn&#8217;t. But, you don&#8217;t have to be a light tech to speak the basics. The key, I&#8217;ve found, is to know what the fixtures are (spots, washes, scanners, strobes - all kind of self-explanatory), and the right terms for what the fixtures do (If you say &#8216;CTO&#8217; you&#8217;ll usually be taken a little bit more seriously) and what the colors and filters are, and also the basics of how a lighting scene is constructed. Also, if you don&#8217;t know the tech, get to know him or her (yes, her - one of the best in the biz <a href="https://www.facebook.com/miss.allegra"> is a girl</a>.) and develop a rapport. If it&#8217;s early in the night, the tech is usually just running through the motions, and will probably be up for a break in the routine. Use the opening DJ as a &#8220;practice target&#8221;, and get some cues set up for yourself.</p>

<p>Now, this all kind of reeks of cheating. And, maybe it is. However, the way I can ethically justify it is now, in a lot of places, the tech will actually bring up &#8220;my&#8221; cues, without me even asking. At Space, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve asked Dennis or Gabriel for a specific cue in months. It just all falls into place. They know what will make for a great image, and more importantly, when to deploy those cues, for maximum effect on both the crowd and my image capture. We work together on it.</p>

<p>Plus, a good tech will know the flow and rhythm to the music and crowd, and having specific cues becomes less and less necessary, since the lighting will just happen. When a song peaks, you know there will be a sizable amount of strobing, for example. Or when there is a lull in the track, it could go dark, or a nice blue wash from the Platinum Beams will kick in.</p>

<p>Of course, the assumption being made here is that you are shooting in a venue that is equipped with a decent lighting rig, and, beyond that, a dedicated lighting technician. Some smaller venues still run their lighting systems on autopilot, or according to a preset schedule (Lightjockey allows for scheduled cues based on the time of day, even), depending on the needs of the venue. That being said, most places of that nature actually have a lot of practical lighting, or a good dose of ambient light. There&#8217;s a lot of light out there if you know where to find it.</p>

<p>But, if the situation allows for it, definitely get to know and work with the light techs in a venue, the resultant images will be much more &#8220;meaningful&#8221; than your usual run-of-the-mill flash-and-dash captures.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm a social media sceptic and I have a blog...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/09/im-a-social-media-sceptic-and-i-have-a-blog-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-09T11:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/09/im-a-social-media-sceptic-and-i-have-a-blog-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/blog-5407.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'OCP'" ></p>

<p>This morning, when I woke up, a post on Facebook by <a href="http://helloimscott.com/">Scott Alexander</a> caught my eye.</p>

<blockquote><p>A good article for photographers and artists of any medium, really. While you&#8217;re on Edin&#8217;s site reading this, I highly recommend checking out the rest of his site. Great photographer with a superb eye.</p><footer><strong>Scott Alexander</strong> <cite>A Facebook Post</cite></footer></blockquote>




<!-- more -->


<p>The post linked to <a href="http://www.edinchavez.com/blog/why-should-i-start-a-blog/">an article by local photographer Edin Chavez</a>, on why a photographer should have a blog. The reasons are pretty obvious, ranging from showcasing your work to SEO, and, most importantly, <em>control</em>.</p>

<p>Now, maybe it sounds a little obsessive, but at the end of the day, having a slice of web property you control from top to bottom is important, especially if you are in the creative field. And, unfortunately, there&#8217;s quite a large amount of creative types who don&#8217;t have a web property that they explicitly have ownership of. I know more than a few working photographers who only use social media to showcase their works, for example. This can be dangerous.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m a &#8220;social media sceptic&#8221;. I&#8217;ve been on the internet in one way or another since 1992, around the time the World Wide Web was born. And yes, there was an <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was/">internet before then</a>. My dad was/is a network engineer, so we always had some form of basic online access. In general, we passed on the walled-garden online services of the day like AOL, Compu$erve, and so on. I actually preferred local dialup BBSes, which, in a way, were primitive social networks.</p>

<p>You could post up content, chat with other users, and transfer files around. It was basically a text-mode Facebook, if you think about it. However, after a few years, the era of the BBS faded, replaced by easy internet access and the rise of consumer usage of the WWW. Once people got situated and used to &#8220;dot com&#8221;, soon after came the rise of user-provided content, i.e. the first blogs. Blogging was around before the term was coined (a lot of personal websites had a running journal of the owner&#8217;s thoughts&#8230;), but with the advent of primitive <a href="http://www.movabletype.org/">CMS</a> systems, publishing content became a trivial point and shoot exercise. Then, of course, that was extended into social networking as we know it. Friendster kicked off the craze, then MySpace, then proceeding on to Twitter and Facebook, with of course Google constantly on the move to be &#8220;the&#8221; internet.</p>

<p>However, through all those trends and sea changes, the ability to host and publish your own content on your own web property has remained. I know a few &#8220;social media managers&#8221; (the title is largely meaningless), and their biggest challenge is keeping up with the trends in services and platforms. Today it is Facebook, tomorrow it could (hopefully) be <a href="http://join.app.net/">app.net</a>, or a move to the <a href="https://joindiaspora.com/">Diaspora</a> model of community-run distributed social networking. Nonetheless, it&#8217;s a lot to digest and keep up with. It&#8217;s the nature of the beast, as it were.</p>

<p>And therein lies the problem. I see a lot of people who rely and base their businesses on a specific form of social media. A few years ago, I knew people who made businesses based on doing MySpace profile templates, and they acted as if it was their gateway to untold riches. Now, you have companies building applications around Facebook, acting in much the same way. With the cyclical trendy nature of social media, most of these companies are destined to fail, or disappear, due to their reliance on someone else&#8217;s platform for their business. It&#8217;s akin to relying on General Motors cars exclusively for your delivery business, rather than any operational vehicle.</p>

<p>Now, one could drive themselves crazy keeping up with these social media trends. Every so often, you have to convert and repost your content. One bulwark against that, (to bring it all home!), is having your own web property. Now, <a href="http://www.edinchavez.com/blog/why-should-i-start-a-blog/">Edin espouses Wordpress and/or Blogger</a> as a publishing platform, and I of course champion <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, but that battle is more of a technical one than a political one.</p>

<p>The key is, hosting your content on your own systems, and using social media to drive people to those systems. I know with Octopress it will be a trivial matter to write a plug-in to support broadcasting to any future social network, due to it&#8217;s open-source nature. And even though Wordpress is rather closed in comparison, some enterprising developer will link WP with whichever future social network becomes ascendent. But, at the end of the day, with having your own domain, own hosting, and own content, one can make themselves immune from the often-flaky, trendy, and chaotic world of social media.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your obligatory post-election post...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/07/your-obligatory-post-election-post-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-07T01:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/07/your-obligatory-post-election-post-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/IMG_6714.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The rest of the country'" ></p>

<p>As of right now, President Barack Obama has secured his spot for a second term as President of these United States. To most observers, it wasn&#8217;t entirely unexpected, but his challenger, Mitt Romney, did put up a good fight, appealing to the &#8220;rest of America&#8221;, as it were, rather than focusing on the urban centers in the states with high electoral votes, as Obama did. In essence, it created the same split the US had four years ago. The map looks much the same, with the coasts being &#8220;blue&#8221; and the interior of the country being &#8220;red&#8221;&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In my travels I&#8217;ve visited each and every state in the Lower 48. At the base level, life will go on for each and every citizen of the US, much as it has had for them over the course of their lives. Whether there&#8217;s a Democrat or a Republican in the White House, their lives will go on. They will grow up, get jobs, maybe get married, maybe kick out a few kids, get old, and pass on, regardless of their location or political affiliation. Sure, economic conditions and the overall mood of the country do change (we are, as a lot, more miserable now than twenty years ago), but the overall lifestyle and conditions have remained pretty steady. Most of us have a roof over our heads and food on the table, which means we&#8217;re ahead of most of the world by a fair margin.</p>

<p>If we want to effect true change in our lives and political system, we can&#8217;t rely on just electing a different face of the same system every four years. Politicians may enter the world of politics with the best of ideals, but once in, they are either corrupted by power, or beaten down by the depth of the problems with our system, and they do the government equivalent of collecting a paycheck and just go through the motions.</p>

<p>To effect these changes, some have looked to the &#8220;third parties&#8221; in the US political system. Ranging from serious politicians such as ex-Republican governor of New Mexico <a href="http://garyjohnson2012.com/">Gary Johnson</a> of the <a href="http://lp.org/">Libertarian Party</a>, to publicity hounds like Roseanne Barr, the world of third-party politics is a diverse and wild one. Unfortunately, as it stands, no one has yet to make a serious dent in the two-party system. Johnson may or may not have come close, but as of this writing, it&#8217;s hard to find out whether he crossed the &#8220;magic&#8221; threshold of getting 5 percent of the popular vote. This threshold, if crossed, would permit the Libertarian Party to qualify for matching campaign funds from the government in the next election cycle, a major bonus.</p>

<p>Now, I tend to focus on the Libertarians a lot, mainly because that is my registered party affiliation. It isn&#8217;t a big secret that I have a distaste for big central government. I see big central government much like I see a big corporation. The government (corporation) only holds itself up to it&#8217;s biggest shareholders (the corporations in this case!) and disregards the interests of the individual citizen. What the Libertarian platform seeks to accomplish is to scale back government to the bare minimums needed to maintain a cohesive nation, and decentralize a lot of functions that are currently central, allowing for a more responsive form of government. Note, for the record, Libertarians aren&#8217;t anarchists or corporatists. The philosophy at it&#8217;s root level actually allows for debate and discussion on the form of government itself, actually. Some who identify as Libertarians are borderline anarchists, sure, but most are just decent citizens looking to live their lives with a minimum of active government interference, but also expecting that the government should be there to discharge it&#8217;s prescribed duties, whatever those may be at a given moment.</p>

<p>For example, the Libertarian take on war is that it is generally a bad thing. A Libertarian government shouldn&#8217;t conduct offensive campaigns, only defensive. Thus, the government is responsible for the safety of it&#8217;s taxpayers from external threats. This also obviously extends to basic police functions as well. I&#8217;m actually of the same bent. If I&#8217;m paying taxes, even if they are minimal, I would want the body I&#8217;m paying taxes into, to be able to take care of me and keep me safe. Sure, I&#8217;m pro-Second Amendment. When seconds count, the cops are minutes away, after all, but if you step it up a level, a Walther PPS isn&#8217;t really going to matter much against a full-on army. I would expect a government to provide a small standing force to do that for me.</p>

<p>Much along the same lines, and where I kind of split with the general party line (again, the party generally welcomes dissent and debate), is that the government should provide a basic form of emergency health care, covered by taxes. With the abolition of many government agencies, basic healthcare could be provided, even at a lower tax rate. After all, if I&#8217;m healthy, I&#8217;m able to work and pay taxes into the system. If I&#8217;m sick or infirm, I&#8217;m not able to work.</p>

<p>Beyond making sure the citizens are safe and healthy, the government should be hands-off. However, under the current system, that just isn&#8217;t possible. There is an entire industry built around a two-party strong central government system. Lobbyists, contractors, bureaucrats, and so many others depend on this very system for their livelihood. The system in place isn&#8217;t interested in the welfare of it&#8217;s citizens, it is only interested in safeguarding it&#8217;s existence in perpetuity. Much like the fictional &#8220;Matrix&#8221;, some people are so plugged in and dependent, they&#8217;ll stop at nothing to ensure the survival of their system.</p>

<p>Thus, beyond the change in government, we need a sea change in society for true progress to be made. Less and less, we should look to big government to solve all our ills, or big business for that matter. People need to get off of their social media and reality show addictions and get involved in the political process, before their right to do so is gradually usurped. The right to keep and bear arms could be revoked tomorrow and only a few NRA lobbyists would raise a fuss, but if someone set off an EMP weapon in each Facebook data center, there would be a mass insurrection. Bread and circuses keep the masses in check. People bitch about their privacy rights all the time, but they&#8217;ll share every bowel movement on Facebook, like it matters. That&#8217;s a personal pet peeve of mine. Fact is, even if I like you, I don&#8217;t care. Spare me the mundane. Let me know when you do something interesting. Checking in at your cubicle is not interesting. Oops, nearly went off track there.</p>

<p>Also, we need to reawaken the spirit of &#8220;Do It Yourself&#8221; in this country. Now, I&#8217;m not suggesting we all become aircraft mechanics and architects and build our own personal planes and buildings, but at the same time, I&#8217;m shocked at the lack of general knowledge of the way things work in some of the people around me. Now, grant it, I&#8217;m certainly deficient in some of these areas (until recently, cars were a &#8216;stomp-on-gas-pedal-and-go-that-way&#8217; affair to me), but I&#8217;m actually amazed at the overall level of ignorance I encounter. I think a spirit of &#8220;DIY&#8221; would encourage more government participation by the citizens.</p>

<p>Now, this could be a double-edged sword. People may not always think about what is best for the community, but what is best for them. For example, outlawing abortion might suit the family down the street just fine, but might not ring true for the struggling single mom-to-be down the street. Where people definitely need to mind their own business is in matters of the body, so to speak. My body, my rules. As long as my mistakes only harm me, I should be allowed to make them without penalty or interference. Abortion, drug use, even assisted suicide, aka &#8220;death with dignity&#8221; should be decisions left to the individual, not others. At the end of the day, the Libertarian ideal is about individual freedom. Right now, there is a severe lack of it in this country. Sure, there&#8217;s a lot we can do, but at the same time, there is a lot we cannot do, that we should be able to do, especially when it comes to ourselves.</p>

<p>I didn&#8217;t mean for this to turn into a pro-Libertarian rant, OK, maybe I did, but nonetheless, the issues are still staring us in the face, even though our everyday life continues unabated, and even though at a basic level, for most of us, it isn&#8217;t that bad.</p>

<p>But, it could be better. My ideas and concepts could actually make accomplishing that quite easy. And, of course, if you just choose to kick back and figure out things as you go along, that&#8217;s alright too. It is your right as a human being to do the amount of work you think is necessary to be happy. For some this involves 16-hour days festering under fluorescent tubes. For others, this involves being outdoors and building things. For others, it kind of involves a lot of random things. It&#8217;s your life, neither the government, your friends, parents, families, talking heads on TV, self-help gurus, priests, rabbis, imams, or swamis need to be in the business of telling you how to live it.</p>

<p>Now, with the current federal election over, Obama has four more years to deliver on his promises. Being human, he won&#8217;t deliver on them all, but the American people just granted him an extension. While I hope he delivers on some, and misses the ball on others, I do know it&#8217;s up to us to keep an eye on him and the government as a whole, and gradually try to effect the sea change I spoke about earlier. Revolutions don&#8217;t happen overnight, even in this day and age. Patience is key.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Communities and Conduct...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/01/on-communities-and-conduct-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T02:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/01/on-communities-and-conduct-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/appnet.png" width="781" height="446" title="'alpha dot app dot net slash pod'" ></p>

<p>I&#8217;ve recently jumped onto a new social networking service called <a href="http://join.app.net/">app.net</a>. Founded by <a href="http://daltoncaldwell.com/">Dalton Caldwell</a>, app.net is, at a basic level, an ad-free version of Twitter. You basically pay $5 a month or $36 a year to join, and from there it&#8217;s pretty smooth sailing. Like any new service online, there&#8217;s a small fanatical userbase laying the groundwork for the new community, including the &#8220;tone&#8221;&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A few years ago, when <a href="http://www.technogeno.us/">Ryan</a> and I were kicking off <a href="http://talknightlife.com/">TNL</a>, one of the things we thought about was setting the standard for discourse in the community. The initial way we did this was via an invite system. We basically told people we knew and liked about the new site, gave them the gateway password, and told them to have at it while we built it. We invited people we knew were capable of intelligent discourse, as well as deliberately inviting a few &#8220;disruptive&#8221; elements, just to see if our little idea of the community setting the tone worked. For the most part, it did. Where our previous community frequently walked the line with porn, spam, and some pretty vicious personal battles, the TNL experiment proved to be mild in comparison. (Yes, mild&#8230;I wish we exported the blue site DB before we got shown the door, there were some real gems in there!) However, in general, it seemed to prove a point that an online community, especially a niche one, is capable of being largely self-regulating.</p>

<p>But, if a community grows to be amazingly large, can it self-police? It&#8217;s hard to say. Look at Facebook. Even if you have a limited friend list, you are still subject to the content they post, and they generally take influence from their friends, and so on. So, Facebook has devolved into a mindless mash of memes, chain letters, tabloid news, and general idiocy. However, objectively, sometimes general idiocy can be fun. I&#8217;ll gladly admit to laughing at the latest meme. I love &#8220;Me Gusta&#8221; ragefaces and the &#8220;Because &#8216;Fuck You&#8217;, That&#8217;s Why!&#8221; meme actually kind of sums up how I feel about most things I do. However, the general tone of Facebook is one of a shopping mall with disinterested mall cops who only do what they have to do, in order to keep their jobs. And the self-policing actions are generally arbitrary. People will laugh at a video of a guy getting hit by a train, but not if it originated from someone they have a problem with. Then it&#8217;s game on, they&#8217;re clicking &#8220;hide/report&#8221; for all it&#8217;s worth.</p>

<p>Twitter isn&#8217;t much better off. Due to it&#8217;s nature it is limited to short messages, but now that they have to make money, they are injecting ads into every available nook and cranny of the service. Which, since it&#8217;s a free service, they have every right to. It&#8217;s basically the mall, but you can only say things in short sentences. Very chaotic, and of course prone to brain-dropping syndrome.</p>

<p>Now, app.net is far smaller than both Facebook and Twitter. As of last count, they have less than 30,000 users. Which isn&#8217;t bad for a service that is not owned by a major corporation, and explicitly asks you to pay money for access, in exchange for providing a clean and friendly environment. It is the VIP lounge of the social networking scene. Well, back when VIP lounges actually were VIP anyhow.</p>

<p>The virtue of this small paywall is that it tends to keep the casual user out. When you have an open social network or community site, basically anyone with something to say can come by. Now, I&#8217;m all about giving people the freedom to express themselves, but on the internet, the price of that freedom is spam and a lower quality of conduct. On a free network, that is. Spammers aren&#8217;t going to pay to access a small community of individuals who have no interest in their products, and anyone with a &#8220;casual&#8221; opinion or an insult isn&#8217;t going to pay money just to rattle someone&#8217;s cage. With app.net, it has led to a general atmosphere of camaraderie and educated discourse. While the language itself is as &#8220;free&#8221; as any other site, it&#8217;s generally used in context, and not just for the sake of saying &#8220;fuck&#8221; every third word. And the feeling is generally virulent. The user feels he or she needs to be at the level of the community in order to engage them. I post on there a few times a day, and I&#8217;m usually pretty cautious about how I phrase myself. Now, one of the virtues of app.net is an open API. You pay a little extra for access, but it allows for a whole host of third-party applications and tie-ins. Today, I started using an <a href="http://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a>recipe to link my Instagram feed to app.net. While something like this is encouraged as it makes app.net more appealing, I almost feel that I should maybe de-link it, since some of my Instagrams are a bit low-brow for the community.</p>

<p>However, it seems app.net, with it&#8217;s spirit of dissatisfaction against the status quo of monolithic and exploitative social networks like Facebook and Twitter, is proving on a larger scale, that the early adopters can and do set the tone and unwritten code of conduct for a web community and social network. It will be an interesting experiment to watch, especially if it catches fire in a major way. How will advertisers approach a community that has no love for their techniques, but still uses their products anyways? How will they advertise in a place with no advertising mechanism? Will app.net cancel the accounts of spammers? Those questions do remain. I can see &#8220;guerrilla marketers&#8221; and so-called &#8220;social media consultants&#8221; signing up at the least. Those types of people lose sleep over the fact that somewhere in the world, there&#8217;s a social media service they aren&#8217;t a part of. God forbid their already-rigged metrics slip half a percentage point. Wait till they find out there&#8217;s services in China with half-a-billion members who conduct their daily discourse entirely in Mandarin. They&#8217;ll be running down to the mall kiosks to buy Rosetta Stone - Mandarin Edition.</p>

<p>Thankfully app.net has a very prominent blocking feature.</p>

<p>The way I see it developing is much like TV networks such as HBO did. People specifically pay money to access HBO, not only for it&#8217;s quality unfiltered content, but because there are no obvious ads. I say &#8216;obvious&#8217; since I do consider the little half-hour bits about stuff on HBO produced by HBO to be a form of advertising designed to keep you subscribed. Which is fine. It is the service merely preserving itself. I guess the app.net staff does the same thing, since Dalton actively participates in the community and keeps people informed on &#8220;what&#8217;s next&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>Personally, I think it&#8217;s the future. I think social media is going to go more &#8220;boutique&#8221;, and less &#8220;mall&#8221;, and people will have to adjust their thinking accordingly. The open internet will and should always still be there, but more and more, I see paid-for and niche social and community sites becoming the norm as people tire of the constant bombardment of advertisers on the large free services like Facebook and Twitter.</p>

<p>They aren&#8217;t destined for failure either. I can actually see them adopting a two-tiered approach in the classic web fashion. Free access with ads, or pay a small monthly fee to remove them. They&#8217;ll take a page from the small innovators like app.net and call it their own. However, to truly compete, they need more effective filters. An ad-free experience means nothing if there&#8217;s still guerrilla marketers vying for your attention. &#8220;Hey Pod, haven&#8217;t seen you in awhile, how&#8217;s life? Oh really? Cool, well, ya know, I can get you 10,000 followers in a month if you act right now!&#8221;.</p>

<p>But that&#8217;s for another rant.</p>

<p>I think I&#8217;m going to go post some cat photos on Facebook and say the word &#8216;fuck&#8217; a few times in succession. Then off to app.net and make recommendations on camera equipment.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The virtues of open-source...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/29/the-virtues-of-open-source-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T13:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/29/the-virtues-of-open-source-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ruby.png" width="679" height="410" title="'Coding'" ></p>

<p>Sorry about the dearth of updates over the past few days. The wedding edit took some time, as well as real-life things having to happen as well. And then Halloween. The biggest, most interesting challenge, however, was the selection and deployment of a web application to display the edited photos from Tal and Erick&#8217;s wedding&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The edit itself went flawlessly. With my MacBook Air being a completely solid-state system, the actual rendering and editing took no time at all. Any time spent was purely on creative decisions. Protip - double-check that your sensor is clean. Cloudless blue skies make for wonderful wedding backdrops, but every little dust particle shows up. And the ultrasonic cleaner will not get them all. I spent a good amount of time spotting each photo. I usually check my sensor, but my MK II has the cleaning system, so I thought nothing of it. Wrong. Dust still adheres to the sensor surface.</p>

<p>I teased the bride and groom with little Instagram previews of my progress. It was a photo of a photo, but they got a kick out of it.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/23//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/RJTU0XAgCa/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage2.s3.amazonaws.com/ba2799ba1d7311e2959322000a1e9e0c_7.jpg' alt='Your turn in the render render @simply_sarah7' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='308863042945417370_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Finally, I completed the edit, and then had to tackle the task of how best to display the photos.</p>

<p>Now, the obvious solution would have been to just use a canned solution like Flickr, or 500 px. While both services have their strong points, the fact that I don&#8217;t have direct control over my content did give me cause for concern. Plus, with my recent forays into the world of building web applications and coding, I wanted to roll my own solution as much as possible.</p>

<p>Initially, I wanted to present the site via Octopress. I have experience in Octopress now, because of this blog, and several photo display plugins have been written for the platform.</p>

<p>I had done some research, and found that the web app <a href="http://fancyapps.com/fancybox">Fancybox</a> integrated somewhat smoothly with Octopress. Also, a fellow Octopress user, <a href="http://tritarget.org/blog/2012/05/07/integrating-photos-into-octopress-using-fancybox-and-plugin/">Tritarget</a> had written a pretty good plugin which made the display of photos even easier, since it utilized simple Markdown tags, rather than coding raw HTML.</p>

<p>To make things easy, and not interfere with the operation of this blog, I chose to spin up another instance on my <a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a> account. Heroku is the ideal choice for this and other projects of mine because I can spin up as many instances as I want, and only accrue charges for the total amount of resources (regardless of the number of apps) that I consume. After a little tweaking and adjustments, I got Fancybox and the plugin to play nice with Octopress.</p>

<p>Fancybox is probably the best-looking HTML-based photo display app out there. Slick transitions, a great UI, and easy implementation (mostly), make for a great quick-and-dirty display solution. However, the downside is, there is no practical way, that I found, to do a &#8220;gallery&#8221;. And a gallery was needed since my final edit came to 530 photos.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/preview_collage.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Previews'" ></p>

<p>And I certainly wasn&#8217;t going to manually input the Markdown tags for 530 photos. So, with that in mind, I decided to divest my thoughts of using Octopress. I set out to find a dedicated photo display solution. Some enterprising individuals had written plugins which can read Flickr sets, but I didn&#8217;t want to host on Flickr, for copyright and personal reasons. So, I googled around a bit and found several Rails-based photo gallery apps.</p>

<p>Now, some of you may ask, why wouldn&#8217;t I just use the Rails-based photo gallery app that I had already, i.e. <a href="http://seenightlife.com/">See Nightlife</a>?</p>

<p>Well, to be honest, See Nightlife is broken. I can upload and display, but all organizational tools are offline. It&#8217;s a &#8220;write once&#8221; solution as it stands. I can&#8217;t even delete photos. Also, Ryan and I simply haven&#8217;t had the time to fix it. Plus, the app it was based on, <a href="https://github.com/rapind/albumdy">Albumdy</a> is no longer being maintained.</p>

<p>As this was to display the wedding photos of two of my closest friends, something a little more reliable needed to be found. These are wedding photos, not a bunch of images of kids blindly worshipping some guy playing music off of his Mac.</p>

<p>So, with that in mind, I settled on a fairly popular Rails app called <a href="http://balderapp.com/">Balder.</a></p>

<p>Developed and maintained by Espen Antonsen out of Norway, Balder is a currently-maintained-and-produced Rails app for displaying photos in a collection/album format. And it fit my use case perfectly, as I wanted to host my photos on S3, and have the app live on Heroku. Heroku is more for running applications, and not storage. S3 is eminently more suited to storage, hence &#8220;Simple Storage Service&#8221; (S3). Espen himself uses this setup, and even provided a howto guide <a href="http://blog.inspired.no/rails-photo-gallery-balder-on-heroku-and-s3-726/">on his blog</a> on how to do it. In a nutshell, you provide Balder your S3 key, secret, and bucket name in a config file, commit to Heroku, and go from there. The one stumbling block I encountered is that the uploader itself tries to call an EXIF display module, which is dependent on a UNIX executable, which to my knowledge, cannot be installed on Heroku. So, even though the initial deployment was fast, the actual implementation wasn&#8217;t.</p>

<p>Now, where the virtues of open source kick in is that I had the code for Balder on my local machine. Through Heroku&#8217;s logging, I could see where the app was breaking uploads. I&#8217;m still a &#8216;babe in the woods&#8217; when it comes to coding, but I can read what the code is doing. I saw where it was getting hung up, but had no idea on how to fix it, or comment it out, since I specifically didn&#8217;t need EXIF data to be displayed. For those who may not be familiar, EXIF data is basically metadata contained in a JPEG file, which shows things like the camera type, exposure settings, and so on. You can see the EXIF data of a photo by doing the &#8220;File Info&#8221; function on your operating system of choice.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/exif.png" width="964" height="541" title="'Coding'" ></p>

<p>So, via the <a href="https://github.com/espen/balder">issues tracker in the Github repository for Balder</a>, I submitted a request for support from the developer. Now, since the app is free, and Espen derives no income from it, he was under zero obligation to respond to me. Since it was the weekend, I didn&#8217;t expect much right away. But, by this morning, he had filed a response to my request:</p>

<blockquote><p>Try commenting out &#8220;before_create :exif_read&#8221; in the photo model. I will look into this later but currently too busy with other work.</p><footer><strong>Espen Antonsen</strong> <cite><a href='https://github.com/espen/balder/issues/36'>HTML5 Uploader Generates HTTP Error</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I appreciated his honesty, that&#8217;s for sure. Way more than I expected. Most free open-source projects are one-shot deals where the developer does the initial work, and then forgets about it. So, I was pleasantly surprised at a reply.</p>

<p>And fortunately, his solution worked. I commented out a call to the non-existent EXIF module, and successfully uploaded some photos as a test. After confidently seeing that they displayed and cycled according to my wishes, I then began to upload the wedding photos in earnest. Balder has an excellent organizational structure. I can create a collection, let&#8217;s call it &#8220;Wedding&#8221;, and then albums for each portion of the event. Very slick. Five stars. And wonderful support from someone whom isn&#8217;t even obligated to do so.</p>

<p>Now, if this was a closed-source solution or a problem with a hosted service like Flickr, I would have had no way of figuring out what was wrong. I would have had to email their support, wait, and hope they could get to the issue in time. With open-source, I can peek under the hood, make some educated assessments as to what the issue is, and attempt a fix on my own. Or at the least, get concrete info that the developer understands so he or she can make a more effective fix. Plus, I got to learn a little more about just what makes a Rails-based web app tick.</p>

<p>Right now, the app is deployed to Heroku, and running smoothly. I plan on using Balder in general, from here on out and whenever possible for my hosting needs. Open source for the win, as they say.</p>

<ul>
<li>Sidebar: I&#8217;d love to show you guys the results of the wedding, but since it was a personal affair, I would rather receive clearance before I share the results with the public. Thanks for understanding, all.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A classic sunset...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/23/a-classic-sunset-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T00:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/23/a-classic-sunset-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/t-2535.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Perty'" ></p>

<p>You definitely can&#8217;t argue with the sunsets on the Outer Banks of North Carolina.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Sure, sunset photos are contrived and &#8220;have been done&#8221;, but sometimes, regardless of your skill level, every photographer needs to shoot a few &#8220;typical&#8221; images. If anything, for those of us who take ourselves too seriously, you can justify it as a &#8220;test&#8221; or &#8220;calibration&#8221; or &#8220;comparison&#8221;.</p>

<p>Besides, it&#8217;s rather nice-looking.</p>

<p>I think in terms of &#8220;a place to go to do nothing&#8221;, Emerald Isle has Key West beat. There is absolutely nothing going on but the weather. No clubs, no bars, just some pretty pricey real estate and people just kicking back. You have to bring your own fun, essentially. Which was kind of nice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting weddings...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/22/shooting-weddings-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T01:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/22/shooting-weddings-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/talerick_preview.jpg" width="960" height="610" title="'FU-T'" ></p>

<p>A huge congratulations to my friends and neighbors Talmage and Erick on their wedding this past weekend. We all went up to Emerald Isle, NC for the ceremony. It was pretty spectacular.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t explicitly advertise myself as a wedding photographer. While I know it can be lucrative, I&#8217;ve also heard a lot of horror stories from other shooters about the stress involved, and not just from bridezillas either&#8230;</p>

<p>But I don&#8217;t turn down weddings that come my way&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Typically, a wedding will come my way about once a year. It&#8217;s always through a friend or acquaintance. And, for the most part, they know how I shoot when they hire me. They know that I&#8217;m definitely not a wedding photography specialist.</p>

<p>The wedding I shot this past weekend with Tal and Erick was a great example. I&#8217;ve known Tal since about 2004 through the club scene and her being a poster on TNL, and Erick for a little bit longer than that. They both knew my specialties in terms of photography. But, they also wanted a distinct look and feel for their photos, and also the obvious of preferring to hire a friend rather than someone they didn&#8217;t know.</p>

<p>For me, it was an opportunity to change things up a bit in terms of my photo work, and an excuse to rent some quality equipment and maybe try some new concepts.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/19//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q_FrW8ggJe/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage6.s3.amazonaws.com/d13ac15c1a5511e29c6822000a1f9688_7.jpg' alt='Tele for @talmagelisabeth wedding.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=34.682976,-76.912536'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=34.682976,-76.912536&markers=34.682976,-76.912536&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Best House At The Biotch' /></a><br/>Taken at Best House At The Biotch</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='305988269492011614_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>My loadout for the wedding started as a grandiose idea in my head. Since my &#8220;gift&#8221; to them was essentially my work (only thing I asked for was transport and lodging), I wanted to make it shine. However, since I&#8217;m a one-man show here, eventually less was more. My final kit was:</p>

<ul>
<li>5D MK II - primary body</li>
<li>50D - backup body</li>
<li>580 EX Speedlite</li>
<li>580 EX II Speedlite from <a href="http://lensrentals.com/">Lens Rentals</a>.</li>
<li>16-35mm 2.8 L zoom lens</li>
<li>50mm 1.2 L prime lens</li>
<li>70-200 2.8 II L zoom lens</li>
<li>2 Fong Lightspheres from <a href="http://lensrentals.com/">Lens Rentals</a></li>
<li>ST-E2 Speedlite transmitter</li>
<li>2 32 GB CF cards</li>
<li>Joby Gorillapod</li>
<li>The Podbook Air</li>
<li>A GoPro Hero 2 from <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>And even then this was heavy. That&#8217;s a lot of glass and accessories to haul with you.</p>

<p>I was there primarily in a still-photography capacity, however, I did want to shoot some video too. A mutual friend, Pat Theodore, was on video duty with his Nikons, but I offered to throw in whatever I got with the GoPro and my MK II into the mix.</p>

<p>Thankfully, the one variable that I could not control cooperated. The weather was amazing.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/19//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q-v-TfggF9/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/52bcbd681a3b11e282a722000a1c8689_7.jpg' alt='Perty.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=34.680565526,-76.923046936'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=34.680565526,-76.923046936&markers=34.680565526,-76.923046936&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='On The Beach Drinking Beers' /></a><br/>Taken at On The Beach Drinking Beers</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='305892814431060349_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>The Emerald Isle weather gods were definitely with us that day. And the wedding was planned to be right around sunset.</p>

<p>The true challenge of the wedding really wasn&#8217;t on a technical level for me. I was shooting at golden hour, on the beach, with people I know and get along famously with. The real challenge was on an organizational level. As I was the only still shooter for the wedding, I had my hands full, even with a small party (around 30 people), such as this one. I can see now why full-time wedding shooters, always have a second person with them. I got the photos I wanted, and then some, but it was definitely a few minutes of sheer intensity as I scrambled around to get the images. The biggest savior was definitely the 70-200. From a practical standpoint, the lens enabled me to get &#8220;the&#8221; key images of the actual vows portion of the ceremony, without being on top of the bride and groom. I also utilized one of the 580s I had with me as a remote light. I used the Gorillapod to strap it to the &#8220;altar&#8221; framework and put it on a secondary channel which I clicked over to as I needed it. I ended up not really using it, but it was nice to have on hand. And I had the GoPro running as a continuous record of the ceremony. I wonder how that came out&#8230;</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tal-3107.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'In close but not'" ></p>

<p>And, one can definitely not argue with the virtue of having someone trained in makeup on hand. One of Tal&#8217;s friends, Kristin, along with Michelle T, handled that duty. Sure, brides have to look their best, but us behind the lens appreciate it too. A well-done makeup job saves us enormous amounts of time later. Tal has a natural glow to her anyways, but the makeup job will be saving me hours of time in post production this coming week.</p>

<p>Now, where the ceremony was mainly, from a technical perspective, about the 70-200, the candids at the reception back at the beach house were all about going wide, and using my 50 1.2 L. While not a nightclub setting, the lighting was darker and variable, and I wanted to get some &#8220;candids&#8221; like they expected out of me. And the 50 came through, especially later, when someone (not gonna say who!) decided to set off some heavy-duty fireworks in celebration of the happy couple.</p>

<p>That being said, it was definitely a great departure from my norm in terms of shooting. I probably bought a little more equipment than I really needed to for this specific ceremony, but, it is best to be overprepared than under. And, a wedding is one situation where you definitely need to make the client aware of whether you are there for stills, or video. I grabbed some video as time permitted, but I didn&#8217;t make it a priority. I had the GoPro with me mainly as an experiment, and anything out of the MK II was when the moment became rather static.</p>

<p>After this experience, I can say I do have more of an appreciation for what full-time wedding shooters do. It&#8217;s a tough job, even if you know the people involved. Would I get into wedding photography full-time? Well, only if I could get a gig like this past one on a regular basis. I&#8217;m not too sure if I&#8217;d be down for a full-on church-and-500-family-members-and-freeloaders style ceremony.</p>

<p>But, more importantly, congrats once again to Talmage and Erick. You guys rock. I&#8217;ll have your custom site and edits sorted probably around the time you get in from Captiva&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoPro has had a busy week...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/17/gopro-has-had-a-busy-week-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-17T10:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/17/gopro-has-had-a-busy-week-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51601636?title=1&amp;byline=1&amp;portrait=1" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51601636">• GoPro Hero 2 Protune Test - Nighttime Drive •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>The fine folks at GoPro have had a busy week. For existing owners of the Hero2, they released a new firmware set, which included a new set of shooting modes collectively grouped under the name &#8216;Protune&#8217;. Protune basically doubles the bitrate of the GoPro&#8217;s recorded files to 35 Mbps, and produces a more &#8216;flat&#8217; file with no in-camera color corrections or sharpening. And, in bigger news, they rolled the GoPro Hero 3 last night, which adds built-in WiFi, 4K video recording (albeit at 15 FPS), all packaged in a smaller-profile body&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, the Hero 3 just went on sale for pre-order, so I obviously don&#8217;t have one on hand yet. I was this &#8220;&lt;>&#8221; close to buying a Hero 2, but fortunately I didn&#8217;t. I have the wedding of my great friends and neighbors Tal and Erick to shoot this weekend up in North Carolina, and I wanted to strap a GoPro next to the &#8220;altar&#8221; and record the vows portion from an alternate angle, so I was going to pull the trigger and buy a Hero 2. Fortunately, time kind of ran out on me, so I had to make do with borrowing <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis&#8217;</a> Hero 2. I told him I&#8217;d upgrade it to the Protune firmware while I was at it.</p>

<p>So, with that in mind, I figured I&#8217;d take Protune for a spin.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/16//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q3gj9EggEx/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/a2921adc180511e2a46d1231381b4837_7.jpg' alt='A #protune test of @gopro !' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='303854708114719025_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I strapped the Hero 2 to the front left bumper of the 210, and proceeded to record my drive down to Blue Martini in Brickell for my &#8220;Tuesday Tradition&#8221; shooting session over at Jive With The Band.</p>

<p>You can see the results above, and judge for yourself. I did some basic color correction and exposure adjustment in Final Cut Pro X, and exported this to Vimeo via Compressor 4 using the standard Vimeo preset.</p>

<p>The unaltered video out of the camera is very noisy. This was to be expected, since Protune deactivates all in-camera processing, including noise reduction. It&#8217;s about as close to RAW video as you are likely to get out of something in the class of the GoPro. Colors were very neutral and flat. The dynamic range was increased, due to the &#8220;flat&#8221; nature of the file. At first glance, it actually appeared to be worse than the previous firmware output.</p>

<p>However, this was the expected result. Ideally, if you can&#8217;t get true RAW output out of your camera, you want a file that is as untouched and as uncompressed as possible, to allow for these adjustments to be made with more precise tools present on your laptop. Which is exactly what Protune accommodates, as much as possible. Also, it does reveal the limitations of the tiny sensor in the camera. It&#8217;s a noisy mess, and GoPro is definitely to be commended for developing decent in-camera noise reduction and sharpening techniques for their standard firmware. FYI, you can turn Protune off and go back to the standard modes at any time.</p>

<p>That being said, for anyone remotely interested in video, I don&#8217;t recommend it. You can really make the output of the GoPro shine with Protune, using your choice of post-production software, whether it&#8217;s Final Cut Pro X, or GoPro&#8217;s own Cineform. Once you understand the purpose of Protune, it is definitely a winner. It gets the camera&#8217;s ideas about things out of the way of your workflow, and lets you make the decisions on color correction, sharpening, noise, and so on.</p>

<p>For a $300 unit, the GoPro Hero 2 with Protune is a winner in my book. I&#8217;ll be doing some daylight tests today and tomorrow, which I will post about soon thereafter.</p>

<p>As for the Hero 3? That will most likely make it into my bag in short order. GoPro, if you pick this up, I&#8217;m always game to beat around a demo unit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It is like my version of Mr Sparkle.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/my-version-of-mr-sparkle/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T18:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/my-version-of-mr-sparkle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/niceday-1479.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Mirinda'" ></p>

<p>It was a positively stunning day here in South Florida, so I jumped in the 210 and went out for a bit.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I made my usual Saturday stop at Whole Foods, this time the South Beach one. The Aventura one has better wraps, but the Beach one is closer, and I wanted to shoot some random stuff on the Beach anyways.</p>

<p>After my tuna wrap, I proceeded up Collins to the Ocean Terrace around 74th Street. I figured I&#8217;d try to get some shallow DOF shots out on the sand. I was experimenting with trying to capture one breaking wave, when an orange can thumped into my foot.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/niceday-1476.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Mirinda'" ></p>

<p>&#8220;Mirinda?&#8221; I thought, &#8220;What the hell is Mirinda?&#8221;</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a girl&#8217;s name in some quarters, but I never saw it applied to a beverage. So, curious, I picked up the can. It was unopened, and aside from the Mirinda logo, it lacked the usual nutritional value grid, and also the volume was listed as 330 mL only. No Imperial measurements. My god, it&#8217;s a can from the future!</p>

<p>It was totally my Mr Sparkle moment.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dnaLRbbc-54" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>But, my momentary flashback to a Simpsons episode faded, and it turns out Mirinda is a product of Pepsi, primarily distributed in Asia. The can actually said &#8220;Distributed by Pepsi Singapore&#8221; on the side.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QvBo3qggAv/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/e3132586156e11e283e622000a1fb86d_7.jpg' alt='This must have fallen off of a ship. #mirinda #singapore @norahlovesmakeup_mua idea? This is in Miami Beach.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/hudson'>Hudson</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.86046311,-80.1200069'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.86046311,-80.1200069&markers=25.86046311,-80.1200069&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Maracas Place' /></a><br/>Taken at Maracas Place</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301466906651656239_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I&#8217;m guessing it probably fell off of a passing cargo freighter, which most likely took on provisions in the port of Singapore. There&#8217;s an ever so slight chance it washed up from further away, but most likely it is the boring explanation.</p>

<p>This was totally my Mr Sparkle moment though.</p>

<p>Now, the can is still sealed, so in theory the beverage should be consumable. It&#8217;s in my fridge right now. I don&#8217;t drink soda anymore though&#8230;</p>

<p>Oh, and I&#8217;m totally loving how things look at 1.2 during broad daylight. Very surreal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone summed it up eloquently...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T03:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jordyn-6643.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'It fell in line...'" ></p>

<p>While some tell me my strength lies in capturing images, I also have been told I can write well. However, in terms of writing, I do tend to ramble. Hence, this blog&#8217;s tagline having the words &#8220;general ramblings&#8221;&#8230;</p>

<p>So, when someone asks for me to summarize something, it&#8217;s nigh-impossible for me to do. So, if you asked me to sum up my own body of photographic work, I&#8217;d be at a loss to condense it to a sentence or two. I cringe at committing grammar crimes when I have to post to Twitter. The art of summary is lost to me.</p>

<p>However, someone summarized what I do so well for me just a few minutes ago&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->




<blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it&#8230;</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>And <em>boom</em>, that sums it up.</p>

<p>I could sit here for hours expounding on noise levels, a-to-d conversions, electric fields emanating from poorly-shielded cabling, the native ISO of a given sensor, and don&#8217;t-point-your-lens-at-a-10-watt-laser-you-fool type of things and it wouldn&#8217;t be a summary of how I manage to pull off a shot. It&#8217;d be the Book of Pod so to speak. Which, some people like, and some people don&#8217;t.</p>

<p>It actually speaks volumes about having an outside opinion.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QtZ7SrAgIA/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4906bc4c14f011e2bacf123138179cfe_7.jpg' alt='You can see the guy about to jump out.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.82752892,-80.187165969'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.82752892,-80.187165969&markers=25.82752892,-80.187165969&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='55th Street Station' /></a><br/>Taken at 55th Street Station</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301010775764500992_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I had just come back from a nighttime run (yes Ryan, I do run around this neighborhood at 1 AM) and I picked up a text conversation where I had left it off earlier. My friend Adriana had just moved from the construction mess called Brickell, to a cozy new joint on Collins Avenue in &#8220;Condo Canyon&#8221; with her boyfriend. She was inviting me over for a little housewarming thing tomorrow, and she mentioned the last thing she had picked up from her old apt was a piece of mine that she purchased back in 2009:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/frances_2008.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Frances at Space - 2008'" ></p>

<p>I had done an exhibit of some of my &#8220;dancer photos&#8221; at the first <a href="http://lifeisart.org">Life Is Art</a> exhibit in Wynwood. Life is Art, by <a href="http://soulofmiami.org">Soul of Miami</a> founder James Echols, is a local organization that supports up-and-coming artists of all stripes. Since that first open show in 2009, they&#8217;ve come a long way and are quite renowned in the art community, especially amongst artists who may not be &#8220;hip&#8221; enough to warrant the attention of some of the more corporate art organizations in town. Adriana, at the time, was their treasurer, and had expressed an interest in obtaining a print of one of my images, specifically the one above. So, her mom took it upon herself to pull me aside and purchase it from me for her. As my exhibit was digital (I didn&#8217;t have the budget to produce 20 prints of size), I took the &#8220;order&#8221; and contacted my print provider to generate a canvas-framed print for me of this piece. A few weeks later, it was delivered to Adriana, to much acclaim. Oddly enough it&#8217;s the only &#8220;dancer&#8221; piece I have ever sold. Either I just haven&#8217;t marketed them properly or people don&#8217;t go for half-naked girls in smoky nightclubs as <em>objets d&#8217;art</em>.</p>

<p>Fast-forward to today. As pieces of art are often delicate, they are usually transported separately from other items in a moving adventure. Anyways, in a conversation about that piece tonight, Adriana was asking me about how I capture moments like that, and I did have a hard time summarizing it up. So, she put it into words that had previously escaped me:</p>

<blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it&#8230;</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>And yes, that&#8217;s it. Minus the technical details, which, if anyone asks, I&#8217;ll gladly explain, that&#8217;s pretty much it. I see the image in my head, and I wait for the world to fall in line. Whether it&#8217;s in a club or below a deserted bridge in Key West, that&#8217;s it. If I had to sum it up into a Twitter-friendly sentence, that is it.</p>

<p>Now, if I can summarize this post, it would be, &#8220;A different perspective always helps&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>Oh, and Ade, thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting video wide open.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T12:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51143544" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51143544">• 50 1.2 L video test wide open at 1.2 •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>Shooting video using the 50 1.2 L is an interesting experience, to say the least&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>One of the biggest things cinematographers and videographers, such as <a href="http://watcha3.com/">Buster</a> over at A3, have conveyed to me, is the desire to shoot at the lowest ISO possible when shooting video, preferably below ISO 1000, though I have gotten great results at ISO 1600, and I&#8217;ll go beyond that, if I know the video is going to be laden with effects in post.</p>

<p>That being said, the obvious requirement to shoot at a low ISO is, lots of light. And &#8220;lots of light&#8221; in the video world, means something a bit different than in the world of still photography, for a few reasons.</p>

<p>First off, due to the nature of video, you are limited to a shutter speed, at the low end, of 1/30 second. Though, for the best results, most videographers, including <a href="http://blog.vincentlaforet.com">Vincent Laforet</a>, recommend a shutter speed of 1/50 second, to mesh better with common monitor refresh rates. So, almost by default, you are limited in your light gathering ability, when shooting video.</p>

<p>At that point, your options are, crank the ISO, open up as fast as your lens can go, or dump a lot of light on the scene. Or any combination thereof.</p>

<p>As an experiment, I chose to shoot the sequence above at ISO 320, 1/50 second shutter speed, all wide open at f1.2. As you can see, Caroline drifts in and out of the zone of critical focus on numerous occasions. However, the video quality is amazing. At ISO 320, the 5D MK II generates superb results. In reality I could have stopped down a bit, since the lighting tech at Blue Martini was kind enough to have the system running at maximum intensity at the time.</p>

<p>I can definitely recommend the 50 1.2 L for video work. It&#8217;s a very versatile prime, and the image quality is amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On mental instability...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/on-mental-instability-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T02:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/on-mental-instability-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9070.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The crazy ones.'" ></p>

<p>An article in the New York Times caught my eye today, on the subject of <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes">medicating the children of our society</a> for a range of supposed mental illnesses.</p>

<p>Now, I don&#8217;t condemn the benefits of modern medicine, and I also don&#8217;t condemn the use of drugs recreationally. However, as odd as it may sound with this stance, I&#8217;m actually kind of against the overprescription of psychotropic medications.</p>

<p>For several reasons&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->




<blockquote><p>We’ve decided as a society that it’s too expensive to modify the kid’s environment. So we have to modify the kid.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz interviews Dr Michael Anderson</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes'>Attention Disorder or Not, Pills to Help in School</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I&#8217;m not an educational professional. I&#8217;ve been told I can convey knowledge rather effectively, but educational techniques are not in any of my various professional and non-professional job descriptions.</p>

<p>Be that as it may, I do pay attention to trends in society with regards to the educational methods being used to teach children today. And, frankly, the trend of medicating children this way scares me.</p>

<p>Objectively, it&#8217;s lazy. The educators lack the patience to effectively deal with the children, so they fall back on a pharmaceutical solution. Now, I&#8217;ll grant you that there may be children who genuinely need these medications just to function in daily life, but from the article above, it seems to reflect the now-obvious trend of seeing a pharmaceutical solution as a way out.</p>

<blockquote><p>On the Rocafort family’s kitchen shelf in Ball Ground, Ga., next to the peanut butter and chicken broth, sits a wire basket brimming with bottles of the children’s medications, prescribed by Dr. Anderson: Adderall for Alexis, 12; and Ethan, 9; Risperdal (an antipsychotic for mood stabilization) for Quintn and Perry, both 11; and Clonidine (a sleep aid to counteract the other medications) for all four, taken nightly.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes'>www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I would call it a statistical norm if one of the children in the family described here required medicating, but when each and every child is on a spectrum of psychotropic drugs, there&#8217;s clear evidence to suggest overprescription is at work here. Nevermind what Mom and Dad might be on.</p>

<blockquote><p>To help me focus on my school work, my homework, listening to Mom and Dad, and not doing what I used to do to my teachers, to make them mad,” he said. He described the week in the hospital and the effects of Risperdal: “If I don’t take my medicine I’d be having attitudes. I’d be disrespecting my parents. I wouldn’t be like this.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz interviewing Quintn Rocafort, age 11</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes'>www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Listen, when I was 11, I was a disrespectful little shit. I regularly threw fits, pissed off my parents and teachers, and didn&#8217;t have that many friends. Yeah, some things never change. However, I was usually lumped in, in terms of intelligence, with the &#8220;gifted&#8221; children, and the school (which was not well-funded!), sought out non-pharmaceutical solutions to my supposed problems. Now, this was the 1980s, so most of the drugs being prescribed to kids these days didn&#8217;t exist, or if they did, it was never considered that they should be given to an 11 year-old child. Basically, the general gist in my case was &#8220;he&#8217;ll grow out of it&#8221;, or &#8220;If he keeps it up, someone will set him straight&#8221;.</p>

<p>However, at no time were my supposed issues considered abnormal or irregular. If anything, the most my parents and teachers did was channel the energy into different areas where my spontaneity would be maximized. A child today who acted like I did, would be force-fed Adderall and told to get back to crunching away at math.</p>

<p>Joking and humor aside though, I managed to get through it and make the most of my mental attributes. I&#8217;ve never been to a therapist, and I&#8217;ve never been on a psychotropic regimen (I took Adderall once and it made me sick), and I manage to pay the bills, maintain a home, and have a social life inside and outside of my work. In other words, I&#8217;m in the ballpark with regards to most statistical norms in American society.</p>

<p>That being said, I do recognize my own mental quirks. I can&#8217;t focus on something for more than ten or fifteen minutes at a time. My mind is always on fire in twenty different directions at once. Only if something truly engages me, can I get around this. For example, I can &#8220;zone out&#8221; and shoot for hours on end. I can write on subjects that interest me without deviating from the task. However, even with tasks I find pointless or uninteresting, if they need to get done, I&#8217;ll get around to doing it by the time it needs to be completed. Usually.</p>

<p>I have a vague notion of time, and I question 95 percent of what crosses my path, so to speak. I&#8217;ll deviate and spend an hour arguing with someone on how pointless something is. For example, a pet peeve of mine is people who take a hour to make a mundane decision, like, what to eat for lunch. My take on lunch or any meal is, &#8220;eat it and move on to the next thing&#8230;&#8221;, since in my head, there&#8217;s other things way more interesting than food. Give me a reasonably-healthy buffet or salad-bar style setup. I&#8217;d rather spend the time multitasking, i.e. I can eat and bang out a blog article, edit some photos, optimize some code, or be social. Food goes in one way, and it comes out another. Whoopee. I&#8217;m sure every foodie in town will want to kill me now.</p>

<p>I also have a hard time bringing people into my inner circle. I&#8217;m severely paranoid around new people. Though is it paranoia if they really are out to get you? But, with time, I&#8217;ll bring people into the circle. Otherwise I&#8217;m pretty a pretty cold customer. Those who know me know the whole &#8220;sunglasses and &#8216;I am smiling&#8217; &#8221; routine.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/30//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QNmbQuAgJE/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/8b20b1280b3b11e2839c1231381b6c7e_7.jpg' alt='I am smiling.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/lo-fi'>Lo-fi</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.849085,-80.15046864'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.849085,-80.15046864&markers=25.849085,-80.15046864&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Atlantic Broadband' /></a><br/>Taken at Atlantic Broadband</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='292058549993996868_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Sidebar: I had to deviate from writing this article to derive the media_id of that Instagram photo. It took a minute or two since I saw something that caught my eye along the way. Which made me think of something else, a way of getting that ID without having to kick the Instagram API. Which brings me to my point.</p>

<p>My point is, is that my mental quirks make me who I am. I&#8217;m a paranoid, random sort of guy who can&#8217;t focus on things for long periods of time and I&#8217;m always going off in twenty different directions at once. But, I believe it is those aspects of my personality which enable my creativity and ingenuity. If my parents, or later on, I myself, chose to medicate those quirks away, what would be left?</p>

<p>Basically another BlackBerry-wielding drone in the machine, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Listen, I&#8217;m no revolutionary. I fill out the forms when I have to, and I have &#8220;normal&#8221; things like bills and household chores and so forth. My life is actually pretty mundane sometimes. Though the point is, I was never medicated or told outright to stop acting a certain way. I figured it out as I went along, and I manage to maintain a semblance of a healthy existence, while still retaining the characteristics which make me who I am. All without the modifying effects of psychotropic medications.</p>

<p>And yes, I&#8217;m well aware that just about any substance consumed could be considered a mood-altering substance, but I&#8217;m certainly not dependent on any of them. I love my energy drinks but I don&#8217;t require them to stay ahead. I&#8217;ll get through the day. Comparing a Red Bull to an Adderall regimen is like comparing a 9mm round to a cluster bomb unit though. Same idea (boom), but a huge degree of difference in said boom.</p>

<p>Plus, beyond the poorly-understood detrimental health effects upon the children of our society caused by these substances, it&#8217;s coaching society into a habit of medicating our mental quirks away. Already, there&#8217;s generations of people my age and older who regularly medicate themselves to &#8220;stay ahead&#8221;, and &#8220;stay competitive&#8221;. And these habits are passed down to their children. In the pursuit of the almighty dollar, people drop a panoply of psychotropic medications on a scale to make the ghost of Elvis envious. College students deal in pharmaceuticals just to get that A on the final. Here&#8217;s a clue on that, hotshot, the answers are usually found rather easily, and cheaper than scoring some of Merck&#8217;s finest. Yes, I&#8217;m saying that you can pay off a TA to get the answer key, pretty much.</p>

<p>Now, don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not condemning modern medicine. If I get shot or otherwise grievously injured, I want the best technology that the medical field can provide to patch me up and make me better. I&#8217;m just not so sure we should be medicating away our supposed mental quirks, since it seems that we, as a society, are bent on numbing and erasing the individual features of our psyche that make each and every one of us unique. Do we really all want to be on this statistical norm? Is the goal in life to tap away at Excel spreadsheets all day under the harsh glare of fluorescent lights? The paranoid part of me says that the overmedication of society is conditioning for just that. A pseudo-state of complacency found in pill form. Blissful ignorance, if you will.</p>

<p>Sure, society needs fiends tapping away at Excel and crunching numbers, but you know what? I&#8217;ve met people, whom I consider crazy, who legitimately get off on that sort of thing. Enough that even without medication, there&#8217;s plenty of people who are motivated by their own personal thrill of solving a complex statistical problem in order to better optimize the interest rate on someone&#8217;s savings account. There&#8217;s enough &#8220;natural&#8221; accountants out there, is what I am getting at. I think we&#8217;re all capable of harnessing our own mental quirks to our benefit, and neither we, nor our children, need to be doped up on Adderall all the time.</p>

<p>And, it&#8217;s the crazy ones (yes, I know, I know, we&#8217;ve all seen the old Apple ads&#8230;) who are usually moving things forward for us as a society. Einstein wore the same outfit every day. Steve Jobs was a tyrant and yelled at people a lot, Leonardo was borderline anti-social, Van Gogh cut off his own ear. But these people left lasting positive impressions on society. If they had been medicated into submission, where would we be?</p>

<p>The long-term effects, beyond the physical, are that we are merely medicating away the effects of a sick society. We&#8217;re not getting at the root causes of the pressure to use these medications, we&#8217;re just merely masking the symptoms.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not here to condemn anyone&#8217;s use of any drug, legal or otherwise. It&#8217;s your body, it&#8217;s your choice. Just consider that you may be snuffing out what makes you unique in this world. I might be a whirlwind of random ramblings and crackpot schemes, but that&#8217;s what makes me who I am. If I adhere to a statistical norm and toe the party line all the time, there&#8217;s really no point in me, as a unique individual, in sticking around. And that, my dear small audience, is a fate worse than death.</p>

<p>Footnote: I&#8217;m not a medical professional, either. I&#8217;m just calling it like I see it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ramblings after the weekend...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08/ramblings-after-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T23:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08/ramblings-after-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9386.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Still here at 9 AM?'" ></p>

<p>It was one of those random &#8220;on and off&#8221; weekends.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Much like any other mental factor, creativity seems to have a finite supply of sorts, and can be slow to replenish. Thursday, I shot a scenic I&#8217;m really proud of, the aptly-titled (yes, I&#8217;m totally being narcissistic here) &#8220;Where The Buses Don&#8217;t Run&#8221;.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/outwhere_rev-8882.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'US 27 Northbound Broward County'" ></p>

<p>I did this on a Thursday night/Friday morning, and I did the editing and &#8220;mastering&#8221; work on Friday. When I intend to sell a print, I tend to nitpick. I&#8217;ll obsess over minute color corrections, lens flares, and wish for things like my print provider accepting TIFF uploads on the off chance there&#8217;s some minor compression artifacts which could be visible at a large enough print size.</p>

<p>Oh, and by the way, &#8220;Out Where The Buses Don&#8217;t Run&#8221; is for sale on my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">Fine Art America</a> site, along with eight other pieces I consider potential sellers. I&#8217;m getting more and more into shooting nighttime scenics. Though I could do without the bugs in the Everglades. There was a mosquito in the 210 on my way home that night. The hardest part was concentrating on keeping steady at 130 km/h while hoping the little bastard would just go away. I did the &#8220;open all windows and go even faster&#8221; trick and that seemed to help.</p>

<p>That being said, I was fully intent on going back out to shoot more scenics on Friday, but that actually never panned out. I couldn&#8217;t think of a location to scope out. I might try west this week, now that I think about it.</p>

<p>Saturday was my usual club night over at <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space</a>. Two of my favorites, Chus + Ceballos, were on hand to provide an extended musical soundtrack to the evening. These guys &#8220;get it&#8221;, they know they are there to keep the crowd moving, and they provide an excellent musical selection over the course of ten or more hours on the decks. Great guys in person, too. They&#8217;re always game for the photo op, and they actually love to meet their fans. They <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/06/the-musical-ecosystem/">know their place in the musical ecosystem</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9091.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'That Nikon is like a periscope'" ></p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QiwaZHAgNP/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/5be1081a11b011e2aeda22000a1de2e0_7.jpg' alt='Los Tios @chuslesteban @clubspacemiami @jhartlein @ppod @travisrogersmia More at http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/chus-and-ceballos-return-to-space#5' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='298013445259920207_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I still have to figure out how to derive that media_id without having to manually kick the Instagram API. If anyone knows how, let me know.</p>

<p>That being said, I definitely had &#8220;more creative energy&#8221; by that Saturday night. Some plans for early hours didn&#8217;t materialize. I was supposed to attend a bachelor/bachelorette party at Scarlett&#8217;s up in Hollywood, but the &#8220;confirmation&#8221; message never arrived that the people were actually gonna go. By then, it was 1:30 in the morning and I was already framing my mind from staring at desperate girls on the pole to actually doing something productive. So, I kind of said &#8220;the hell with it&#8221;, jumped into a <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car 2 Go</a>, and drove on over to Space.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QeHL8FAgAh/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/88cd369e104511e2b7ea22000a1fc2ec_7.jpg' alt='Saddle up. @car2gomiami to @clubspacemiami' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='296706232201379873_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Car 2 Go is saving me so much money in cab fare. It&#8217;s amazing. Plus, they never thought of my use case until I told them. They posted on Facebook about using their service to get to the Brickell Oktoberfest party, and taking the safe way (a cab) home. Agalmic cowboy diplomacy.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9217.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Hi Jordyn'" ></p>

<p>Anyways, Space was the usual &#8216;rock&#8217; of Miami nightlife this past weekend. Great atmosphere, an interesting crowd, and great music. It&#8217;s not a trendy VIP club, and it doesn&#8217;t aspire to be. In my mind it&#8217;s the heart of Miami nightlife. It is one venue you can go to without even bothering to check their website to see who is playing. A friend of mine suggested that their marketing campaign should be &#8220;Space: We&#8217;re fucking open.&#8221;</p>

<p>I did my usual rounds at the venue, including switching out to the 50 1.2 L as the morning rolled on. It&#8217;s a learning curve, but one I&#8217;m glad to participate in. It&#8217;s a great lens and you can do amazing things with it wide open. Every Canon user should have it in their arsenal.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9335.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Lucy I'm Home'" ></p>

<p>At 1.2, you will have throwaway images. Nature of the beast in a nightclub. Just keep shooting, but don&#8217;t turn it into a Golden BB spray-and-pray affair. If the shot doesn&#8217;t happen, it doesn&#8217;t happen.</p>

<p>I left a little after 9 AM Sunday morning. I woke up Sunday afternoon, since I had a Keys trip planned, but the weather totally did not cooperate. I ended up turning around on the Turnpike Extension after a huge downpour kicked in, with more forecast for Monday. Though Monday turned out to be a rather nice day. Such is luck I guess.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll try to make it down again in the next few weeks. Maybe after Halloween Weekend.</p>

<p>Totally random weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
