<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photo | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/photo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-03T17:33:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keys Standard Time.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/03/keys-standard-time/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T13:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/03/keys-standard-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648_blog.jpg" width="960" height="308" title="'Yellow Shark Channel'" ></p>

<p>I've always liked going down to the Keys, especially the Lower Keys and Key West.</p>

<p>It is one of the few places I've been to in the US where things are truly running at a different pace. No one's concerned about their latest Facebook status, what Justin Bieber said on Twitter, or what their Klout score (a rigged and meaningless metric by the way) is.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It's removed from the mainland as it were, by geography, but it's not a pig-ignorant backwater of the Ozarks populated by people who are poised to vote for Romney this coming November. You can go to Key West, relax, but not feel like you are in a premillenial timewarp. They are connected down there, they just choose not to make a big deal of it. That's actually the way I think they feel down there, "don't make a big deal of it".</p>

<p>After a fairly interesting morning of shooting photos of the Labor Day Weekend event at Space, featuring DJs AN21, Robert Dietz (a true master of his craft by the way), and Reboot (aka Frank...I always call DJs by their real names), I decided to call it off around 8 AM, get some rest, and actually go out and <em>produce</em> something photographically that day. I hadn't generated much other than nightlife-related material over the preceding few weeks, so I figured I should get to it and find an interesting slice of land to document.</p>

<p>So, I figured why not head south? I've had good photo experiences there before, and I've always made mental notes on stopping points on the way down. So around 4 PM after some much-needed rest, I jumped in the 210 and headed to the Turnpike southbound.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tipover.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Tip Over'" ></p>

<p>I like driving the Homestead Extension to the Florida Turnpike. It's fairly new so the pavement hasn't succumbed to the elements as of yet, and it's never so congested that you are reduced to driving at a crawl. You can easily cruise at 85 MPH (keep your eyes open!) and not have to fuss with slowing down.</p>

<p>After a quick fill-up in Florida City ($4.29 a gallon for premium...), I got to the Overseas Highway proper.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/overseas.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Blaue'" ></p>

<p>Now, if you want to talk about minor driving frustrations, the Overseas Highway is it. One lane, with a few passing zones, and a lot of people have a nasty habit of going below the speed limit. I'm not a speed demon, but I do like to keep up a good pace, ya know?</p>

<p>Anyways, things were progressing swimmingly. And it being Labor Day weekend, the whole stretch of the Keys was abuzz with activity. People were out boating, barbecuing, RVing, and just having a grand old time.</p>

<p>Around 7:30 PM or so, I started getting to what I consider the "fertile" photo-opportunity grounds of the Islamorada area of the Keys. I've shot there before, but this time around, the sky was extremely cooperative.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ohmy.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Oh my'" ></p>

<p>I saw the colors and cloud formations, and oddly enough I was very close to the site of my last great landscape piece at the Indian Key Channel. Now, unlike that fortuitous encounter in April, the parking area at Indian Key was packed with people, all in the long-weekend frame of mind. However, no one seemed to mind that I was setting up a bunch of photo equipment. Even a park ranger/Fish and Wildlife cop could care less, it seemed.</p>

<p>I had to work fast though. This was a random stop, yes, but I was here to shoot something. So, I set up, and got to it. The sun was rapidly descending. I know one of the rules of landscape and scenic photography is to get on-site hours beforehand, but sometimes you can't make that happen. So, you have to work with what you got.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4623.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Pylons - they go south'" ></p>

<p>There was no wind threatening to carry me off into the sea, so I had a nice stable platform with which to compose. Definitely more "colorful" than my last visit. I think I'm gonna make a little "project" out of the Indian Key channel at different times of the year.</p>

<p>Then, finally, I think I nailed it. I moved to the eastern side of "that bridge", and everything just sort of came together. The sun was below the horizon, but still, there was enough light to make the sky interesting, and the bridge became a jagged shadow across the frame. I saw it. One shot, one kill, as it were.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648.jpg" width="960" height="1440" title="'Fire away'" ></p>

<p>This one frame made the whole trip worth the effort. They say you know you have a good photo even before you process it, and right there, I knew it. Yellow Shark Channel is officially "my spot" now. FYI, the piece above will be for sale later today at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> site.</p>

<p>I didn't end the day there though. I figured I was already most of the way down the highway, so I proceeded on to Key West proper.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/doppler.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Doppler'" ></p>

<p>I made it Key West around 10 PM. The scene was in full swing, so I parked and decided to go walkabout, as it were, and take things in. I like Key West itself. It's a modern resort town, but the whole atmosphere encourages me to relax. I'm seriously thinking about figuring out how to maintain a residence down there. It's just a different way of life, really. You can just live your life at your own pace, and not worry about the petty bullshit which seemingly consumes Americans these days. No worrying about keeping up with the Joneses, as it were. And again, it's not a cradle of ignorance. The whole area is connected and part of the world, they just choose not to get caught up in the "rat race". Maybe in my old (not that old!) age I'm turning into a bum, I don't know.</p>

<p>I did grab a few street scene images, and also scoped out a few potential "Residence B" places. I'd actually be into a timeshare arrangement if the circumstances I have in mind worked out. Eventually I suppose I'll become a burnout and just live there. It'd be kinda nice. Me, a bungalow, and a boat. Though that bungalow would be pretty high-tech. I do love my toys. And I'd get one of those covers for the 210 so it's nice and safe from the seagulls and parrots.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/sloppy.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'sloppy'" ></p>

<p>There's just a certain allure to it, you know? You can just kind of be there, do what you need to in order to provide shelter and the essentials of life, and not get caught up in the petty antics of society. Like I said at the start of this article, everyone, whether they are tourists or locals, seems to be just fine with letting things be. They're not caught up in the rat race of wealth accumulation, and are just about enjoying life, and not rotting away flying a desk somewhere. Hey, if flying a desk is your thing, go for it, but I personally have other things in mind.</p>

<p>Maybe they're on to something down there. I'll be back more often, for sure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One of the things that makes it worthwhile.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/28/one-of-the-things-that-makes-it-worthwhile/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T21:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/28/one-of-the-things-that-makes-it-worthwhile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/thanx.png" width="258" height="280" title="'Thanks!'" ></p>

<p>Like I've stated before. I don't really do what I do with the end-goal of money in my sights. Having money is nice, and certainly has it's benefits in today's society, but I've found along the way that if your driving force is solely the acquisition of it, and the conspicuous consumption of it, it will corrupt. I've seen some really good people turn into <em>raging assholes</em> because of it. Or just plain old douchebags. Pardon my language.</p>

<p>I do what I do because I really love to do it. Photo work, video work, and the occasional web project keep me happy and put food on the table, and allow for a balance in my life to spend with friends and family. I don't expect any sort of accolade or reward.</p>

<p>But occasionally they do come in.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I tend to laugh off social networking as a diversion and, at the business level, a potential waste of resources. The most successful businesspeople in the world that I personally know and know of didn't build their empires by posting Facebook posts and ads, but they did it pretty much by turning out a good product or service. Yes, you gotta get the word out, but the business will come to you after that initial push.</p>

<p>But, anyways, I was talking about social networking, not business. Oh, by the way, I don't have much in the way of business acumen. I can tell you what camera or computer to buy, but beyond that, you're on your own.</p>

<p>Social networking, right. Yes, it's mostly a diversion and a front for large-scale data mining that would make the KGB envious, but sometimes it does have it's moments.</p>

<p>Like tonight. The person in the Facebook chat window above friend-requested me earlier this evening. Now, I didn't quite recognize this person off the bat, but we had enough mutual known friends for me to theorize that we had met at some point in the past. So, I figured I would "clear" this person and take it from there. If they proved to be a spammer or an unscrupulous promoter, it would take all of five seconds to screen them. Facebook does do things right on occasion.</p>

<p>About a few minutes later, the above message came through. I was out on a run and unfortunately the person was offline by the time I got back, so realtime communication wasn't possible. However, at the risk of being sappy, that did make my night. Again, I don't expect awards or accolades for my work, but when they come in completely unsolicited, it does make my day.</p>

<p>Thank you kind semi-stranger. You made my night.</p>

<p>OK, back to my scheduled ranting and raving.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruising South Florida.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/25/cruising-south-florida/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-25T11:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/25/cruising-south-florida</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p>Apparently there's a hurricane on the way. Or a tropical storm at the most. It's the usual subdued panic in South Florida. Yes, I'm aware that even a tropical storm can cause damage, and it's always better to be safe than sorry, but if the news media is to be believed, Armageddon is upon us.</p>

<p>It made for a very low-key Friday night, that's for sure. And today is shaping up to be more of the same.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Which is actually OK with me. I like to kick back and relax and do what I want rather than what I need to do. And one of those things is cruising around and shooting the deserted streets at night. In my mind, it's similar, in a way, to the scenics and landscapes I've been shooting lately. There's definitely an interesting juxtaposition with the works of humanity in the photo, but humanity itself isn't present.</p>

<p>And last night made that easy. No one was out, anywhere. I ostensibly drove north on the express lanes in I-95 to try out a new set of tires I put on the W210 earlier in the day. Bridgestone RE970s if anyone is curious. And in the rain at cruising speed, they stuck to the road like glue, even at "autobahn" speeds of 130 kph...around 81 mph or so.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage5.instagram.com/e1e54fdeee6a11e1829522000a1e88aa_7.jpg" title="'I-95 NB Express'" ></p>

<p>Of course I had my gear on me, since I intended on getting off the beaten path and shooting some deserted streets. From Downtown Fort Lauderdale to Washington Avenue on South Beach to Wynwood in Miami, it was a quiet Friday night. There were small bursts of activity here and there, but it was definitely a slow night. Which suited me just fine. I captured some excellent deserted street scenes.</p>

<p>One of the challenges, of course, was keeping my camera dry. I kind of forgot about that. However, I improvised with a plastic bag from my trunk and a musty old t-shirt to wipe away any condensation. And even though I had my trusty Manfrotto tripod with me, I handheld all of my images from the past evening. ISO 3200 and 6400. Don't fear the noise.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3454.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3462.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3473.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3476.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p>Driving Washington Avenue was fun. I drove from 5th Street to Lincoln, and marveled at all the shuttered nightclub spaces. It's really the subject of another rant, but it's amazing to see the huge seasonal turnover in nightclubs on the Beach. You think these guys would realize there's only three big players in town and only so many people to go around.</p>

<p>Anyways, it was a successful street scene shooting session. This wasn't commercially motivated, it was all "just for me". I think in the quest to stay solvent, a lot of photographers forget to go out and shoot what they want in addition to what they need to shoot. Though a fortunate few can shoot what they want and it fills their needs quite nicely. Regardless, shooting what you want is definitely recommended. It's relaxing if anything. Strip your kit down to what you need (again, don't fear the noise), get out there, and press the shutter button.</p>

<p>Be safe out there, South Florida.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fear of photography?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/21/a-fear-of-photography/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T12:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/21/a-fear-of-photography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ferrer-2724.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'I can seeeeee you!'" ></p>

<p>Local photojournalist and all-around good guy <a href="http://www.pixiq.com/contributors/248">Carlos Miller</a> got me thinking recently after the last <a href="http://www.pixiq.com/article/four-cop-cars-get-called-on-us">photo protest</a> he staged in front of the Miami Herald building.</p>

<p>A lot of people have a fear of photography. And I really can't figure out why. Sure, for some people I can see it. They're doing something they probably shouldn't be, and there's scads of photographic recording devices around them, which may or may not be recording their actions. I encounter it out in the clubs from time to time. I like to shoot wide, as you can see above, and I may inadvertently capture someone doing something (or someone, ba-dum-ching...) they shouldn't be.</p>

<p>It certainly isn't deliberate on my part though. Whatever transgressions you may be committing, that's your problem and not mine. I'm not out to ruin your life, since it appears that you're quite capable of doing that on your own. And no, I won't delete it. You are a noisy red smear at the bottom of the frame. And you probably shouldn't be cheating on your pretty wife in front of thousands of people and about that many cameras.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>But, that's just with crackheads in nightclubs, which, fortunately, form a small minority of our population.</p>

<p>The real head-scratcher is the people who get worked up over photography in public places. If you can see it from a public location, you can shoot it, it's that simple. I don't buy the national security bit or anything of that nature. If I take a photo of the refinery near Fort Lauderdale airport, the photo, other than a creative piece, tells me nothing. It's a collection of pipes. It won't aid a terrorist in planning to blow it up. And, if a terrorist wants to blow up the refinery, a photo isn't going to hinder or help him or her too much. It's not like in the movies where they can deduce where the 2-meter wide exhaust vent is from a cell phone photo.</p>

<p>Even more puzzling are the ordinary citizens who bring it upon themselves to get worked up over photos in public places. The photo protest I mentioned is a perfect example. In a nutshell, the ordinary citizen was a security guard, who took it upon himself to misquote the law, leading to the situation described in Carlos' blog entry. Now, a few words on that.</p>

<p>A security guard is an ordinary citizen. He doesn't have police powers. As a matter of fact, he's even more restricted from certain actions in the course of his job than an ordinary citizen is. The industry's slogan is "Observe and Report". That's about all they can do. Plus, from a pragmatic perspective, the pay scale isn't high enough to justify more than that. If I was working the front desk at the Herald, I'd either ignore it and get back to my Youtube viewing, or just kick it upstairs and let the bureaucrats in facilities deal with it. Yes, I'm being totally lazy and "not dedicated", but for $12/hr and no benefits, you're only going to get so much out of me. I'd rather spend my effort on something more meaningful, ya know?</p>

<p>Getting worked up about people shooting photos in public places is a complete waste of one's energy. There's so much more out there to expend effort on. Plus, if you think about it, the camera is ubiquitous now. If something is not recorded, that is an unusual set of circumstances indeed. In a society such as ours, there's at least one camera recording the scene at all times in any given public location. The ethics of such ubiquitous recording? Well, that's another debate entirely.</p>

<p>But such recording shouldn't be feared. If you don't want it recorded, don't put it in a public location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digging in the crates.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/digging-in-the-crates/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T17:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/digging-in-the-crates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://seenightlife.com/photos/15591/original_mixreunion-chilloutroom-mix.jpg" width="640" height="427" title="'The Mix'" ></p>

<p>I was doing a little digging today, and happened upon this little gem from when I was just getting started in my club shooting days.</p>

<p>Shot on film at South Beach's then-notorious afterhours, called The Mix, I took it for a <em>class project</em> at UM no less.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I shot this frame on a roll of store-bought Fujicolor Xperia 400 film for my Intro to Color Photography and Printmaking (ART 3xx?) at UM in late 1999. We had to develop our own film, and then print it out on a very disagreeable Kreonite RA4 paper processor.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.dphoto.us/classifieds/data/5/6103promate1-large.jpg" width="672" height="504" title="'Kreonite'" ></p>

<p>Often offline, or out of service entirely, the printer, similar to the above, was a hotly-contested piece of hardware over in the photo lab at UM. The irony being of course the amount of money it cost to go to UM, and we were saddled with a creaky processor.</p>

<p>I'm sure nowadays, time has improved the department somewhat (sidebar, if anyone from the UM photo department reads this, I'd love to do a guest spot!), and the learning path is almost entirely digital.</p>

<p>Which begs the question, in the photo world, is it possible to effectively learn the fundamentals when you can immediately see the results?</p>

<p>In the real world, there are plenty of shooters out there who make a living of it, and have never touched film or learned the formalities. They shoot via the Golden BB method, hoping that if they spray enough projectiles in the air, one will hit the target. Personally, it seems like a waste, even in the digital realm. Plus I feel you don't really learn if you depend on getting that one lucky photo in a session. I would much rather analyze the situation, set up accordingly, and push the shutter button once. I guess, in military terms, I'd be a sniper. One shot, one kill. I'm not in a hurry.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://seenightlife.com/photos/2008/original_dannyhowells001.jpg" width="640" height="427" title="'Danny Howells at Space'" ></p>

<p>Photos like the above weren't composed with the Golden BB method. You only had a finite amount of frames to work with, and none could be deleted and reused. Each shot had to count, for the most part.</p>

<p>It's a more efficient and elegant workflow anyhow. Each image counts, rather than just one throwaway amongst many.</p>

<p>The benefits of digital technology on photography have been enormous, with digital sensors objectively outperforming film in almost all aspects. However, along the way, certain techniques and refinements have been lost. The Golden BB method is sadly prevalent, unfortunately.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
