<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photo | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/photo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-08-13T23:47:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We can't make art from air.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T22:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage8.instagram.com/5ba9a3d8e32611e1a4431231381407ca_7.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Gear and girl'" ></p>

<p>I got into a discussion just now over on <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=6&t=19857">Talk Nightlife</a> with James, founder of <a href="http://soulofmiami.org/">Soul of Miami</a> about some of the trials and tribulations of the photographers and photo editors in the Olympics. I linked on over to a <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/photographers-blog/2012/08/10/click-edit-crop-or-drop/">blog post on Reuters</a> about the workflow of their on-site photo team. James' comment was that it was fascinating, but essentially <strong>"It really does not seem like they could possibly be getting paid enough for that."</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
Sadly, that is the truth. However, most of us whom are into the photo and video industries aren't into it for a big payday. Sure, income is nice, but at the end of the day, a photo career is a lot of hard work, and is often times frustrating, and the income rarely is there.</p>

<p>Sure, every guy and girl behind the lens has fantasies of one day making that 'big score', and not having to work again, but in most cases, that never happens. They might make what would be equivalent to mid-to-high five figures on average per year, but most of that money gets eaten up in taxes, reinvesting in the business, and general expenses associated with running said business. It's why if you see a photographer with a bunch of fancy non-photo-related toys, chances are that he or she probably has a second source of money, whether it's a "real job", another business that pays real money, or comes from money and happens to have a "hobby". And yes, there's always the slight chance that they scored and are living quite well off of their photo incomes.</p>

<p>Since the digital revolution, the intrinsic monetary value of photography has gone down enormously. A lot of shooters struggle to stay afloat and often have to make concessions and do other things to make ends meet. I'm a perfect example. I earn money from photography and video, but I have to tinker with websites and take on odd tasks related to the web to make ends meet. I'm very frugal but things still cost money. Also, it is a bit more costly to obtain basic health insurance on your own, than it is if you are part of a standard corporate entity.</p>

<p>It's actually why I've come around a bit on the whole government-provided healthcare issue actually. I'm for small government, but I do think one of the duties of the government is to take care of it's taxpayers. I think that if we're taken care of on a basic level by state health insurance, that would actually free us, as a people, up to take more risks in business and our personal lives. I know a lot of people with big ideas and dreams, who don't want to leave their corporate gigs, because said gigs provide the benefit of health insurance. And, obviously those corporate gigs demand a fair share of one's time and energy. But the healthcare rant is another post entirely. Hey, it's my blog, I don't have to necessarily adhere to standard editorial guidelines.</p>

<p>But anyways, society as a whole has come to devalue the work of photographers. Now, at no point has a photography career ever been a sure path to untold riches or success. Whether the workflow was analog or digital, it's always been the rare person who made their millions off of photography. And if they did make their millions off of it, chances are they are dead or pretty close to it, and the value of their work has increased by virtue of that. Suffice to say, the quickest way to increase the value of your photography is to die, preferably in a dramatic fashion.</p>

<p>All jokes aside though, the value, and the respect of the art has been diminished somewhat over the past decade. And it has been a two-pronged assault, from without, and from within. From without, it's been clients seeking the cheap way out. Even the most professional organizations expect to be able to pay only a pittance for work. A campaign that might cost thousands on the part of the photographer to execute, the client might only be willing to pay a few hundred dollars for. Of course everyone wants to spend as little as possible, but there is a point where the client base does need to remember that 'they get what they pay for'. You only pay a few hundred dollars, well, that is about all the work you will get. Someone recently offered me $50 and a bucket of booze to shoot a party. I blew them off, it wasn't even worth a response. Everyone knows I like to have a drink or two, but I won't work for that sort of thing. I have bills to pay. And $50 would not cover my own nightly expenses, as the gig was on South Beach (no Car2Go), and of course my time in post and editing.
If you want to pay me $50, I'd expect a chauffeured ride to and from the venue, and I'll probably take three photos, steal your girlfriend, and not bother delivering the edit (1 photo) until sometime in 2025.</p>

<p>And that's just the problem from without. The problem from within is almost as bad. The digital revolution has put quality imaging tools into the hands of all. For $400 or less (say, a used Drebel kit), one can obtain a quality digital SLR with a basic lens. Under decent lighting conditions, this kit can objectively shoot great images, even in the hands of an amateur. And said images could conceivably be used for commercial purposes with the right editing and post production. So, now, businesses can hire "some guy they know", or "do it in-house" (though there's nothing wrong with an staff shooter in some instances, as long as rights and releases are fair), and attempt to save a buck or two, and have "some guy they know" fix any of the problems later, or leave the fixing to some beleaguered designer at a graphic design firm somewhere. Sidebar: graphic designers hate that.</p>

<p>When confronted, the businesses and the shooters themselves will often plead ignorance, or claim that "this is the way things are now, deal with it".
Understandably, the dynamics of the digital economy have changed things, but photographers and other visual professionals do need to have an income to survive and keep providing these services to clients. If all photography was cheap and/or free, eventually there would be no photographers to generate the images clients require and need. And computer rendering of realistic scenes is far more expensive (to do right) than booking the services of a photographer, so don't try to get me there!</p>

<p>What's even worse is the lack of understanding of licensing and rights, as well. Very few businesses understand this. They treat all photographic work for them as work-for-hire, with unlimited use. To them, once the photo is taken, it is theirs. It doesn't work that way. Licensing and sale is one of the only ways a photographer can stand a chance of making a reasonable living nowadays, especially in the situations I've described above. And very few photographers understand it as well as they should. It took me awhile to get a handle on it, but once one understands the ins and outs of it, it's easy to figure out.
In this case, Google is your friend. Search for "editorial photography rate guidelines" and go from there. I'm not being lazy, there is just a huge amount of information on pricing your work accordingly. FYI, it's why a decent-sized print of mine will run you a few hundred dollars or more at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> page.</p>

<p>Again, we're in this because we love to do it, not because we're seeking a route to glorious riches and untold glory. All anyone behind the lens asks for is just compensation to cover the costs of doing business, and enjoy life while we're at it. I don't think there's many photographers out there whom are greedy and driven by dollar signs. Even we like to put the camera down sometimes and take a little vacation somewhere. With a smaller camera of course.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say, that's a nice camera...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/gearhead.jpg" width="960" height="203" title="'Go Pro on W210'" ></p>

<p>One of the most common questions that anyone in the photo or video industry gets asked, is, "<em>What sort of gear do you use?</em>"</p>

<p>Well, it's a reasonable question. The general public and professionals alike like to know that sort of thing, and it's a good conversation starter with anyone in the visual arts.</p>

<p>Me? What do I use?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My primary rig is a Canon 5D MK II full-frame DSLR for both still and video applications. Lenswise I have a 16-35 2.8 L, a 50 1.2 L, and a 70-200 2.8 L, all by Canon. And on the lighting end, a 580 EX flashgun (it goes pop and lights up things) and an ST-E2 wireless controller for the flash (so I can change the angle of light, etc...). And that's it, not counting a backup body. And of course some Macs for editing and heavy lifting.</p>

<p>It's a small assortment of gear, by no means a huge arsenal. Plus, when are in a more freeform situation such as an event or nightclub shoot, working with what you have on hand in a small satchel makes it far more interesting. This ethos is actually more and more common amongst professional photographers and videographers. Lenses and camera bodies aren't cheap, and it doesn't make sense to carry gear you don't use that often. So, a lot of pros on a budget and a lot who aren't, they simply rent.</p>

<p>The rise of photo gear rental house over the past decade has been phenomenal. All major cities have photo and video gear rental houses, such as <a href="http://aperturepro.com/"><strong>Aperture</strong></a> here in Miami, and online outlets such as <a href="http://lensrentals.com/"><strong>Lensrentals.com</strong></a> can ship just about any type of lens, camera body, lighting instrument, or accessory to your location overnight, and the rental rates are fiercely competitive. You can rent a $10,000 lens for a few hundred dollars a week. It's perfect for the one gig that requires it, or just plain old experimentation. I occasionally rent specialized lenses outside of my work just for experimentation. Sometimes I find a commercial use for it and end up purchasing it, as I did with the 50 1.2 L. I rented it repeatedly, and I ended up purchasing it as part of my permanent arsenal. It's also obviously a great way to audition gear you intend to buy.</p>

<p>And in the end, especially in these days when it's harder and harder for photographers and video pros to get a reasonable paycheck, every dollar saved counts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A year back in Miami.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/a-year-back-in-miami/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T14:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/a-year-back-in-miami</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/skyline-7023_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Downtown Miami'" ></p>

<p><b>Support this site! Buy a print of the Miami Skyline pictured above over at my <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/downtown-miami-2012-dan-vidal.html">FAA Gallery</a>.</b></p>

<p>It's been a year since I've gotten back to Miami. I beat to death the <a href="http://dvdigital.tumblr.com/post/9305311687/miami-versus-vegas-since-ive-been-back-people">differences between Miami and Vegas</a>
over on my old Tumblr, so I won't get into it here all over again.</p>

<p>In a nutshell though, absence made the heart grow fonder, and despite the faults of Miami, I'm still glad I came back.</p>

<p>A lot of people rain on Miami's parade at any opportunity. The "lack of culture" and the lack of "real" opportunities outside of the world of
hospitality and tourism usually factor into most people's discussions about the downsides of living in this area.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>However, if you look closer, Miami is a very young city. Founded in 1896, it is the oldest municipality in South Florida. The area was settled prior to that, but no real development occurred until then. So, as it were, the city, and the area in general, have a scant 150 years of history to support it. Cultural meccas like Boston and New York have centuries of cultural development. Nonetheless, even with the relative age of our society here, certain things considered "cultural" have definitely taken hold. Gatherings and events like Art Walk and of course the almighty Art Basel Miami exemplify this. Along with our crop of homegrown musical talent, which spans way beyond the stereotypical "Latin" sound. Groups like ArtOfficial and Spam All-Stars are in the global music scene representing the 305, as it were.</p>

<p>Now, on the subject of opportunity. A lot of people bemoan the lack of "real" companies having branches or operations here. The fact is, they do. Most major corporations, ranging from heavyweights like Xerox and Canon, to more specialized outfits like Diageo (liquor) have their Latin American headquarters here. Along the same lines, the major South American banks are headquartered here for reasons of safety and stability, and proximity to their home countries. However, it's the lack of "corporatism" in where Miami can shine. A city like Miami is ripe for the spirit of self-employment and entrepreneurship. Even educated people who choose to locate here, often start their own business in any number of fields, including "Miami typical" ones like hospitality, entertainment, the arts, and music, or even unexpected fields like software development and engineering. I personally know several local talented software developers who work from home or small office spaces on projects that are headquartered around the globe.</p>

<p>It's actually people like these who represent the future of doing things. I see cities like Miami becoming immensely popular as a living location as self-employment and telecommuting become more and more accepted and popular. And why not? Most common tasks in any business environment don't require much more than a computer with an internet connection, with the office space being a mere formality and comforter for employers. Of course, for such things to take hold, a sea change in our attitudes towards work and employment need to happen. I'll leave that for another rant entirely.</p>

<p>However, it's this unconventional environment which drew me here, and drew me back home after my absence. The travel opportunities were fun, but there's definitely no place like home.</p>

<p>Besides, being unconventional is fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond nightlife...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/beyond-nightlife-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/beyond-nightlife-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<p>I venture outside of the world of nightlife in my shooting when possible. While challenging as it is to shoot in that sort of environment "my way", even more of a challenge is to take something rather common, the landscape photograph, and put my own spin on it.</p>

<p>What I like to find is a mix of the works of humans with the works of nature. So, on a drive to Key West one evening, I had it in my mind to try to capture a sunset off of one of the islands on the way down to Key West.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>One of the frustrations of that, is that it isn't always possible to get that ideal angle, simply due to the traffic situation on the way down. Unless you plan way in advance (which I should have), you have to deal with the vagaries of only having one main road the entire way. Thus you can find yourself stuck behind some slow-movers, just as that magic hour hits.</p>

<p>I was gauging an ideal destination based on an earlier trip I had made a few weeks prior. I didn't make it all the way down to Key West, but I had dropped a few pins on my iPhone's map utility, to mark a few places. The one I had in mind was close, but traffic wasn't cooperating. So, when the ideal time hit, I took a gamble and pulled over next to this bridge.</p>

<p>The wind was whipping about like crazy, to the point where I had to fight to stabilize both myself and my camera, despite a heavy-duty Manfrotto tripod. Eventually, I settled into the scene, and ended up composing the above. Much like an expert sniper, I knew I "had it" even before the RAW data worked it's way through my MK II's processors and appeared on the screen. Initially a little underexposed to preserve the sky detail (you can always adjust your exposure upwards later, it's much harder to adjust downwards and bring out detail, even in RAW), I could still see the end result in my head, which is represented above.</p>

<p>While I'm fairly new to landscape photography, I can definitely appreciate the skill it takes to get the image, both from a technical and a logistical perspective. Preparation helps, but sometimes you just have to be ready for the moment to hit.</p>

<p>I'll be posting more images in this theme as time goes on, both from my back catalog, and new works as I produce them.</p>

<p>And now a word from our sponsor...me.</p>

<p><i>Enjoy 'Islamorada Crossing'? Why not purchase a quality printed copy of it for yourself or someone special? Point your browsers over to my <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/islamorada-crossing-dan-vidal.html">print provider (click/tap!)</a> and get your copy today. Available in a whole range of sizes and finishes. Use discount code 'GZTFYJ' to get 20 percent off your final order price. I definitely appreciate the business!</i></p>

<p>Yes, even I have to eat on occasion.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some words on my style]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/some-words-on-my-style/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T15:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/some-words-on-my-style</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tort-9921.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn Hartlein on the box at Space'" ></p>

<p>A lot of people ask me why I shoot like I do, when it comes to nightlife and concerts. Well, there's many reasons.</p>


<p>Nowadays, with the ubiquity of the 'nightlife photographer', or 'the guy with the blog' (yes, I'm well aware that I'm writing this on a blog platform), one has to strive to differentiate themselves in order to be unique, stand out, and get work. Even if your end goal isn't necessarily financially-oriented (and it shouldn't be, you aren't going to get rich shooting concerts and clubs, it's something you have to like to do), your job or vision is easier to pull off if you can develop a coherent style to call your own.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I've been working in clubs for about fifteen years now. I started by helping my friend John, now the owner of <a href="http://alchemyavcs.com/">Alchemy Audio Visual Systems</a> with lugging around his nascent rig of EAW speaker cabinets and Crown amplifiers, and doing double duty as his light tech. We provided reinforcement for local punk bands and some DJ shows as well. I was also majoring in motion picture production and fine art photography at the <a href="http://miami.edu/">University of Miami</a>, and working for their IT department as well.</p>

<p>Anyways, I managed to work my nighttime activities into legitimate coursework for my photography classes. I would shoot some of the bands and our lighting setups, when time permitted. Early on, one of the biggest "rules" of most venues, if they were cool with me shooting at all, was that flash photography was frowned upon or genuinely prohibited around the performers of the evening. Totally understandable, for two reasons. First off, if you are DJing or playing an instrument, a flash blowing off in your field of vision can be distracting, or even dangerous, if you are the sort of performer who tends to be very dynamic. Also, and this forms the basis of my style, the performers are usually well-lit, or can be at request.</p>

<p>Basically, there's a lot of light around if you know how to use it. Nightclubs and concert halls are generally regarded as being dark and dingy, but there is a lot of light within them. LED screens, flat panel displays, swirling intelligent lights, the glow from POS terminals, even candlelight. It can all be used to pull off an effective photo, while not having to resort to using flash photography. Now, there is nothing inherently wrong with flash photography. Used properly, it can provide a wonderful balance to a scene. Used improperly, the results can be substandard, and the act of taking the photo itself can be distracting. One of the keys to successful concert and nightclub photography in my mind is to blend in with the scenery. People tend to be themselves if they think you are one of the crowd, and not some guy with an SLR looking for attention, free entry, and cheap laughs. We all know that guy, he's not nice.</p>

<p>Of course, working with the light that is there presents some challenges. Invariably you are operating at a very shallow depth-of-field, a slow shutter speed, a high ISO, or all three. I won't get into it in this post, but all three can be compensated for, especially high ISO. High ISO is the easiest to compensate for, actually. Flat out accept the noise. It's there, use it and move on. ISO 6400 on a modern DSLR is actually more usable than ISO 1600 on a roll of Fujicolor from the 1990s, even without noise reduction.</p>

<p>So basically, my style is the result of the environment I generally shoot in, and my ethos of blending in with the crowd rather than being the focus of it.
<img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tort-9712.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Work it.'" ></p>

<p>Use the light that's there, you might surprise yourself.</p>

<p>(Oh, and this is only a test - I'll add photos in a bit)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
