<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photo | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/photo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-11T15:02:07-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram Embedding.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11/instagram-embedding/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T11:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11/instagram-embedding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/09/11//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/PbIV-nAgDn/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/9255154afbd411e1b2f422000a1e9a50_7.jpg' alt='Not quite a throwback but remember this @jacquejaxx ?' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/earlybird'>Earlybird</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835243225,-80.182678222'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835243225,-80.182678222&markers=25.835243225,-80.182678222&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='25.835243225,-80.182678222' /></a></p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='277852496720953575_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>Works in a way. I have to retrieve the media_id for each Instagram photo. It's not implicit in the URL. Hi Jacque.</p>

<p>Hopefully this works.</p>

<p>Access token needed.</p>

<p>Tokens.</p>

<p>OK.</p>

<p>Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wynwood Artwalk Too Hot To Handle?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T23:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/artwalk.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Artwalk Wynwood Artwalk Miami'" ></p>

<p>Though I guess I could be considered part of the Miami art community, I almost never go to Artwalk in Wynwood. I'm usually busy Saturday nights, or I consider my rare downtime more valuable than bouncing from gallery to gallery, most of which probably wouldn't exhibit anything I do. Photography is sort of underrepresented at Artwalk, but that's for another rant.</p>

<p>So anyways, the rare times I go to it are last-minute call-ups like I did earlier tonight.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I got a text from my good friend <strong>Emi Guerra</strong>, he wanted to go out and cruise Artwalk and meet some of the Miami art community to tell them about his forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>, the big music and art festival taking place on December 8th and 9th during Art Basel. The big announcement of the lineup is Monday, even though it has been leaked. So I won't post it here since you can find it <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/">elsewhere.</a>.</p>

<p>But anyways, he wanted to go out and see the artists and art people. Makes sense if you are throwing an art-oriented festival. And, since I'm kinda in touch with these people (am I?) he invited me along.</p>

<p>So, I jumped into the 210 and zipped on down Biscayne to Wynwood.</p>

<p>Once I got to the area, what a bloody mission. Traffic was at a gridlocked standstill, and there were throngs of people out and about, to the point where Northwest 2nd Avenue was a pedestrian thoroughfare. I was supposed to meet Emi and his UR1 team at Wynwood Walls, and I ended up having to park about seven blocks away. I'm a healthy boy now so it's no big deal, but it's the principle. And I will not valet. The 210 isn't an SLS or an E 63, but it's my baby and no one except me and the crew at <a href="http://masterclassauto.com/">Masterclass Auto</a> touches the steering wheel.</p>

<p>Some have called for the major streets of Wynwood to be closed off to automotive traffic during Artwalk. 100 percent, yes. Please. Do this. Commissioner Sarnoff, it's your district (for now), make it happen. The cops have their hands full pushing vehicular and pedestrian traffic around, and it's a complete cluster down there, and it actually hampers the enjoyment of Artwalk.</p>

<p>So yes, Artwalk has truly exploded into a Miami social phenomenon. We officially have an art scene here as far as I'm concerned. Go us.</p>

<p>However, I finally did get situated, and met Emi, along with UR1's Jackie Richie, Emi's assistant Andrea, Alex Martinez of <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Deepsleep</a>, and a few other scene people I know at Wynwood Walls, which was "at capacty" and had this weird dining area with a velvet rope and such set up.</p>

<p>They gotta update the artwork there. It's been the same since I last went to Artwalk (oddly enough with Emi's brother, Eddy) over two years ago. I'll paint a wall. It won't be anything "arty", but it will be something from my mind. I'll mention it here even.</p>

<p>As I mentioned earlier, everyone was out in force. Now, was everyone into the art? Hardly. Most people "Artwalking" couldn't tell you if that was a piece by Nagelbett or Britto. They are out for the social experience. Emi phrased it best when he said, "They are out for something to do, and it's cheap to go to Artwalk. Shit is expensive these days..."</p>

<p>He hit the nail on the head. Shit is expensive these days. Dinner for two will run you $100 or more. A night out at a club, even Space, will run you $100 per person (drinks, cover, and so on) or more if you VIP it. Having fun costs money!</p>

<p>But not at Artwalk. The galleries often have cash bars and/or free (albeit low-quality) booze on hand. They usually arrange a sponsorship or something. And the food trucks are out in force, and the food is cheap, though I wouldn't necessarily trust it. Yeah, the modern food trucks have all the amenities, but it's still a food truck, ya know? We called 'em the "roach coaches" back in Jersey. Note to food truck owners, I'm not saying that your food truck has roaches. If you're that concerned about what I said, you probably have something to hide. Be confident in your product and people talking shit, like me, won't affect your business. Let freedom ring.</p>

<p>But yes, anyways, people are out for Artwalk because it's cheap, interesting, and there's a good social dynamic. And the galleries and artists put up with it since it will get their works exposed to the five percent of the people who actually know their art and are in a position to do something about it.</p>

<p>And yes, please block off the streets. Artwalk is now truly a "phenomenon" and it needs to be handled properly. Our art scene is finally getting some worldwide respect, and it'd be a shame if logistical squabbles killed off a major component of it.</p>

<p>Maybe I should run for the City Commission and make Artwalk one of my campaign platforms...</p>

<p>Dan Vidal For District 2 Commissioner!</p>

<p>Sidebar: Yes, I'm aware the issues mentioned here are old. But these first few articles on my blog are kind of for SEO purposes, as well as stuff that is on my mind, regardless of when it happened. It's my blog, after all.</p>

<p>Sidebar 2: Yes, this devolved into a rant. In a nutshell, I did have fun at Artwalk. The food truck area is a great concept. Get 'em all in one place. Also, good seeing the <a href="http://car2go.com/">Miami Car2Go</a> people out...thanks for the T-shirt guys.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the premise of exclusivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/on-the-premise-of-exclusivity/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T19:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/on-the-premise-of-exclusivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ex.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'MK II overlooking Space'" ></p>

<p>Over the years, a lot of people have been under the mistaken assumption that I've been the "exclusive" photographer for venues and events I've worked with.</p>

<p>I don't enforce or expect exclusivity, and here's why...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>At the root of it all, I'm only one person. I can only be in so many places within a venue at once, especially if it's a large scale venue such as Space. I'll be upstairs on the Terrace, but the Loft might be uncovered, or the Ballroom. There isn't money in the budget to clone me.</p>

<p>Also, the fact that photographers prior to me didn't enforce exclusivity with their venue clients was an enormous boost to me being able to do what I do today. If they hadn't left that door open, I might not have been as far along as I am today. However, back when I got started, the position/gig of "club photographer" was a rare one indeed. More on that in a minute.</p>

<p>And, if I were a large-scale venue manager/owner, and I had it in the budget, I would definitely want multiple photographic perspectives on what was going on that evening. Each and every person who picks up a camera has their own thoughts and ideas on how an image should come out, and it is a definite advertising boon to have those multiple perspectives represented. And in the case of email-harvesting sites posing as photo sites, the venue gets multiple sources of data. I don't necessarily approve of the tactic, but it is what it is, and if I were a venue owner or manager, I would avail myself of a few of those sites.</p>

<p>Finally, to be honest, enforcing exclusivity and being "the guy" is a real <em>pain</em>. You're expected to be everywhere at once, cover the event exactly in the style the client wants, which may not be your style, and the task of club photographer rapidly turns from a fun profession to a "job", i.e. something you have to do to make money. And, frankly, I can think of many healthier activities that aren't fun to do at all, that would earn me the same money or more that I do documenting the nightclub scene. I do it primarily because I love to do it, and the financial benefits are just the icing on the cake. You don't see people clamoring to spend thousands of dollars on camera equipment just to take it into a smoke-filled room with loud music and sloppy drunk people because it's a job.</p>

<p>However, the situation today could be regarded as a little different. Since I got started, the position of club photographer has gone from a rare job description, to one of almost ubiquity. Often, the last thing a party would consider is booking a photographer to document an event. It was usually a "6 PM on the night of the event" request, if they thought about it at all. Of course the internet changed that.</p>

<p>Now, if you throw a party at a club, it's expected that you will have at least one or two guys on hand to document the event. However, some venues tend to go a little overboard, thinking any exposure is good, and let any guy with an SLR and an excuse into the venue. With the modern set of circumstances in mind, I'd at least require that the shooter have a full-fledged website (and not just a Facebook page or Flickr gallery) with which their images were to be posted. And, I'd probably cap the amount of shooters within a venue to a certain amount to avoid "shooting gallery" syndrome where there is, in fact, ten or more shooters in a venue. So, exclusivity on one person, not so much, but not overkill like some places are now. Especially if you add in everyone with their iPhones blazing away. But that's for another rant.</p>

<p>If you're in the club shooting world, keep shooting. Don't expect or enforce exclusivity though, it's not practical and definitely not in the spirit of things. There's enough subject matter for all (well, most) of us.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The musical ecosystem.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/the-musical-ecosystem/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T02:24:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/the-musical-ecosystem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jive-4963.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Guy yelling at Adam'" ></p>

<p>I like shooting live concerts. There's more than one guy or girl on stage, and there's a lot of activity to document, from the vocalist to the instrumentalists, there's always someone moving about and in action. Plus, the lighting can't be argued with since the whole point of them being lit is to be seen. I actually like that almost every Tuesday I get to shoot Jive at Blue Martini Brickell.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It's a singing contest of sorts, but it brings out some real talent. Whether they are there for fun or hoping for a big break, I don't know, but it's a fun event to shoot. The band, Higher Ground, is on point with their covers, so it gives the contestants a real thrill to have a genuine live band behind them. And the dynamics of shooting it are a welcome change from my usual club shooting.</p>

<p>Not that I mind the DJ-oriented shooting. It's interesting, still after all these years, even with the proliferation of the DJ-as-rockstar during this current dance music bubble. Though some of these guys, it's gone to their heads.</p>

<p>When I first started this, over a decade ago, DJs kind of knew where they fit in within the musical ecosystem. They were curators and purveyors of music. Even if they produced their own tracks, they were still sought after and regarded first and foremost, as musical librarians of a sort. You went to a specific DJ's club night to hear new music since you trusted their musical taste was in line with yours. The end result was that you hopefully would go out to the record store the next day and purchase the tracks you heard. Even when the internet flipped the record store idea on it's face, the hope was you'd go to your online record shop and do the same.</p>

<p>Then came the rockstar phenomenon. DJs demanded more and more salaries, for correspondingly less work. Even disregarding automation, most DJs are content to go from A to B and back again and ask for a $50,000 paycheck. I can remember when DJs would get paid a tenth of that, and do far more work behind the decks, even when the change from vinyl to CDs happened. And most of all, DJs knew where they fit in the scheme of things. They knew their job was to provide the soundtrack for a night out, not be the sole focus of a night out. They helped maintain the dynamic of providing great music to a party. Now, unfortunately, we're in a sort of twilight zone where DJs get stage setups that rival those of genuine musicians, all to frame them pressing some keys on a Macbook. Now, some of the kids might argue that they're "really doing something" up there, but the sad fact is, it's all just sequencing and basic mixing. Very few DJs are actually doing anything innovative with the tools at hand. Though, those that are, ironically enough, are working the club scene and not about being the glory hogs of the world. You have veterans like Carl Cox who still throw down ten hour sets, working three or four inputs at once, and creating new compositions on the fly. And you have one of my favorites, the legendary Pete Tong, who generally eschews the festival scene, preferring to focus on his BBC show, and bringing the newest records and all the classics to the clubs. He knows he's there to drive the dancefloor and show the party people a good time. One of the best sets I've heard recently was his WMC session at Space. He'll actually be on the very same Terrace this coming weekend. I personally can't wait, and I'm at the point know where I'm pretty jaded and it takes a lot to get me excited with regards to DJs.</p>

<p>Maybe that's why I get a kick out of a little party like Jive. It's a bunch of people having a good time and not taking everything so seriously. The cash prize ($200) isn't going to solve world hunger or put a kid through college, so the people participating are usually just up there to have a good time. I think in the end if the rockstar DJs in the world remember that's all people really want, we can get back to some sort of rationality in the dance club scene. It's ironic, the live music scene in general (not just little singing contests in Brickell!) from what I can see is actually getting more down to earth, whereas DJs are getting more and more egotistical in their demands. Even Axl Rose in his prime would be envious of some of these guys' riders. But, from where I sit, I see it as a bubble. I'm confident the DJ world will get back to reality soon.</p>

<p>Oh and a disclaimer, I do sincerely appreciate what some DJs do on and off the decks. Those guys usually end up in my iPhone playlist. I'll post it up someday. I think I do have an audio player plugin. Actually yeah I do. Note to self, start posting some sets of genuinely good DJs. But if any of you dear readers want a good place to start, just hunt out the sets of (in no particular order): Pete Tong, Victor Calderone, Roger Sanchez, The Martinez Brothers, Dennis Ferrer, Danny Tenaglia, Loco Dice, Marco Carola, Oscar G, Patrick M, Mark M (Miami), Trent Cantrelle, the Cocodrills, Louie Vega, Frankie Knuckles, and Eric Prydz to name a few.</p>

<p>I'll try and kick up a favorite mix of mine in the next few days. I gotta see how it will affect my S3 bill. And also if there's anything copyright-related I might have to worry about.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keys Standard Time.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/03/keys-standard-time/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T13:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/03/keys-standard-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648_blog.jpg" width="960" height="308" title="'Yellow Shark Channel'" ></p>

<p>I've always liked going down to the Keys, especially the Lower Keys and Key West.</p>

<p>It is one of the few places I've been to in the US where things are truly running at a different pace. No one's concerned about their latest Facebook status, what Justin Bieber said on Twitter, or what their Klout score (a rigged and meaningless metric by the way) is.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It's removed from the mainland as it were, by geography, but it's not a pig-ignorant backwater of the Ozarks populated by people who are poised to vote for Romney this coming November. You can go to Key West, relax, but not feel like you are in a premillenial timewarp. They are connected down there, they just choose not to make a big deal of it. That's actually the way I think they feel down there, "don't make a big deal of it".</p>

<p>After a fairly interesting morning of shooting photos of the Labor Day Weekend event at Space, featuring DJs AN21, Robert Dietz (a true master of his craft by the way), and Reboot (aka Frank...I always call DJs by their real names), I decided to call it off around 8 AM, get some rest, and actually go out and <em>produce</em> something photographically that day. I hadn't generated much other than nightlife-related material over the preceding few weeks, so I figured I should get to it and find an interesting slice of land to document.</p>

<p>So, I figured why not head south? I've had good photo experiences there before, and I've always made mental notes on stopping points on the way down. So around 4 PM after some much-needed rest, I jumped in the 210 and headed to the Turnpike southbound.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tipover.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Tip Over'" ></p>

<p>I like driving the Homestead Extension to the Florida Turnpike. It's fairly new so the pavement hasn't succumbed to the elements as of yet, and it's never so congested that you are reduced to driving at a crawl. You can easily cruise at 85 MPH (keep your eyes open!) and not have to fuss with slowing down.</p>

<p>After a quick fill-up in Florida City ($4.29 a gallon for premium...), I got to the Overseas Highway proper.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/overseas.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Blaue'" ></p>

<p>Now, if you want to talk about minor driving frustrations, the Overseas Highway is it. One lane, with a few passing zones, and a lot of people have a nasty habit of going below the speed limit. I'm not a speed demon, but I do like to keep up a good pace, ya know?</p>

<p>Anyways, things were progressing swimmingly. And it being Labor Day weekend, the whole stretch of the Keys was abuzz with activity. People were out boating, barbecuing, RVing, and just having a grand old time.</p>

<p>Around 7:30 PM or so, I started getting to what I consider the "fertile" photo-opportunity grounds of the Islamorada area of the Keys. I've shot there before, but this time around, the sky was extremely cooperative.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ohmy.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Oh my'" ></p>

<p>I saw the colors and cloud formations, and oddly enough I was very close to the site of my last great landscape piece at the Indian Key Channel. Now, unlike that fortuitous encounter in April, the parking area at Indian Key was packed with people, all in the long-weekend frame of mind. However, no one seemed to mind that I was setting up a bunch of photo equipment. Even a park ranger/Fish and Wildlife cop could care less, it seemed.</p>

<p>I had to work fast though. This was a random stop, yes, but I was here to shoot something. So, I set up, and got to it. The sun was rapidly descending. I know one of the rules of landscape and scenic photography is to get on-site hours beforehand, but sometimes you can't make that happen. So, you have to work with what you got.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4623.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Pylons - they go south'" ></p>

<p>There was no wind threatening to carry me off into the sea, so I had a nice stable platform with which to compose. Definitely more "colorful" than my last visit. I think I'm gonna make a little "project" out of the Indian Key channel at different times of the year.</p>

<p>Then, finally, I think I nailed it. I moved to the eastern side of "that bridge", and everything just sort of came together. The sun was below the horizon, but still, there was enough light to make the sky interesting, and the bridge became a jagged shadow across the frame. I saw it. One shot, one kill, as it were.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648.jpg" width="960" height="1440" title="'Fire away'" ></p>

<p>This one frame made the whole trip worth the effort. They say you know you have a good photo even before you process it, and right there, I knew it. Yellow Shark Channel is officially "my spot" now. FYI, the piece above will be for sale later today at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> site.</p>

<p>I didn't end the day there though. I figured I was already most of the way down the highway, so I proceeded on to Key West proper.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/doppler.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Doppler'" ></p>

<p>I made it Key West around 10 PM. The scene was in full swing, so I parked and decided to go walkabout, as it were, and take things in. I like Key West itself. It's a modern resort town, but the whole atmosphere encourages me to relax. I'm seriously thinking about figuring out how to maintain a residence down there. It's just a different way of life, really. You can just live your life at your own pace, and not worry about the petty bullshit which seemingly consumes Americans these days. No worrying about keeping up with the Joneses, as it were. And again, it's not a cradle of ignorance. The whole area is connected and part of the world, they just choose not to get caught up in the "rat race". Maybe in my old (not that old!) age I'm turning into a bum, I don't know.</p>

<p>I did grab a few street scene images, and also scoped out a few potential "Residence B" places. I'd actually be into a timeshare arrangement if the circumstances I have in mind worked out. Eventually I suppose I'll become a burnout and just live there. It'd be kinda nice. Me, a bungalow, and a boat. Though that bungalow would be pretty high-tech. I do love my toys. And I'd get one of those covers for the 210 so it's nice and safe from the seagulls and parrots.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/sloppy.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'sloppy'" ></p>

<p>There's just a certain allure to it, you know? You can just kind of be there, do what you need to in order to provide shelter and the essentials of life, and not get caught up in the petty antics of society. Like I said at the start of this article, everyone, whether they are tourists or locals, seems to be just fine with letting things be. They're not caught up in the rat race of wealth accumulation, and are just about enjoying life, and not rotting away flying a desk somewhere. Hey, if flying a desk is your thing, go for it, but I personally have other things in mind.</p>

<p>Maybe they're on to something down there. I'll be back more often, for sure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
