<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photo | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/photo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-10-29T14:47:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A classic sunset...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/23/a-classic-sunset-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T00:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/23/a-classic-sunset-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/t-2535.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Perty'" ></p>

<p>You definitely can't argue with the sunsets on the Outer Banks of North Carolina.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Sure, sunset photos are contrived and "have been done", but sometimes, regardless of your skill level, every photographer needs to shoot a few "typical" images. If anything, for those of us who take ourselves too seriously, you can justify it as a "test" or "calibration" or "comparison".</p>

<p>Besides, it's rather nice-looking.</p>

<p>I think in terms of "a place to go to do nothing", Emerald Isle has Key West beat. There is absolutely nothing going on but the weather. No clubs, no bars, just some pretty pricey real estate and people just kicking back. You have to bring your own fun, essentially. Which was kind of nice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting weddings...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/22/shooting-weddings-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T01:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/22/shooting-weddings-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/talerick_preview.jpg" width="960" height="610" title="'FU-T'" ></p>

<p>A huge congratulations to my friends and neighbors Talmage and Erick on their wedding this past weekend. We all went up to Emerald Isle, NC for the ceremony. It was pretty spectacular.</p>

<p>I don't explicitly advertise myself as a wedding photographer. While I know it can be lucrative, I've also heard a lot of horror stories from other shooters about the stress involved, and not just from bridezillas either...</p>

<p>But I don't turn down weddings that come my way...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Typically, a wedding will come my way about once a year. It's always through a friend or acquaintance. And, for the most part, they know how I shoot when they hire me. They know that I'm definitely not a wedding photography specialist.</p>

<p>The wedding I shot this past weekend with Tal and Erick was a great example. I've known Tal since about 2004 through the club scene and her being a poster on TNL, and Erick for a little bit longer than that. They both knew my specialties in terms of photography. But, they also wanted a distinct look and feel for their photos, and also the obvious of preferring to hire a friend rather than someone they didn't know.</p>

<p>For me, it was an opportunity to change things up a bit in terms of my photo work, and an excuse to rent some quality equipment and maybe try some new concepts.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/19//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q_FrW8ggJe/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage6.s3.amazonaws.com/d13ac15c1a5511e29c6822000a1f9688_7.jpg' alt='Tele for @talmagelisabeth wedding.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=34.682976,-76.912536'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=34.682976,-76.912536&markers=34.682976,-76.912536&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Best House At The Biotch' /></a><br/>Taken at Best House At The Biotch</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='305988269492011614_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>My loadout for the wedding started as a grandiose idea in my head. Since my "gift" to them was essentially my work (only thing I asked for was transport and lodging), I wanted to make it shine. However, since I'm a one-man show here, eventually less was more. My final kit was:</p>

<ul>
<li>5D MK II - primary body</li>
<li>50D - backup body</li>
<li>580 EX Speedlite</li>
<li>580 EX II Speedlite from <a href="http://lensrentals.com/">Lens Rentals</a>.</li>
<li>16-35mm 2.8 L zoom lens</li>
<li>50mm 1.2 L prime lens</li>
<li>70-200 2.8 II L zoom lens</li>
<li>2 Fong Lightspheres from <a href="http://lensrentals.com/">Lens Rentals</a></li>
<li>ST-E2 Speedlite transmitter</li>
<li>2 32 GB CF cards</li>
<li>Joby Gorillapod</li>
<li>The Podbook Air</li>
<li>A GoPro Hero 2 from <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>And even then this was heavy. That's a lot of glass and accessories to haul with you.</p>

<p>I was there primarily in a still-photography capacity, however, I did want to shoot some video too. A mutual friend, Pat Theodore, was on video duty with his Nikons, but I offered to throw in whatever I got with the GoPro and my MK II into the mix.</p>

<p>Thankfully, the one variable that I could not control cooperated. The weather was amazing.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/19//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q-v-TfggF9/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/52bcbd681a3b11e282a722000a1c8689_7.jpg' alt='Perty.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=34.680565526,-76.923046936'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=34.680565526,-76.923046936&markers=34.680565526,-76.923046936&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='On The Beach Drinking Beers' /></a><br/>Taken at On The Beach Drinking Beers</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='305892814431060349_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>The Emerald Isle weather gods were definitely with us that day. And the wedding was planned to be right around sunset.</p>

<p>The true challenge of the wedding really wasn't on a technical level for me. I was shooting at golden hour, on the beach, with people I know and get along famously with. The real challenge was on an organizational level. As I was the only still shooter for the wedding, I had my hands full, even with a small party (around 30 people), such as this one. I can see now why full-time wedding shooters, always have a second person with them. I got the photos I wanted, and then some, but it was definitely a few minutes of sheer intensity as I scrambled around to get the images. The biggest savior was definitely the 70-200. From a practical standpoint, the lens enabled me to get "the" key images of the actual vows portion of the ceremony, without being on top of the bride and groom. I also utilized one of the 580s I had with me as a remote light. I used the Gorillapod to strap it to the "altar" framework and put it on a secondary channel which I clicked over to as I needed it. I ended up not really using it, but it was nice to have on hand. And I had the GoPro running as a continuous record of the ceremony. I wonder how that came out...</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tal-3107.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'In close but not'" ></p>

<p>And, one can definitely not argue with the virtue of having someone trained in makeup on hand. One of Tal's friends, Kristin, along with Michelle T, handled that duty. Sure, brides have to look their best, but us behind the lens appreciate it too. A well-done makeup job saves us enormous amounts of time later. Tal has a natural glow to her anyways, but the makeup job will be saving me hours of time in post production this coming week.</p>

<p>Now, where the ceremony was mainly, from a technical perspective, about the 70-200, the candids at the reception back at the beach house were all about going wide, and using my 50 1.2 L. While not a nightclub setting, the lighting was darker and variable, and I wanted to get some "candids" like they expected out of me. And the 50 came through, especially later, when someone (not gonna say who!) decided to set off some heavy-duty fireworks in celebration of the happy couple.</p>

<p>That being said, it was definitely a great departure from my norm in terms of shooting. I probably bought a little more equipment than I really needed to for this specific ceremony, but, it is best to be overprepared than under. And, a wedding is one situation where you definitely need to make the client aware of whether you are there for stills, or video. I grabbed some video as time permitted, but I didn't make it a priority. I had the GoPro with me mainly as an experiment, and anything out of the MK II was when the moment became rather static.</p>

<p>After this experience, I can say I do have more of an appreciation for what full-time wedding shooters do. It's a tough job, even if you know the people involved. Would I get into wedding photography full-time? Well, only if I could get a gig like this past one on a regular basis. I'm not too sure if I'd be down for a full-on church-and-500-family-members-and-freeloaders style ceremony.</p>

<p>But, more importantly, congrats once again to Talmage and Erick. You guys rock. I'll have your custom site and edits sorted probably around the time you get in from Captiva...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It is like my version of Mr Sparkle.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/my-version-of-mr-sparkle/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T18:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/my-version-of-mr-sparkle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/niceday-1479.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Mirinda'" ></p>

<p>It was a positively stunning day here in South Florida, so I jumped in the 210 and went out for a bit.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I made my usual Saturday stop at Whole Foods, this time the South Beach one. The Aventura one has better wraps, but the Beach one is closer, and I wanted to shoot some random stuff on the Beach anyways.</p>

<p>After my tuna wrap, I proceeded up Collins to the Ocean Terrace around 74th Street. I figured I'd try to get some shallow DOF shots out on the sand. I was experimenting with trying to capture one breaking wave, when an orange can thumped into my foot.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/niceday-1476.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Mirinda'" ></p>

<p>"Mirinda?" I thought, "What the hell is Mirinda?"</p>

<p>It's a girl's name in some quarters, but I never saw it applied to a beverage. So, curious, I picked up the can. It was unopened, and aside from the Mirinda logo, it lacked the usual nutritional value grid, and also the volume was listed as 330 mL only. No Imperial measurements. My god, it's a can from the future!</p>

<p>It was totally my Mr Sparkle moment.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dnaLRbbc-54" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>But, my momentary flashback to a Simpsons episode faded, and it turns out Mirinda is a product of Pepsi, primarily distributed in Asia. The can actually said "Distributed by Pepsi Singapore" on the side.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QvBo3qggAv/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/e3132586156e11e283e622000a1fb86d_7.jpg' alt='This must have fallen off of a ship. #mirinda #singapore @norahlovesmakeup_mua idea? This is in Miami Beach.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/hudson'>Hudson</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.86046311,-80.1200069'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.86046311,-80.1200069&markers=25.86046311,-80.1200069&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Maracas Place' /></a><br/>Taken at Maracas Place</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301466906651656239_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I'm guessing it probably fell off of a passing cargo freighter, which most likely took on provisions in the port of Singapore. There's an ever so slight chance it washed up from further away, but most likely it is the boring explanation.</p>

<p>This was totally my Mr Sparkle moment though.</p>

<p>Now, the can is still sealed, so in theory the beverage should be consumable. It's in my fridge right now. I don't drink soda anymore though...</p>

<p>Oh, and I'm totally loving how things look at 1.2 during broad daylight. Very surreal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone summed it up eloquently...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T03:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jordyn-6643.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'It fell in line...'" ></p>

<p>While some tell me my strength lies in capturing images, I also have been told I can write well. However, in terms of writing, I do tend to ramble. Hence, this blog's tagline having the words "general ramblings"...</p>

<p>So, when someone asks for me to summarize something, it's nigh-impossible for me to do. So, if you asked me to sum up my own body of photographic work, I'd be at a loss to condense it to a sentence or two. I cringe at committing grammar crimes when I have to post to Twitter. The art of summary is lost to me.</p>

<p>However, someone summarized what I do so well for me just a few minutes ago...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it...</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And <em>boom</em>, that sums it up.</p>

<p>I could sit here for hours expounding on noise levels, a-to-d conversions, electric fields emanating from poorly-shielded cabling, the native ISO of a given sensor, and don't-point-your-lens-at-a-10-watt-laser-you-fool type of things and it wouldn't be a summary of how I manage to pull off a shot. It'd be the Book of Pod so to speak. Which, some people like, and some people don't.</p>

<p>It actually speaks volumes about having an outside opinion.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QtZ7SrAgIA/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4906bc4c14f011e2bacf123138179cfe_7.jpg' alt='You can see the guy about to jump out.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.82752892,-80.187165969'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.82752892,-80.187165969&markers=25.82752892,-80.187165969&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='55th Street Station' /></a><br/>Taken at 55th Street Station</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301010775764500992_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I had just come back from a nighttime run (yes Ryan, I do run around this neighborhood at 1 AM) and I picked up a text conversation where I had left it off earlier. My friend Adriana had just moved from the construction mess called Brickell, to a cozy new joint on Collins Avenue in "Condo Canyon" with her boyfriend. She was inviting me over for a little housewarming thing tomorrow, and she mentioned the last thing she had picked up from her old apt was a piece of mine that she purchased back in 2009:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/frances_2008.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Frances at Space - 2008'" ></p>

<p>I had done an exhibit of some of my "dancer photos" at the first <a href="http://lifeisart.org">Life Is Art</a> exhibit in Wynwood. Life is Art, by <a href="http://soulofmiami.org">Soul of Miami</a> founder James Echols, is a local organization that supports up-and-coming artists of all stripes. Since that first open show in 2009, they've come a long way and are quite renowned in the art community, especially amongst artists who may not be "hip" enough to warrant the attention of some of the more corporate art organizations in town. Adriana, at the time, was their treasurer, and had expressed an interest in obtaining a print of one of my images, specifically the one above. So, her mom took it upon herself to pull me aside and purchase it from me for her. As my exhibit was digital (I didn't have the budget to produce 20 prints of size), I took the "order" and contacted my print provider to generate a canvas-framed print for me of this piece. A few weeks later, it was delivered to Adriana, to much acclaim. Oddly enough it's the only "dancer" piece I have ever sold. Either I just haven't marketed them properly or people don't go for half-naked girls in smoky nightclubs as <em>objets d'art</em>.</p>

<p>Fast-forward to today. As pieces of art are often delicate, they are usually transported separately from other items in a moving adventure. Anyways, in a conversation about that piece tonight, Adriana was asking me about how I capture moments like that, and I did have a hard time summarizing it up. So, she put it into words that had previously escaped me:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it...</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And yes, that's it. Minus the technical details, which, if anyone asks, I'll gladly explain, that's pretty much it. I see the image in my head, and I wait for the world to fall in line. Whether it's in a club or below a deserted bridge in Key West, that's it. If I had to sum it up into a Twitter-friendly sentence, that is it.</p>

<p>Now, if I can summarize this post, it would be, "A different perspective always helps..."</p>

<p>Oh, and Ade, thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ramblings after the weekend...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08/ramblings-after-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T23:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08/ramblings-after-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9386.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Still here at 9 AM?'" ></p>

<p>It was one of those random "on and off" weekends.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Much like any other mental factor, creativity seems to have a finite supply of sorts, and can be slow to replenish. Thursday, I shot a scenic I'm really proud of, the aptly-titled (yes, I'm totally being narcissistic here) "Where The Buses Don't Run".</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/outwhere_rev-8882.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'US 27 Northbound Broward County'" ></p>

<p>I did this on a Thursday night/Friday morning, and I did the editing and "mastering" work on Friday. When I intend to sell a print, I tend to nitpick. I'll obsess over minute color corrections, lens flares, and wish for things like my print provider accepting TIFF uploads on the off chance there's some minor compression artifacts which could be visible at a large enough print size.</p>

<p>Oh, and by the way, "Out Where The Buses Don't Run" is for sale on my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">Fine Art America</a> site, along with eight other pieces I consider potential sellers. I'm getting more and more into shooting nighttime scenics. Though I could do without the bugs in the Everglades. There was a mosquito in the 210 on my way home that night. The hardest part was concentrating on keeping steady at 130 km/h while hoping the little bastard would just go away. I did the "open all windows and go even faster" trick and that seemed to help.</p>

<p>That being said, I was fully intent on going back out to shoot more scenics on Friday, but that actually never panned out. I couldn't think of a location to scope out. I might try west this week, now that I think about it.</p>

<p>Saturday was my usual club night over at <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space</a>. Two of my favorites, Chus + Ceballos, were on hand to provide an extended musical soundtrack to the evening. These guys "get it", they know they are there to keep the crowd moving, and they provide an excellent musical selection over the course of ten or more hours on the decks. Great guys in person, too. They're always game for the photo op, and they actually love to meet their fans. They <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/06/the-musical-ecosystem/">know their place in the musical ecosystem</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9091.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'That Nikon is like a periscope'" ></p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/08//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QiwaZHAgNP/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/5be1081a11b011e2aeda22000a1de2e0_7.jpg' alt='Los Tios @chuslesteban @clubspacemiami @jhartlein @ppod @travisrogersmia More at http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/chus-and-ceballos-return-to-space#5' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='298013445259920207_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I still have to figure out how to derive that media_id without having to manually kick the Instagram API. If anyone knows how, let me know.</p>

<p>That being said, I definitely had "more creative energy" by that Saturday night. Some plans for early hours didn't materialize. I was supposed to attend a bachelor/bachelorette party at Scarlett's up in Hollywood, but the "confirmation" message never arrived that the people were actually gonna go. By then, it was 1:30 in the morning and I was already framing my mind from staring at desperate girls on the pole to actually doing something productive. So, I kind of said "the hell with it", jumped into a <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car 2 Go</a>, and drove on over to Space.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QeHL8FAgAh/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/88cd369e104511e2b7ea22000a1fc2ec_7.jpg' alt='Saddle up. @car2gomiami to @clubspacemiami' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='296706232201379873_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>Car 2 Go is saving me so much money in cab fare. It's amazing. Plus, they never thought of my use case until I told them. They posted on Facebook about using their service to get to the Brickell Oktoberfest party, and taking the safe way (a cab) home. Agalmic cowboy diplomacy.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9217.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Hi Jordyn'" ></p>

<p>Anyways, Space was the usual 'rock' of Miami nightlife this past weekend. Great atmosphere, an interesting crowd, and great music. It's not a trendy VIP club, and it doesn't aspire to be. In my mind it's the heart of Miami nightlife. It is one venue you can go to without even bothering to check their website to see who is playing. A friend of mine suggested that their marketing campaign should be "Space: We're fucking open."</p>

<p>I did my usual rounds at the venue, including switching out to the 50 1.2 L as the morning rolled on. It's a learning curve, but one I'm glad to participate in. It's a great lens and you can do amazing things with it wide open. Every Canon user should have it in their arsenal.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9335.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Lucy I'm Home'" ></p>

<p>At 1.2, you will have throwaway images. Nature of the beast in a nightclub. Just keep shooting, but don't turn it into a Golden BB spray-and-pray affair. If the shot doesn't happen, it doesn't happen.</p>

<p>I left a little after 9 AM Sunday morning. I woke up Sunday afternoon, since I had a Keys trip planned, but the weather totally did not cooperate. I ended up turning around on the Turnpike Extension after a huge downpour kicked in, with more forecast for Monday. Though Monday turned out to be a rather nice day. Such is luck I guess.</p>

<p>I'll try to make it down again in the next few weeks. Maybe after Halloween Weekend.</p>

<p>Totally random weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
