<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: video | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/video/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-28T14:18:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I like Vimeo.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/i-like-vimeo/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T14:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/i-like-vimeo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="" height="" src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/46506653 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Vimeo is the superior video sharing platform, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Why?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It plays your content, and gets out of the way. Anything beyond that is up to you.</p>

<p>And yes, the plugin works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On passing on knowledge...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/on-passing-on-knowledge-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/on-passing-on-knowledge-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6552.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Roger Sanchez - A real DJ at work'" ></p>

<p>A lot of people ask me about my photos, "How did you do that?"</p>

<p>Well, truth be told, it isn't a huge secret on how I, or any other working photographer, pulls off their images...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I was having a discussion with <a href="http://ryanalynporter.com">Ryan</a> the other day, in response to my prior posting about <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera/">being more than the guy with the camera.</a></p>

<p>Ryan bought forth the term <em>agalmics</em> during our discussion. In a nutshell, agalmics is:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The study and practice of the production and allocation of non-scarce goods.</p><footer><strong>Robert Levin</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.openverse.com/~dtinker/agalmics.html'>Agalmics - the Marginalization of Scarcity</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And yes, that was an excuse to show off the shiny blockquote tag here in Octopress. Which actually ties into what I'm talking about here.</p>

<p>The internet has made knowledge of most subjects a non-scarce resource. From the implementation of the blockquote tag here on my blog, to just how the heck I composed that image of Roger that leads off the article, to the basic techniques Roger uses to mix music together in his DJ sets, the transfer of knowledge has definitely become a non-scarce resource. It's really not much of an exaggeration to say that the sum of human knowledge is online these days.</p>

<p>With a few exceptions, the directions on how to do just about anything have been documented online, and those directions are freely accessible. And if they are not freely accessible at first, some more searching will bring forth a free alternative on how to get something done. I mention that because some academic research is locked behind paywalls. However, similar research is often freely accessible, and the assiduous student can often come to the same conclusions the researchers hiding behind paywalls do.</p>

<p>But anyways, with regards to my photo work, I don't mind freely passing on the knowledge, even if I paid for it a long time ago. If I'm stingy with the knowledge, the person asking for it, if they are determined enough, will seek it out on their own, and undoubtedly discover it elsewhere. Ryan put it bluntly:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>An agalmic entrepreneur's currency is his reputation.</p><footer><strong>Ryan Porter</strong> <cite><a href='http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=20149&amp;st=0&amp;sk=t&amp;sd=a'>EDM Is the Wimpiest Youth Movement Ever? - TNL Thread</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>My reputation (other than being a scandal!) tends to lie in the direction that I am in possession of a lot of knowledge, and I have no qualms about giving it away. It's a currency that can be spent and earned just like money nowadays. And simply because people have faith that the knowledge will benefit them. Much like the US Dollar is only worth something because the world believes it is worth something. We've assigned value to it, and it is no longer based on the reserves of a scarce material, i.e. gold.</p>

<p>But unlike gold, knowledge and information are no longer scarce. It's all out there, free for the taking. Even if you do not own your own computer or have your own internet connection, you can avail yourself of free resources to get online, and access the same information a guy on his iPad next to his pool on Star Island can.</p>

<p>So with that in mind, I tend to not object if someone sincerely asks how I manage to pull something off in the photographic realm. I get something out of it, myself, personally. I tend to be a miserable rat bastard about some things, like the political system, the popularity of dubstep, ravers, fluorescent lighting, BlackBerries, and American Idol. So I guess, subconsciously, to balance out that deficit in the karma bank, I kind of get a visceral thrill when I can pass on what I've learned. That, and when it comes to photo work at least, I can only pass on the parameters of what I've done, it's up to the person I'm teaching to implement it at the right time. It's like your parents can tell you how to drive a car, but eventually you have to get behind the wheel and do it yourself. And once you are behind the wheel, it's a lot different than when Mom told you not to stomp on the accelerator.</p>

<p>And as far as someone using that knowledge against me? Well, I don't see it as being used against me, since I really don't play that game. If someone takes what I've showed them and apes my style, and gets more work than I do, that's fine. Even if they don't acknowledge where they learned it from. Recognition and attribution are nice and "proper internet etiquette", but I don't expect it these days. I figure it is something they have to live with. And I'm really not in the recognition game, either. If what I do helps a friend or a client do well, I usually get taken along for the ride. There's a lot of things at play out in the world that are way more powerful than myself, and I figure it's easier to just ride the wave and catch a ride, rather than try to take on those forces directly. Either way, I end up doing alright for myself.</p>

<p>With that in mind, I do plan on passing on little bits and pieces of what I know in this here blog, kind of as a way to balance out some of the more ornery aspects of it, and also just for the sake of composing my thoughts on "paper". Sometimes it'll be about photographic and video techniques I know, other times it'll be about coding this here site, and maybe on occasion some bits and pieces on the fine art of Mercedes maintenance as I learn more about that.</p>

<p>I'm on a bit of a roll right now, let me kick off the first one. In the next post. Let's keep this somewhat organized.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You need to think fourth-dimensionally, Marty!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/you-need-to-think-fourth-dimensionally-marty/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T12:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/you-need-to-think-fourth-dimensionally-marty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/49508063" width="960" height="540" frameborder="1" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/49508063">• Season 8 Finals - Jive With The Band •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>I'm relearning the fine art of video editing. I learned on an analog system (real film!) though the concepts carry over. It's all about the story.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My current weapon of choice for editing is Final Cut Pro X. While the dyed-in-the-wool digital video types give it hell for being too much like iMovie and not a "real" pro product like it was, I find FCP-X suits my fancy for the basic video projects I'm doing myself at the moment. Like I've mentioned in the past, I usually just shoot, and pass my results off to someone with more editing and VFX skills like <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com/">Alex and his team over at Deepsleep</a>. However, even they use Final Cut Pro X for their final editing workflow.</p>

<p>In the end, an edit is an edit. You're trying to tell a story, and all the VFX goodies and title transitions in the world won't help if your timing and sequencing is off. That's actually something that takes years to master. I know in my head where I want to go with the story, I'm still just learning the modern tools of the trade. So yes, sometimes my edits are "off". It's a work in progress.</p>

<p>You have to think fourth-dimensionally. When shooting and when editing. You have to have an idea of what you want to shoot, and during the edit, what you have in your "bin". In an event like Jive, the regular repeat singers often perform twice throughout the night, once in the beginning, and once near the end to really knock the crowd out. I have to remember that sometimes I'll have "better" footage of say, Sir Diego, from later on in the night, even if his first performance knocked it out of the park. Sometimes it's the reverse actually. Either way, I have to keep in mind I have multiple takes. Keeping the bin coherent is key.</p>

<p>And this is just on the video side. The audio side is a whole other ball of wax. I record with a basic Sennheiser stereo mic, though I do want to progress to one of their wireless kits where I take a feed straight from the FOH mixer at the bar. That is a $600 investment though, and I'm currently not shooting enough live music events to justify the outlay. It's an amazing widget regardless, though.</p>

<p>Regardless, if you are a photographer getting into video, just remember to think fourth-dimensionally. You are composing a project that exists not only in space, but in time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We can't make art from air.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T22:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage8.instagram.com/5ba9a3d8e32611e1a4431231381407ca_7.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Gear and girl'" ></p>

<p>I got into a discussion just now over on <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=6&t=19857">Talk Nightlife</a> with James, founder of <a href="http://soulofmiami.org/">Soul of Miami</a> about some of the trials and tribulations of the photographers and photo editors in the Olympics. I linked on over to a <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/photographers-blog/2012/08/10/click-edit-crop-or-drop/">blog post on Reuters</a> about the workflow of their on-site photo team. James' comment was that it was fascinating, but essentially <strong>"It really does not seem like they could possibly be getting paid enough for that."</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
Sadly, that is the truth. However, most of us whom are into the photo and video industries aren't into it for a big payday. Sure, income is nice, but at the end of the day, a photo career is a lot of hard work, and is often times frustrating, and the income rarely is there.</p>

<p>Sure, every guy and girl behind the lens has fantasies of one day making that 'big score', and not having to work again, but in most cases, that never happens. They might make what would be equivalent to mid-to-high five figures on average per year, but most of that money gets eaten up in taxes, reinvesting in the business, and general expenses associated with running said business. It's why if you see a photographer with a bunch of fancy non-photo-related toys, chances are that he or she probably has a second source of money, whether it's a "real job", another business that pays real money, or comes from money and happens to have a "hobby". And yes, there's always the slight chance that they scored and are living quite well off of their photo incomes.</p>

<p>Since the digital revolution, the intrinsic monetary value of photography has gone down enormously. A lot of shooters struggle to stay afloat and often have to make concessions and do other things to make ends meet. I'm a perfect example. I earn money from photography and video, but I have to tinker with websites and take on odd tasks related to the web to make ends meet. I'm very frugal but things still cost money. Also, it is a bit more costly to obtain basic health insurance on your own, than it is if you are part of a standard corporate entity.</p>

<p>It's actually why I've come around a bit on the whole government-provided healthcare issue actually. I'm for small government, but I do think one of the duties of the government is to take care of it's taxpayers. I think that if we're taken care of on a basic level by state health insurance, that would actually free us, as a people, up to take more risks in business and our personal lives. I know a lot of people with big ideas and dreams, who don't want to leave their corporate gigs, because said gigs provide the benefit of health insurance. And, obviously those corporate gigs demand a fair share of one's time and energy. But the healthcare rant is another post entirely. Hey, it's my blog, I don't have to necessarily adhere to standard editorial guidelines.</p>

<p>But anyways, society as a whole has come to devalue the work of photographers. Now, at no point has a photography career ever been a sure path to untold riches or success. Whether the workflow was analog or digital, it's always been the rare person who made their millions off of photography. And if they did make their millions off of it, chances are they are dead or pretty close to it, and the value of their work has increased by virtue of that. Suffice to say, the quickest way to increase the value of your photography is to die, preferably in a dramatic fashion.</p>

<p>All jokes aside though, the value, and the respect of the art has been diminished somewhat over the past decade. And it has been a two-pronged assault, from without, and from within. From without, it's been clients seeking the cheap way out. Even the most professional organizations expect to be able to pay only a pittance for work. A campaign that might cost thousands on the part of the photographer to execute, the client might only be willing to pay a few hundred dollars for. Of course everyone wants to spend as little as possible, but there is a point where the client base does need to remember that 'they get what they pay for'. You only pay a few hundred dollars, well, that is about all the work you will get. Someone recently offered me $50 and a bucket of booze to shoot a party. I blew them off, it wasn't even worth a response. Everyone knows I like to have a drink or two, but I won't work for that sort of thing. I have bills to pay. And $50 would not cover my own nightly expenses, as the gig was on South Beach (no Car2Go), and of course my time in post and editing.
If you want to pay me $50, I'd expect a chauffeured ride to and from the venue, and I'll probably take three photos, steal your girlfriend, and not bother delivering the edit (1 photo) until sometime in 2025.</p>

<p>And that's just the problem from without. The problem from within is almost as bad. The digital revolution has put quality imaging tools into the hands of all. For $400 or less (say, a used Drebel kit), one can obtain a quality digital SLR with a basic lens. Under decent lighting conditions, this kit can objectively shoot great images, even in the hands of an amateur. And said images could conceivably be used for commercial purposes with the right editing and post production. So, now, businesses can hire "some guy they know", or "do it in-house" (though there's nothing wrong with an staff shooter in some instances, as long as rights and releases are fair), and attempt to save a buck or two, and have "some guy they know" fix any of the problems later, or leave the fixing to some beleaguered designer at a graphic design firm somewhere. Sidebar: graphic designers hate that.</p>

<p>When confronted, the businesses and the shooters themselves will often plead ignorance, or claim that "this is the way things are now, deal with it".
Understandably, the dynamics of the digital economy have changed things, but photographers and other visual professionals do need to have an income to survive and keep providing these services to clients. If all photography was cheap and/or free, eventually there would be no photographers to generate the images clients require and need. And computer rendering of realistic scenes is far more expensive (to do right) than booking the services of a photographer, so don't try to get me there!</p>

<p>What's even worse is the lack of understanding of licensing and rights, as well. Very few businesses understand this. They treat all photographic work for them as work-for-hire, with unlimited use. To them, once the photo is taken, it is theirs. It doesn't work that way. Licensing and sale is one of the only ways a photographer can stand a chance of making a reasonable living nowadays, especially in the situations I've described above. And very few photographers understand it as well as they should. It took me awhile to get a handle on it, but once one understands the ins and outs of it, it's easy to figure out.
In this case, Google is your friend. Search for "editorial photography rate guidelines" and go from there. I'm not being lazy, there is just a huge amount of information on pricing your work accordingly. FYI, it's why a decent-sized print of mine will run you a few hundred dollars or more at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> page.</p>

<p>Again, we're in this because we love to do it, not because we're seeking a route to glorious riches and untold glory. All anyone behind the lens asks for is just compensation to cover the costs of doing business, and enjoy life while we're at it. I don't think there's many photographers out there whom are greedy and driven by dollar signs. Even we like to put the camera down sometimes and take a little vacation somewhere. With a smaller camera of course, we might see something interesting along the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Redrock Micro.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T12:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/redrock.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Redrock'" ></p>

<p>Yesterday, I had the fortunate opportunity to work with <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Alex Martinez</a> and <a href="http://michaelraveney.com/">Michael Raveney</a> on the next spot for the upcoming <a href="http://ur1festival.com/">UR1 Festival</a>.</p>

<p>Alex, as some of my fans know, provides excellent graphic design work (including my own logo), and Michael is a prominent fashion and editorial photographer here in Miami.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>The project we were all working on was a spot for the forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>. Produced by <strong>Emi Guerra</strong> and <strong>Alex Omes</strong>, the UR1 Festival takes place during Art Basel and will combine all genres of music and art into one helluva massive party. Count me in. I should "lean" on my good friend Emi and get some of my pieces featured therein.</p>

<p>But anyways, we were all tasked to film an upcoming piece promoting the festival. Alex and Michael conceptualized it, and my task was to be the "fly on the wall" and document the making of said piece. I was the documentarian. Excellent. However, I didn't relish the thought of hours of holding my MK II at arms length.</p>

<p>For all the pluses of using a DSLR for video, the one major flaw is that that the DSLR form factor is entirely wrong for shooting video. Holding a front-heavy body at arms length results in very unsteady compositions. So, on the way up to Michael's studio, I popped into <a href="http://aperturepro.com">Aperture</a>. After a brief consultation, I rented a <a href="http://redrockmicro.com/">Redrock Micro</a> mount for my MK II.</p>

<p>Without getting too much into the particulars, this definitely made my life easier. The weight distribution matched that of a traditional video camera, and made my handheld jitters that much more stable. I could glide my shots through the space with ease, and not worry about having to deal with stabilization in post.</p>

<p>Some may blanch at the pricing on Redrock's equipment though. From $350 to well over $1000 depending on the options, it's not cheap. Some suggest using the Chinese knock-off versions on eBay for $150 or less, but in my experience, the Chinese knockoffs are just that, knockoffs, and are prone to falling apart at the wrong time. Live a little, and spend for the Redrock. I know I will.</p>

<p>I'll be posting some of the results after we complete the edit of the video for UR1. We gotta keep it on the down-low, you know.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts1.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts2.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
