<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: video | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/video/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-06T19:48:01-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We can't make art from air.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T22:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage8.instagram.com/5ba9a3d8e32611e1a4431231381407ca_7.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Gear and girl'" ></p>

<p>I got into a discussion just now over on <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=6&t=19857">Talk Nightlife</a> with James, founder of <a href="http://soulofmiami.org/">Soul of Miami</a> about some of the trials and tribulations of the photographers and photo editors in the Olympics. I linked on over to a <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/photographers-blog/2012/08/10/click-edit-crop-or-drop/">blog post on Reuters</a> about the workflow of their on-site photo team. James' comment was that it was fascinating, but essentially <strong>"It really does not seem like they could possibly be getting paid enough for that."</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
Sadly, that is the truth. However, most of us whom are into the photo and video industries aren't into it for a big payday. Sure, income is nice, but at the end of the day, a photo career is a lot of hard work, and is often times frustrating, and the income rarely is there.</p>

<p>Sure, every guy and girl behind the lens has fantasies of one day making that 'big score', and not having to work again, but in most cases, that never happens. They might make what would be equivalent to mid-to-high five figures on average per year, but most of that money gets eaten up in taxes, reinvesting in the business, and general expenses associated with running said business. It's why if you see a photographer with a bunch of fancy non-photo-related toys, chances are that he or she probably has a second source of money, whether it's a "real job", another business that pays real money, or comes from money and happens to have a "hobby". And yes, there's always the slight chance that they scored and are living quite well off of their photo incomes.</p>

<p>Since the digital revolution, the intrinsic monetary value of photography has gone down enormously. A lot of shooters struggle to stay afloat and often have to make concessions and do other things to make ends meet. I'm a perfect example. I earn money from photography and video, but I have to tinker with websites and take on odd tasks related to the web to make ends meet. I'm very frugal but things still cost money. Also, it is a bit more costly to obtain basic health insurance on your own, than it is if you are part of a standard corporate entity.</p>

<p>It's actually why I've come around a bit on the whole government-provided healthcare issue actually. I'm for small government, but I do think one of the duties of the government is to take care of it's taxpayers. I think that if we're taken care of on a basic level by state health insurance, that would actually free us, as a people, up to take more risks in business and our personal lives. I know a lot of people with big ideas and dreams, who don't want to leave their corporate gigs, because said gigs provide the benefit of health insurance. And, obviously those corporate gigs demand a fair share of one's time and energy. But the healthcare rant is another post entirely. Hey, it's my blog, I don't have to necessarily adhere to standard editorial guidelines.</p>

<p>But anyways, society as a whole has come to devalue the work of photographers. Now, at no point has a photography career ever been a sure path to untold riches or success. Whether the workflow was analog or digital, it's always been the rare person who made their millions off of photography. And if they did make their millions off of it, chances are they are dead or pretty close to it, and the value of their work has increased by virtue of that. Suffice to say, the quickest way to increase the value of your photography is to die, preferably in a dramatic fashion.</p>

<p>All jokes aside though, the value, and the respect of the art has been diminished somewhat over the past decade. And it has been a two-pronged assault, from without, and from within. From without, it's been clients seeking the cheap way out. Even the most professional organizations expect to be able to pay only a pittance for work. A campaign that might cost thousands on the part of the photographer to execute, the client might only be willing to pay a few hundred dollars for. Of course everyone wants to spend as little as possible, but there is a point where the client base does need to remember that 'they get what they pay for'. You only pay a few hundred dollars, well, that is about all the work you will get. Someone recently offered me $50 and a bucket of booze to shoot a party. I blew them off, it wasn't even worth a response. Everyone knows I like to have a drink or two, but I won't work for that sort of thing. I have bills to pay. And $50 would not cover my own nightly expenses, as the gig was on South Beach (no Car2Go), and of course my time in post and editing.
If you want to pay me $50, I'd expect a chauffeured ride to and from the venue, and I'll probably take three photos, steal your girlfriend, and not bother delivering the edit (1 photo) until sometime in 2025.</p>

<p>And that's just the problem from without. The problem from within is almost as bad. The digital revolution has put quality imaging tools into the hands of all. For $400 or less (say, a used Drebel kit), one can obtain a quality digital SLR with a basic lens. Under decent lighting conditions, this kit can objectively shoot great images, even in the hands of an amateur. And said images could conceivably be used for commercial purposes with the right editing and post production. So, now, businesses can hire "some guy they know", or "do it in-house" (though there's nothing wrong with an staff shooter in some instances, as long as rights and releases are fair), and attempt to save a buck or two, and have "some guy they know" fix any of the problems later, or leave the fixing to some beleaguered designer at a graphic design firm somewhere. Sidebar: graphic designers hate that.</p>

<p>When confronted, the businesses and the shooters themselves will often plead ignorance, or claim that "this is the way things are now, deal with it".
Understandably, the dynamics of the digital economy have changed things, but photographers and other visual professionals do need to have an income to survive and keep providing these services to clients. If all photography was cheap and/or free, eventually there would be no photographers to generate the images clients require and need. And computer rendering of realistic scenes is far more expensive (to do right) than booking the services of a photographer, so don't try to get me there!</p>

<p>What's even worse is the lack of understanding of licensing and rights, as well. Very few businesses understand this. They treat all photographic work for them as work-for-hire, with unlimited use. To them, once the photo is taken, it is theirs. It doesn't work that way. Licensing and sale is one of the only ways a photographer can stand a chance of making a reasonable living nowadays, especially in the situations I've described above. And very few photographers understand it as well as they should. It took me awhile to get a handle on it, but once one understands the ins and outs of it, it's easy to figure out.
In this case, Google is your friend. Search for "editorial photography rate guidelines" and go from there. I'm not being lazy, there is just a huge amount of information on pricing your work accordingly. FYI, it's why a decent-sized print of mine will run you a few hundred dollars or more at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> page.</p>

<p>Again, we're in this because we love to do it, not because we're seeking a route to glorious riches and untold glory. All anyone behind the lens asks for is just compensation to cover the costs of doing business, and enjoy life while we're at it. I don't think there's many photographers out there whom are greedy and driven by dollar signs. Even we like to put the camera down sometimes and take a little vacation somewhere. With a smaller camera of course, we might see something interesting along the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Redrock Micro.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T12:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/redrock.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Redrock'" ></p>

<p>Yesterday, I had the fortunate opportunity to work with <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Alex Martinez</a> and <a href="http://michaelraveney.com/">Michael Raveney</a> on the next spot for the upcoming <a href="http://ur1festival.com/">UR1 Festival</a>.</p>

<p>Alex, as some of my fans know, provides excellent graphic design work (including my own logo), and Michael is a prominent fashion and editorial photographer here in Miami.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>The project we were all working on was a spot for the forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>. Produced by <strong>Emi Guerra</strong> and <strong>Alex Omes</strong>, the UR1 Festival takes place during Art Basel and will combine all genres of music and art into one helluva massive party. Count me in. I should "lean" on my good friend Emi and get some of my pieces featured therein.</p>

<p>But anyways, we were all tasked to film an upcoming piece promoting the festival. Alex and Michael conceptualized it, and my task was to be the "fly on the wall" and document the making of said piece. I was the documentarian. Excellent. However, I didn't relish the thought of hours of holding my MK II at arms length.</p>

<p>For all the pluses of using a DSLR for video, the one major flaw is that that the DSLR form factor is entirely wrong for shooting video. Holding a front-heavy body at arms length results in very unsteady compositions. So, on the way up to Michael's studio, I popped into <a href="http://aperturepro.com">Aperture</a>. After a brief consultation, I rented a <a href="http://redrockmicro.com/">Redrock Micro</a> mount for my MK II.</p>

<p>Without getting too much into the particulars, this definitely made my life easier. The weight distribution matched that of a traditional video camera, and made my handheld jitters that much more stable. I could glide my shots through the space with ease, and not worry about having to deal with stabilization in post.</p>

<p>Some may blanch at the pricing on Redrock's equipment though. From $350 to well over $1000 depending on the options, it's not cheap. Some suggest using the Chinese knock-off versions on eBay for $150 or less, but in my experience, the Chinese knockoffs are just that, knockoffs, and are prone to falling apart at the wrong time. Live a little, and spend for the Redrock. I know I will.</p>

<p>I'll be posting some of the results after we complete the edit of the video for UR1. We gotta keep it on the down-low, you know.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts1.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts2.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say, that's a nice camera...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/gearhead.jpg" width="960" height="203" title="'Go Pro on W210'" ></p>

<p>One of the most common questions that anyone in the photo or video industry gets asked, is, "<em>What sort of gear do you use?</em>"</p>

<p>Well, it's a reasonable question. The general public and professionals alike like to know that sort of thing, and it's a good conversation starter with anyone in the visual arts.</p>

<p>Me? What do I use?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My primary rig is a Canon 5D MK II full-frame DSLR for both still and video applications. Lenswise I have a 16-35 2.8 L, a 50 1.2 L, and a 70-200 2.8 L, all by Canon. And on the lighting end, a 580 EX flashgun (it goes pop and lights up things) and an ST-E2 wireless controller for the flash (so I can change the angle of light, etc...). And that's it, not counting a backup body. And of course some Macs for editing and heavy lifting.</p>

<p>It's a small assortment of gear, by no means a huge arsenal. Plus, when are in a more freeform situation such as an event or nightclub shoot, working with what you have on hand in a small satchel makes it far more interesting. This ethos is actually more and more common amongst professional photographers and videographers. Lenses and camera bodies aren't cheap, and it doesn't make sense to carry gear you don't use that often. So, a lot of pros on a budget and a lot who aren't, they simply rent.</p>

<p>The rise of photo gear rental house over the past decade has been phenomenal. All major cities have photo and video gear rental houses, such as <a href="http://aperturepro.com/"><strong>Aperture</strong></a> here in Miami, and online outlets such as <a href="http://lensrentals.com/"><strong>Lensrentals.com</strong></a> can ship just about any type of lens, camera body, lighting instrument, or accessory to your location overnight, and the rental rates are fiercely competitive. You can rent a $10,000 lens for a few hundred dollars a week. It's perfect for the one gig that requires it, or just plain old experimentation. I occasionally rent specialized lenses outside of my work just for experimentation. Sometimes I find a commercial use for it and end up purchasing it, as I did with the 50 1.2 L. I rented it repeatedly, and I ended up purchasing it as part of my permanent arsenal. It's also obviously a great way to audition gear you intend to buy.</p>

<p>And in the end, especially in these days when it's harder and harder for photographers and video pros to get a reasonable paycheck, every dollar saved counts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with the GoPro]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/i-fell-in-love-with-the-gopro/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T17:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/i-fell-in-love-with-the-gopro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I borrowed a Go Pro from my friend <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis Rogers</a> after I saw him using one at <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space.</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/46475090" width="960" height="540" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/46475090">GoPro Test</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>I wasn't really interested in it as a club tool, though I could see it being useful as a B-camera for some in-the-booth shots. Where I found the most thrill though, was mounting it to the bumper of my car, and driving around Miami. In the video above, you can see some of the results. I'm not the sharpest editor yet, but the footage speaks for itself, I think. The GoPro is great for what it costs, and will be even better when they roll the new "ProTune" firmware any day now and really pump the bitrate.</p>

<p>And yes, this is a blatant excuse to see if Vimeo embedding works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
