<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: video | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/video/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-27T01:43:51-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting weddings...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/22/shooting-weddings-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T01:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/22/shooting-weddings-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/talerick_preview.jpg" width="960" height="610" title="'FU-T'" ></p>

<p>A huge congratulations to my friends and neighbors Talmage and Erick on their wedding this past weekend. We all went up to Emerald Isle, NC for the ceremony. It was pretty spectacular.</p>

<p>I don't explicitly advertise myself as a wedding photographer. While I know it can be lucrative, I've also heard a lot of horror stories from other shooters about the stress involved, and not just from bridezillas either...</p>

<p>But I don't turn down weddings that come my way...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Typically, a wedding will come my way about once a year. It's always through a friend or acquaintance. And, for the most part, they know how I shoot when they hire me. They know that I'm definitely not a wedding photography specialist.</p>

<p>The wedding I shot this past weekend with Tal and Erick was a great example. I've known Tal since about 2004 through the club scene and her being a poster on TNL, and Erick for a little bit longer than that. They both knew my specialties in terms of photography. But, they also wanted a distinct look and feel for their photos, and also the obvious of preferring to hire a friend rather than someone they didn't know.</p>

<p>For me, it was an opportunity to change things up a bit in terms of my photo work, and an excuse to rent some quality equipment and maybe try some new concepts.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/19//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q_FrW8ggJe/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage6.s3.amazonaws.com/d13ac15c1a5511e29c6822000a1f9688_7.jpg' alt='Tele for @talmagelisabeth wedding.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=34.682976,-76.912536'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=34.682976,-76.912536&markers=34.682976,-76.912536&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Best House At The Biotch' /></a><br/>Taken at Best House At The Biotch</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='305988269492011614_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>My loadout for the wedding started as a grandiose idea in my head. Since my "gift" to them was essentially my work (only thing I asked for was transport and lodging), I wanted to make it shine. However, since I'm a one-man show here, eventually less was more. My final kit was:</p>

<ul>
<li>5D MK II - primary body</li>
<li>50D - backup body</li>
<li>580 EX Speedlite</li>
<li>580 EX II Speedlite from <a href="http://lensrentals.com/">Lens Rentals</a>.</li>
<li>16-35mm 2.8 L zoom lens</li>
<li>50mm 1.2 L prime lens</li>
<li>70-200 2.8 II L zoom lens</li>
<li>2 Fong Lightspheres from <a href="http://lensrentals.com/">Lens Rentals</a></li>
<li>ST-E2 Speedlite transmitter</li>
<li>2 32 GB CF cards</li>
<li>Joby Gorillapod</li>
<li>The Podbook Air</li>
<li>A GoPro Hero 2 from <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>And even then this was heavy. That's a lot of glass and accessories to haul with you.</p>

<p>I was there primarily in a still-photography capacity, however, I did want to shoot some video too. A mutual friend, Pat Theodore, was on video duty with his Nikons, but I offered to throw in whatever I got with the GoPro and my MK II into the mix.</p>

<p>Thankfully, the one variable that I could not control cooperated. The weather was amazing.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/19//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q-v-TfggF9/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/52bcbd681a3b11e282a722000a1c8689_7.jpg' alt='Perty.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=34.680565526,-76.923046936'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=34.680565526,-76.923046936&markers=34.680565526,-76.923046936&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='On The Beach Drinking Beers' /></a><br/>Taken at On The Beach Drinking Beers</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='305892814431060349_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>The Emerald Isle weather gods were definitely with us that day. And the wedding was planned to be right around sunset.</p>

<p>The true challenge of the wedding really wasn't on a technical level for me. I was shooting at golden hour, on the beach, with people I know and get along famously with. The real challenge was on an organizational level. As I was the only still shooter for the wedding, I had my hands full, even with a small party (around 30 people), such as this one. I can see now why full-time wedding shooters, always have a second person with them. I got the photos I wanted, and then some, but it was definitely a few minutes of sheer intensity as I scrambled around to get the images. The biggest savior was definitely the 70-200. From a practical standpoint, the lens enabled me to get "the" key images of the actual vows portion of the ceremony, without being on top of the bride and groom. I also utilized one of the 580s I had with me as a remote light. I used the Gorillapod to strap it to the "altar" framework and put it on a secondary channel which I clicked over to as I needed it. I ended up not really using it, but it was nice to have on hand. And I had the GoPro running as a continuous record of the ceremony. I wonder how that came out...</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tal-3107.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'In close but not'" ></p>

<p>And, one can definitely not argue with the virtue of having someone trained in makeup on hand. One of Tal's friends, Kristin, along with Michelle T, handled that duty. Sure, brides have to look their best, but us behind the lens appreciate it too. A well-done makeup job saves us enormous amounts of time later. Tal has a natural glow to her anyways, but the makeup job will be saving me hours of time in post production this coming week.</p>

<p>Now, where the ceremony was mainly, from a technical perspective, about the 70-200, the candids at the reception back at the beach house were all about going wide, and using my 50 1.2 L. While not a nightclub setting, the lighting was darker and variable, and I wanted to get some "candids" like they expected out of me. And the 50 came through, especially later, when someone (not gonna say who!) decided to set off some heavy-duty fireworks in celebration of the happy couple.</p>

<p>That being said, it was definitely a great departure from my norm in terms of shooting. I probably bought a little more equipment than I really needed to for this specific ceremony, but, it is best to be overprepared than under. And, a wedding is one situation where you definitely need to make the client aware of whether you are there for stills, or video. I grabbed some video as time permitted, but I didn't make it a priority. I had the GoPro with me mainly as an experiment, and anything out of the MK II was when the moment became rather static.</p>

<p>After this experience, I can say I do have more of an appreciation for what full-time wedding shooters do. It's a tough job, even if you know the people involved. Would I get into wedding photography full-time? Well, only if I could get a gig like this past one on a regular basis. I'm not too sure if I'd be down for a full-on church-and-500-family-members-and-freeloaders style ceremony.</p>

<p>But, more importantly, congrats once again to Talmage and Erick. You guys rock. I'll have your custom site and edits sorted probably around the time you get in from Captiva...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoPro has had a busy week...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/17/gopro-has-had-a-busy-week-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-17T10:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/17/gopro-has-had-a-busy-week-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51601636?title=1&amp;byline=1&amp;portrait=1" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51601636">• GoPro Hero 2 Protune Test - Nighttime Drive •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>The fine folks at GoPro have had a busy week. For existing owners of the Hero2, they released a new firmware set, which included a new set of shooting modes collectively grouped under the name 'Protune'. Protune basically doubles the bitrate of the GoPro's recorded files to 35 Mbps, and produces a more 'flat' file with no in-camera color corrections or sharpening. And, in bigger news, they rolled the GoPro Hero 3 last night, which adds built-in WiFi, 4K video recording (albeit at 15 FPS), all packaged in a smaller-profile body...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, the Hero 3 just went on sale for pre-order, so I obviously don't have one on hand yet. I was this "&lt;>" close to buying a Hero 2, but fortunately I didn't. I have the wedding of my great friends and neighbors Tal and Erick to shoot this weekend up in North Carolina, and I wanted to strap a GoPro next to the "altar" and record the vows portion from an alternate angle, so I was going to pull the trigger and buy a Hero 2. Fortunately, time kind of ran out on me, so I had to make do with borrowing <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis'</a> Hero 2. I told him I'd upgrade it to the Protune firmware while I was at it.</p>

<p>So, with that in mind, I figured I'd take Protune for a spin.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/16//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/Q3gj9EggEx/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/a2921adc180511e2a46d1231381b4837_7.jpg' alt='A #protune test of @gopro !' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='303854708114719025_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I strapped the Hero 2 to the front left bumper of the 210, and proceeded to record my drive down to Blue Martini in Brickell for my "Tuesday Tradition" shooting session over at Jive With The Band.</p>

<p>You can see the results above, and judge for yourself. I did some basic color correction and exposure adjustment in Final Cut Pro X, and exported this to Vimeo via Compressor 4 using the standard Vimeo preset.</p>

<p>The unaltered video out of the camera is very noisy. This was to be expected, since Protune deactivates all in-camera processing, including noise reduction. It's about as close to RAW video as you are likely to get out of something in the class of the GoPro. Colors were very neutral and flat. The dynamic range was increased, due to the "flat" nature of the file. At first glance, it actually appeared to be worse than the previous firmware output.</p>

<p>However, this was the expected result. Ideally, if you can't get true RAW output out of your camera, you want a file that is as untouched and as uncompressed as possible, to allow for these adjustments to be made with more precise tools present on your laptop. Which is exactly what Protune accommodates, as much as possible. Also, it does reveal the limitations of the tiny sensor in the camera. It's a noisy mess, and GoPro is definitely to be commended for developing decent in-camera noise reduction and sharpening techniques for their standard firmware. FYI, you can turn Protune off and go back to the standard modes at any time.</p>

<p>That being said, for anyone remotely interested in video, I don't recommend it. You can really make the output of the GoPro shine with Protune, using your choice of post-production software, whether it's Final Cut Pro X, or GoPro's own Cineform. Once you understand the purpose of Protune, it is definitely a winner. It gets the camera's ideas about things out of the way of your workflow, and lets you make the decisions on color correction, sharpening, noise, and so on.</p>

<p>For a $300 unit, the GoPro Hero 2 with Protune is a winner in my book. I'll be doing some daylight tests today and tomorrow, which I will post about soon thereafter.</p>

<p>As for the Hero 3? That will most likely make it into my bag in short order. GoPro, if you pick this up, I'm always game to beat around a demo unit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting video wide open.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T12:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51143544" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51143544">• 50 1.2 L video test wide open at 1.2 •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>Shooting video using the 50 1.2 L is an interesting experience, to say the least...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>One of the biggest things cinematographers and videographers, such as <a href="http://watcha3.com/">Buster</a> over at A3, have conveyed to me, is the desire to shoot at the lowest ISO possible when shooting video, preferably below ISO 1000, though I have gotten great results at ISO 1600, and I'll go beyond that, if I know the video is going to be laden with effects in post.</p>

<p>That being said, the obvious requirement to shoot at a low ISO is, lots of light. And "lots of light" in the video world, means something a bit different than in the world of still photography, for a few reasons.</p>

<p>First off, due to the nature of video, you are limited to a shutter speed, at the low end, of 1/30 second. Though, for the best results, most videographers, including <a href="http://blog.vincentlaforet.com">Vincent Laforet</a>, recommend a shutter speed of 1/50 second, to mesh better with common monitor refresh rates. So, almost by default, you are limited in your light gathering ability, when shooting video.</p>

<p>At that point, your options are, crank the ISO, open up as fast as your lens can go, or dump a lot of light on the scene. Or any combination thereof.</p>

<p>As an experiment, I chose to shoot the sequence above at ISO 320, 1/50 second shutter speed, all wide open at f1.2. As you can see, Caroline drifts in and out of the zone of critical focus on numerous occasions. However, the video quality is amazing. At ISO 320, the 5D MK II generates superb results. In reality I could have stopped down a bit, since the lighting tech at Blue Martini was kind enough to have the system running at maximum intensity at the time.</p>

<p>I can definitely recommend the 50 1.2 L for video work. It's a very versatile prime, and the image quality is amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I like Vimeo.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/i-like-vimeo/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T14:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/i-like-vimeo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="" height="" src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/46506653 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Vimeo is the superior video sharing platform, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Why?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It plays your content, and gets out of the way. Anything beyond that is up to you.</p>

<p>And yes, the plugin works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On passing on knowledge...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/on-passing-on-knowledge-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/on-passing-on-knowledge-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6552.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Roger Sanchez - A real DJ at work'" ></p>

<p>A lot of people ask me about my photos, "How did you do that?"</p>

<p>Well, truth be told, it isn't a huge secret on how I, or any other working photographer, pulls off their images...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I was having a discussion with <a href="http://ryanalynporter.com">Ryan</a> the other day, in response to my prior posting about <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera/">being more than the guy with the camera.</a></p>

<p>Ryan bought forth the term <em>agalmics</em> during our discussion. In a nutshell, agalmics is:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The study and practice of the production and allocation of non-scarce goods.</p><footer><strong>Robert Levin</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.openverse.com/~dtinker/agalmics.html'>Agalmics - the Marginalization of Scarcity</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And yes, that was an excuse to show off the shiny blockquote tag here in Octopress. Which actually ties into what I'm talking about here.</p>

<p>The internet has made knowledge of most subjects a non-scarce resource. From the implementation of the blockquote tag here on my blog, to just how the heck I composed that image of Roger that leads off the article, to the basic techniques Roger uses to mix music together in his DJ sets, the transfer of knowledge has definitely become a non-scarce resource. It's really not much of an exaggeration to say that the sum of human knowledge is online these days.</p>

<p>With a few exceptions, the directions on how to do just about anything have been documented online, and those directions are freely accessible. And if they are not freely accessible at first, some more searching will bring forth a free alternative on how to get something done. I mention that because some academic research is locked behind paywalls. However, similar research is often freely accessible, and the assiduous student can often come to the same conclusions the researchers hiding behind paywalls do.</p>

<p>But anyways, with regards to my photo work, I don't mind freely passing on the knowledge, even if I paid for it a long time ago. If I'm stingy with the knowledge, the person asking for it, if they are determined enough, will seek it out on their own, and undoubtedly discover it elsewhere. Ryan put it bluntly:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>An agalmic entrepreneur's currency is his reputation.</p><footer><strong>Ryan Porter</strong> <cite><a href='http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=20149&amp;st=0&amp;sk=t&amp;sd=a'>EDM Is the Wimpiest Youth Movement Ever? - TNL Thread</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>My reputation (other than being a scandal!) tends to lie in the direction that I am in possession of a lot of knowledge, and I have no qualms about giving it away. It's a currency that can be spent and earned just like money nowadays. And simply because people have faith that the knowledge will benefit them. Much like the US Dollar is only worth something because the world believes it is worth something. We've assigned value to it, and it is no longer based on the reserves of a scarce material, i.e. gold.</p>

<p>But unlike gold, knowledge and information are no longer scarce. It's all out there, free for the taking. Even if you do not own your own computer or have your own internet connection, you can avail yourself of free resources to get online, and access the same information a guy on his iPad next to his pool on Star Island can.</p>

<p>So with that in mind, I tend to not object if someone sincerely asks how I manage to pull something off in the photographic realm. I get something out of it, myself, personally. I tend to be a miserable rat bastard about some things, like the political system, the popularity of dubstep, ravers, fluorescent lighting, BlackBerries, and American Idol. So I guess, subconsciously, to balance out that deficit in the karma bank, I kind of get a visceral thrill when I can pass on what I've learned. That, and when it comes to photo work at least, I can only pass on the parameters of what I've done, it's up to the person I'm teaching to implement it at the right time. It's like your parents can tell you how to drive a car, but eventually you have to get behind the wheel and do it yourself. And once you are behind the wheel, it's a lot different than when Mom told you not to stomp on the accelerator.</p>

<p>And as far as someone using that knowledge against me? Well, I don't see it as being used against me, since I really don't play that game. If someone takes what I've showed them and apes my style, and gets more work than I do, that's fine. Even if they don't acknowledge where they learned it from. Recognition and attribution are nice and "proper internet etiquette", but I don't expect it these days. I figure it is something they have to live with. And I'm really not in the recognition game, either. If what I do helps a friend or a client do well, I usually get taken along for the ride. There's a lot of things at play out in the world that are way more powerful than myself, and I figure it's easier to just ride the wave and catch a ride, rather than try to take on those forces directly. Either way, I end up doing alright for myself.</p>

<p>With that in mind, I do plan on passing on little bits and pieces of what I know in this here blog, kind of as a way to balance out some of the more ornery aspects of it, and also just for the sake of composing my thoughts on "paper". Sometimes it'll be about photographic and video techniques I know, other times it'll be about coding this here site, and maybe on occasion some bits and pieces on the fine art of Mercedes maintenance as I learn more about that.</p>

<p>I'm on a bit of a roll right now, let me kick off the first one. In the next post. Let's keep this somewhat organized.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
