<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: landscape | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/landscape/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-22T14:23:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond nightlife...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/beyond-nightlife-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/beyond-nightlife-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<p>I venture outside of the world of nightlife in my shooting when possible. While challenging as it is to shoot in that sort of environment "my way", even more of a challenge is to take something rather common, the landscape photograph, and put my own spin on it.</p>

<p>What I like to find is a mix of the works of humans with the works of nature. So, on a drive to Key West one evening, I had it in my mind to try to capture a sunset off of one of the islands on the way down to Key West.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>One of the frustrations of that, is that it isn't always possible to get that ideal angle, simply due to the traffic situation on the way down. Unless you plan way in advance (which I should have), you have to deal with the vagaries of only having one main road the entire way. Thus you can find yourself stuck behind some slow-movers, just as that magic hour hits.</p>

<p>I was gauging an ideal destination based on an earlier trip I had made a few weeks prior. I didn't make it all the way down to Key West, but I had dropped a few pins on my iPhone's map utility, to mark a few places. The one I had in mind was close, but traffic wasn't cooperating. So, when the ideal time hit, I took a gamble and pulled over next to this bridge.</p>

<p>The wind was whipping about like crazy, to the point where I had to fight to stabilize both myself and my camera, despite a heavy-duty Manfrotto tripod. Eventually, I settled into the scene, and ended up composing the above. Much like an expert sniper, I knew I "had it" even before the RAW data worked it's way through my MK II's processors and appeared on the screen. Initially a little underexposed to preserve the sky detail (you can always adjust your exposure upwards later, it's much harder to adjust downwards and bring out detail, even in RAW), I could still see the end result in my head, which is represented above.</p>

<p>While I'm fairly new to landscape photography, I can definitely appreciate the skill it takes to get the image, both from a technical and a logistical perspective. Preparation helps, but sometimes you just have to be ready for the moment to hit.</p>

<p>I'll be posting more images in this theme as time goes on, both from my back catalog, and new works as I produce them.</p>

<p>And now a word from our sponsor...me.</p>

<p><i>Enjoy 'Islamorada Crossing'? Why not purchase a quality printed copy of it for yourself or someone special? Point your browsers over to my <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/islamorada-crossing-dan-vidal.html">print provider (click/tap!)</a> and get your copy today. Available in a whole range of sizes and finishes. Use discount code 'GZTFYJ' to get 20 percent off your final order price. I definitely appreciate the business!</i></p>

<p>Yes, even I have to eat on occasion.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
