<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: key west | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/key-west/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-27T01:43:51-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keys Standard Time.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/03/keys-standard-time/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T13:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/03/keys-standard-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648_blog.jpg" width="960" height="308" title="'Yellow Shark Channel'" ></p>

<p>I've always liked going down to the Keys, especially the Lower Keys and Key West.</p>

<p>It is one of the few places I've been to in the US where things are truly running at a different pace. No one's concerned about their latest Facebook status, what Justin Bieber said on Twitter, or what their Klout score (a rigged and meaningless metric by the way) is.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It's removed from the mainland as it were, by geography, but it's not a pig-ignorant backwater of the Ozarks populated by people who are poised to vote for Romney this coming November. You can go to Key West, relax, but not feel like you are in a premillenial timewarp. They are connected down there, they just choose not to make a big deal of it. That's actually the way I think they feel down there, "don't make a big deal of it".</p>

<p>After a fairly interesting morning of shooting photos of the Labor Day Weekend event at Space, featuring DJs AN21, Robert Dietz (a true master of his craft by the way), and Reboot (aka Frank...I always call DJs by their real names), I decided to call it off around 8 AM, get some rest, and actually go out and <em>produce</em> something photographically that day. I hadn't generated much other than nightlife-related material over the preceding few weeks, so I figured I should get to it and find an interesting slice of land to document.</p>

<p>So, I figured why not head south? I've had good photo experiences there before, and I've always made mental notes on stopping points on the way down. So around 4 PM after some much-needed rest, I jumped in the 210 and headed to the Turnpike southbound.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tipover.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Tip Over'" ></p>

<p>I like driving the Homestead Extension to the Florida Turnpike. It's fairly new so the pavement hasn't succumbed to the elements as of yet, and it's never so congested that you are reduced to driving at a crawl. You can easily cruise at 85 MPH (keep your eyes open!) and not have to fuss with slowing down.</p>

<p>After a quick fill-up in Florida City ($4.29 a gallon for premium...), I got to the Overseas Highway proper.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/overseas.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Blaue'" ></p>

<p>Now, if you want to talk about minor driving frustrations, the Overseas Highway is it. One lane, with a few passing zones, and a lot of people have a nasty habit of going below the speed limit. I'm not a speed demon, but I do like to keep up a good pace, ya know?</p>

<p>Anyways, things were progressing swimmingly. And it being Labor Day weekend, the whole stretch of the Keys was abuzz with activity. People were out boating, barbecuing, RVing, and just having a grand old time.</p>

<p>Around 7:30 PM or so, I started getting to what I consider the "fertile" photo-opportunity grounds of the Islamorada area of the Keys. I've shot there before, but this time around, the sky was extremely cooperative.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ohmy.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Oh my'" ></p>

<p>I saw the colors and cloud formations, and oddly enough I was very close to the site of my last great landscape piece at the Indian Key Channel. Now, unlike that fortuitous encounter in April, the parking area at Indian Key was packed with people, all in the long-weekend frame of mind. However, no one seemed to mind that I was setting up a bunch of photo equipment. Even a park ranger/Fish and Wildlife cop could care less, it seemed.</p>

<p>I had to work fast though. This was a random stop, yes, but I was here to shoot something. So, I set up, and got to it. The sun was rapidly descending. I know one of the rules of landscape and scenic photography is to get on-site hours beforehand, but sometimes you can't make that happen. So, you have to work with what you got.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4623.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Pylons - they go south'" ></p>

<p>There was no wind threatening to carry me off into the sea, so I had a nice stable platform with which to compose. Definitely more "colorful" than my last visit. I think I'm gonna make a little "project" out of the Indian Key channel at different times of the year.</p>

<p>Then, finally, I think I nailed it. I moved to the eastern side of "that bridge", and everything just sort of came together. The sun was below the horizon, but still, there was enough light to make the sky interesting, and the bridge became a jagged shadow across the frame. I saw it. One shot, one kill, as it were.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4648.jpg" width="960" height="1440" title="'Fire away'" ></p>

<p>This one frame made the whole trip worth the effort. They say you know you have a good photo even before you process it, and right there, I knew it. Yellow Shark Channel is officially "my spot" now. FYI, the piece above will be for sale later today at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> site.</p>

<p>I didn't end the day there though. I figured I was already most of the way down the highway, so I proceeded on to Key West proper.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/doppler.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Doppler'" ></p>

<p>I made it Key West around 10 PM. The scene was in full swing, so I parked and decided to go walkabout, as it were, and take things in. I like Key West itself. It's a modern resort town, but the whole atmosphere encourages me to relax. I'm seriously thinking about figuring out how to maintain a residence down there. It's just a different way of life, really. You can just live your life at your own pace, and not worry about the petty bullshit which seemingly consumes Americans these days. No worrying about keeping up with the Joneses, as it were. And again, it's not a cradle of ignorance. The whole area is connected and part of the world, they just choose not to get caught up in the "rat race". Maybe in my old (not that old!) age I'm turning into a bum, I don't know.</p>

<p>I did grab a few street scene images, and also scoped out a few potential "Residence B" places. I'd actually be into a timeshare arrangement if the circumstances I have in mind worked out. Eventually I suppose I'll become a burnout and just live there. It'd be kinda nice. Me, a bungalow, and a boat. Though that bungalow would be pretty high-tech. I do love my toys. And I'd get one of those covers for the 210 so it's nice and safe from the seagulls and parrots.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/sloppy.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'sloppy'" ></p>

<p>There's just a certain allure to it, you know? You can just kind of be there, do what you need to in order to provide shelter and the essentials of life, and not get caught up in the petty antics of society. Like I said at the start of this article, everyone, whether they are tourists or locals, seems to be just fine with letting things be. They're not caught up in the rat race of wealth accumulation, and are just about enjoying life, and not rotting away flying a desk somewhere. Hey, if flying a desk is your thing, go for it, but I personally have other things in mind.</p>

<p>Maybe they're on to something down there. I'll be back more often, for sure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond nightlife...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/beyond-nightlife-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/beyond-nightlife-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<p>I venture outside of the world of nightlife in my shooting when possible. While challenging as it is to shoot in that sort of environment "my way", even more of a challenge is to take something rather common, the landscape photograph, and put my own spin on it.</p>

<p>What I like to find is a mix of the works of humans with the works of nature. So, on a drive to Key West one evening, I had it in my mind to try to capture a sunset off of one of the islands on the way down to Key West.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>One of the frustrations of that, is that it isn't always possible to get that ideal angle, simply due to the traffic situation on the way down. Unless you plan way in advance (which I should have), you have to deal with the vagaries of only having one main road the entire way. Thus you can find yourself stuck behind some slow-movers, just as that magic hour hits.</p>

<p>I was gauging an ideal destination based on an earlier trip I had made a few weeks prior. I didn't make it all the way down to Key West, but I had dropped a few pins on my iPhone's map utility, to mark a few places. The one I had in mind was close, but traffic wasn't cooperating. So, when the ideal time hit, I took a gamble and pulled over next to this bridge.</p>

<p>The wind was whipping about like crazy, to the point where I had to fight to stabilize both myself and my camera, despite a heavy-duty Manfrotto tripod. Eventually, I settled into the scene, and ended up composing the above. Much like an expert sniper, I knew I "had it" even before the RAW data worked it's way through my MK II's processors and appeared on the screen. Initially a little underexposed to preserve the sky detail (you can always adjust your exposure upwards later, it's much harder to adjust downwards and bring out detail, even in RAW), I could still see the end result in my head, which is represented above.</p>

<p>While I'm fairly new to landscape photography, I can definitely appreciate the skill it takes to get the image, both from a technical and a logistical perspective. Preparation helps, but sometimes you just have to be ready for the moment to hit.</p>

<p>I'll be posting more images in this theme as time goes on, both from my back catalog, and new works as I produce them.</p>

<p>And now a word from our sponsor...me.</p>

<p><i>Enjoy 'Islamorada Crossing'? Why not purchase a quality printed copy of it for yourself or someone special? Point your browsers over to my <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/islamorada-crossing-dan-vidal.html">print provider (click/tap!)</a> and get your copy today. Available in a whole range of sizes and finishes. Use discount code 'GZTFYJ' to get 20 percent off your final order price. I definitely appreciate the business!</i></p>

<p>Yes, even I have to eat on occasion.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
