<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: redrock | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/redrock/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-08-21T12:27:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Redrock Micro.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T12:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/redrock.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Redrock'" ></p>

<p>Yesterday, I had the fortunate opportunity to work with <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Alex Martinez</a> and <a href="http://michaelraveney.com/">Michael Raveney</a> on the next spot for the upcoming <a href="http://ur1festival.com/">UR1 Festival</a>.</p>

<p>Alex, as some of my fans know, provides excellent graphic design work (including my own logo), and Michael is a prominent fashion and editorial photographer here in Miami.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>The project we were all working on was a spot for the forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>. Produced by <strong>Emi Guerra</strong> and <strong>Alex Omes</strong>, the UR1 Festival takes place during Art Basel and will combine all genres of music and art into one helluva massive party. Count me in. I should "lean" on my good friend Emi and get some of my pieces featured therein.</p>

<p>But anyways, we were all tasked to film an upcoming piece promoting the festival. Alex and Michael conceptualized it, and my task was to be the "fly on the wall" and document the making of said piece. I was the documentarian. Excellent. However, I didn't relish the thought of hours of holding my MK II at arms length.</p>

<p>For all the pluses of using a DSLR for video, the one major flaw is that that the DSLR form factor is entirely wrong for shooting video. Holding a front-heavy body at arms length results in very unsteady compositions. So, on the way up to Michael's studio, I popped into <a href="http://aperturepro.com">Aperture</a>. After a brief consultation, I rented a <a href="http://redrockmicro.com/">Redrock Micro</a> mount for my MK II.</p>

<p>Without getting too much into the particulars, this definitely made my life easier. The weight distribution matched that of a traditional video camera, and made my handheld jitters that much more stable. I could glide my shots through the space with ease, and not worry about having to deal with stabilization in post.</p>

<p>Some may blanch at the pricing on Redrock's equipment though. From $350 to well over $1000 depending on the options, it's not cheap. Some suggest using the Chinese knock-off versions on eBay for $150 or less, but in my experience, the Chinese knockoffs are just that, knockoffs, and are prone to falling apart at the wrong time. Live a little, and spend for the Redrock. I know I will.</p>

<p>I'll be posting some of the results after we complete the edit of the video for UR1. We gotta keep it on the down-low, you know.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts1.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts2.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
