<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: shoegazing | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/shoegazing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-10-10T02:56:01-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The free flow of opinion.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/10/the-free-flow-of-opinion/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T23:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/10/the-free-flow-of-opinion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4655.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Above The Indian Key Channel Bridge - hey it is symbolic of the article'" ></p>

<p>For those of you who maybe only know me through this blog, I also am responsible for the operation of a little web forum called <a href="http://talknightlife.com/">Talk Nightlife</a>.</p>

<p>The reason I mention it in this context is because I actually picked up a few readers over the weekend based on my <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle/">prior post about Artwalk</a>. A Twitter user called <a href="http://twitter.com/walkwynwood">WalkWynwood</a> must have had a Google Alert set up for Artwalk commentary, and kindly tweeted out my blog post on the good and bad of Artwalk. So, I picked up a few readers who only probably know me through this blog, and not the scandalous "TNL".</p>

<p>TNL has actually been an outlet of mine for five years, as of next Monday. It is probably the only nightlife-related resource on the internet not nominally subject to the whims of advertisers.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As a little bit of a backgrounder, TNL was founded in September of 2007, by refugees from another nightlife website, the now-defunct Cooljunkie. In existence since 2000, "CJ" (we love our acronyms!) was an independent site about Miami and South Beach nightlife and culture, founded by two English expats and <a href="http://ryanalynporter.com">the guy who helped me put this blog up.</a> It was actually a blog before blogs were blogs. And there was a notoriously popular forum component. I was bought on in mid-2001 as an itinerant photographer/writer. Unpaid at first, though the sites founders, Nick and Sarah, actually promoted the hell out of me and got me work as my unofficial "agents". It was a fair trade in my mind.</p>

<p>Unlike most web projects, there was a final payoff. In 2005, CJ was bought out by out-of-state rival Clubplanet, aka "CP". Owned by the now-defunct Track Entertainment, CP was a national web forum about nightlife and clubs, with their focus city being New York. There were a few articles in there but no one really bothered to read them. Much like CJ, the popular part of CP was the community aspect. CP bought out CJ because CP wished to have a Miami presence, and and we at CJ kept stopping them. The Miami clubs (our advertisers) were very loyal to us. So, the old logic of "if you can't beat 'em, join 'em", kicked in. CP made us an offer we couldn't refuse (payouts, equity in Track, and continued paid employment) and suddenly we found ourselves with corporate patronage.</p>

<p>Initially the operations continued as is, but with a budget. CJ was maintained as a business unit of it's own, and we were free to keep doing business, as it were, but with funding. It seemed ideal.</p>

<p>However, reality soon reared it's ugly head. CJ had a very active forum community component. Around Miami, it was feared by club owners, DJs, and promoters. Ugly secrets about nightlife routinely got out on the forums, much to the chagrin of the venues, some of which were advertisers. And even though you can't un-ring a bell, we routinely censored or deleted posts that could cast our key advertisers in a bad light. Editorial and community definitely were not separate from advertising. And, we couldn't maintain without these advertisers.</p>

<p>As time went on, eventually the corporate powers-that-be in New York wanted to take direct control over the Miami operations of CJ. That, and a few other things I'm not at liberty to mention (it went all the way to federal court at the end...), led to myself and the key players in CJ to depart the company, without being able to take CJ with us since it no longer was ours.</p>

<p>So, through a few machinations, we ended up under the corporate umbrella of one of the rivals to Track in the entertainment and media space. And thus, it was decided, with their patronage, to explicitly fund and found a website to counter the influence of CJ that we had built. Basically, we had to build something to destroy something else we built.</p>

<p>So, after a little thought, we realized that the most popular part of CJ was the forum, by a factor of four. People didn't go for the articles or even my photos, it was the community part they liked. They liked to be able to post their thoughts, and read the thoughts of others. The more controversial, the better. So, with that in mind, Talk Nightlife was born in September of 2007.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tnl.jpg" width="960" height="632" title="'TNL'" ></p>

<p>Initially, we had the goals, and the requirement from the powers-that-be above, to get some advertisers on board and pay for the investment made to bring the website to life. There was a forum component, a guide to local events, and my photo gallery. And our mission was to keep it as open as possible, since it's what drew people to the site ultimately.</p>

<p>However, it did prove to be a very tricky, and ultimately unsuccessful balance. Advertisers simply weren't interested in being on a site where, a few lines down, there were statements that weren't necessarily supportive of them. The Opium Group, for example, would not place an ad, since they were regularly subject to criticism within the site. The whole "user-generated content" statement didn't hold water with them, since it was expected that us site operators would put our bank accounts before our principles, like good Americans.</p>

<p>After awhile, TNL as a financial priority fell by the wayside. Other web projects financed by the investor in TNL started to bear massive fruit, and took a lot of the pressure off of TNL itself. The investor only really cared that we made money for the "department", not that specific projects made money.</p>

<p>And besides, TNL was accomplishing one mission goal, to sink and destroy CJ, which it did admirably. CJ was rendered defunct, useless, and irrelevant to the discourse in nightlife. TNL slid into a parking orbit, and became the "drama magnet", where it remains today, and is arguably the least-restricted source of nightclub news on the internet.</p>

<p>Now, without a steady source of income (there are advertisers but the ads are usually in-kind or severely discounted), how does the site exist? Well, the site itself costs next to nothing to run. Hosting is inconsequentially cheap, and the maintenance performed by myself and Ryan is negligible. The only screwups are on the side of the hosting service, and we just wait those out. And, the investors lost interest in the site long ago, so there it sits. TNL only really keeps ticking over through a fortuitous set of circumstances. Ryan and I only keep it running because it's an interesting social experiment, and a distraction from our more mundane tasks. And I personally consider it a necessity in the nightlife industry, someone has to provide an unrestricted outlet.</p>

<p>Now, it's not to say TNL is uncensored. It's "self-censored". Each and every user has the ability to edit their own posts if they choose. Clubs could, in theory, pressure users directly to edit their words, if it came down to it. Now, the interesting thing is, since the advent of Facebook and Twitter, clubs focus almost exclusively on those, leaving old-style forums like TNL off their radars. I suppose I should thank Facebook for taking the heat off of us.</p>

<p>However, the question on occasion does come up, are we interested in making money off of the site? The usual answer is no, since we know that if the site is "monetized", eventually advertisers, even if they aren't directly insulted, will object to being placed close to controversial content. While TNL is self-censoring, as I mentioned, most people choose not to censor themselves. Insults, defamation, and even outright hate speech happen on TNL. It's the price of freedom I guess. I personally couldn't see a well-known advertiser like Bacardi wanting to have an ad positioned near the postings of someone who regularly ridicules minorities. Yes, there's someone on TNL who does that. We don't censor him, the community does. But the posts still remain.</p>

<p>So, TNL essentially remains free because we're choosing to not use it to make money.</p>

<p>Which begs the question, can a truly free source of information exist, and still make a profit? Or are truly free sources of information condemned to always operating at a loss, relying on the charity of others to merely exist?</p>

<p>With that in mind, I think we're at a point now in the evolution of the internet, where this is actually less and less of a question. It does not cost much money to operate a site. This blog is a perfect example of it. It is hosted on <a href="http://heroku.com">Heroku</a> which is a platform-as-a-service provider. They provide the infrastructure, and I provide the application, which, in this case, is this blog. Heroku lives in the cloud and charges me for only what I use. This blog is currently so low-impact I have yet to incur a fee. I'm not privy to why Heroku does this, but it may be a remnant of the <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was/">community spirit</a> which characterized the early days of the modern internet era, or it might just be too much damn trouble to monitor usage as such a fine-grained level, so it's easier to let me squat here for free rather than charge me. And the actual pretty pictures are hosted over on <a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/">Amazon S3</a>, which is another large-scale cloud effort, and my storage bill is less than a dollar so far. And, this blog is powered by <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, which is a free, open source blog platform. The breaks there are that there is no formal support or upgrade structure. The programmer of Octopress has no obligation to help me out.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, computing resources and storage are so cheap that maybe nowadays, uncensored and free channels of expression are easier to justify? Cheap hosting, cheap storage, and cheap or free publishing mechanisms. If TNL ever got the rug pulled out from under it, would it be as big of a disaster as some think? I used to think so. We went through the disaster once when we transitioned from CJ to TNL. It took awhile and a fair bit of investment to get the community to move over and to get everything pointed in the right direction. But that was 2007. Nowadays, a TNL-like service could be tossed up for a negligible investment, to the point one person could do it, without requiring a business plan or a way to make back the few dollars per year it costs to run.
Hm, maybe the community spirit is still around in a way. That's something. Whether it's about something inconsequential like nightlife, or something meaningful like politics, war, or social causes, truly free information outlets are necessary to a society that wants to call itself free. In my mind, the free flow of thought and ideas is more important than the balance sheet. Even though in today's society it's very difficult to put your ideals above your daily needs. Ideals don't put food on the table all the time.</p>

<p>And yes, this was my non-angry blog post for today. I don't think I got that worked up, did I? And happy fifth birthday Talk Nightlife. You're my contentious little foster child. Also, if you're of a mind and interested, we're putting together a little shindig somewhere on the 28th of September. Keep checking <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=3&t=20004&st=0&sk=t&sd=a">this thread on TNL</a> for details. It's not an official event since we don't do official anything. Oh, and sign up if you want. Just mention you read about TNL on here and I'll process the login right away.</p>

<p>Sidebar (because it is how I write on this blog): Certain details about TNL I've left intentionally vague. Why? Well, anyone with half a brain knows who was originally behind TNL and who put the money in. However, the general feeling at the time was that their involvement be minimized in public, and it was never discussed further as time went on. Those requests still remain in force from where I sit, even if the investing parties don't remember or don't care. I'm "having some class" with regards to that. I'm definitely grateful for their initial involvement though. I got to help raise a bastard child of a website. If I hear otherwise, I'll let you know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
