<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: the internet | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/the-internet/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-10-13T02:31:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How it was.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T12:24:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lynx.png" width="960" height="588" title="'Lynx'" ></p>

<p>Telnet, Gopher, Lynx.</p>

<p>This is how was way back when. The Web was in it's infancy, and the Internet was still largely the province of academia, the government, and disinterested large corporations.</p>

<p>And it was great.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Now, I'm not going to turn this into a rant of how awesome things were back in the day, even though they were. Don't get me wrong, the advancements in the technology of the internet have been amazing over the past twenty years. The sum of human knowledge can be accessed from a small device that fits in my pocket, regardless of whether I am at home, or 30,000 feet above the midwestern United States. I can transmit and receive photos, audio, and video in realtime from anywhere in the world. Through social networks, I can keep in touch with my friends easily, and even the technophobic can post media of their life events, easily. It's amazing if you think about it.</p>

<p>However, along the way, I think we've lost something. The internet used to have more of a community spirit to it. During the initial move from academia and big business providing access, to the period of time when the hometown ISP reigned supreme, there was an undeniable pioneer spirit online. People were developing technologies and doing things not just for the sake of a payout, but for the betterment of the community as a whole. You could post up a page of your thoughts and ideas and content, and not have to worry about monetizing it or gathering followers on someone else's social network. You ran "your thing" from top to bottom, and ideas and advice were just an email or forum posting away if you didn't know how to do it. Trade and barter were strongly encouraged. You would help someone figure out how to post an inline image on their website, and they in turn would help you post up an audio file on yours.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ns10.jpg" width="960" height="720" title="'NS'" ></p>

<p>It was all quite community-oriented, but we also knew that we needed to make a few bucks to put food on the table and that sort of thing. But the overriding spirit was very 'community', but not to the point of being in someone's business 24/7. You could ask for help if you needed it, but in general if you wanted to be left alone, you were.</p>

<p>I think they called it 'common courtesy' or manners. I think along the way since then, we've lost that. I'm not talking about the trolls really. Trolls have been with us since the early days, even before Goa Tse and rotten.com. Don't google those if you can help it. But, people generally kept out of your business, and didn't spam or otherwise harass you.</p>

<p>A good example happened to me this morning. I had a meeting with a friend of mine at his office in Downtown. When I arrived, he was madly typing away on his laptop, shaming in public as it were, one of his subordinates for spamming his Facebook wall. For reference, my friend is a marketing head for a major nightlife concern. What had happened was several of his promoters had posted promotions repeatedly on his wall, without regards for placement or realizing that there really was no need to do so, since he was the one who ordered the promoters to get to work. But, in my mind, it represented the long-term decline of common courtesy on the internet. Now, everyone's free to speak their mind. This is one of the hallmarks of the internet, you can speak your mind and reach millions with one gesture. However, with that power has come a simply staggering amount of noise. And most of that is simple discourtesy, greed, and hubris.</p>

<p>Everyone is free to make a buck. That's fine. I like to have some money in the bank myself. However, acquiring money at the expense of the ethos of the modern internet doesn't sit well with me. You can get your message out without resorting to underhanded spam tactics and outright data theft. Sadly, in nightlife and entertainment, people think nothing of hijacking other's contacts and private data, all in the name of making one more dollar. Promoters think nothing of co-opting your personal information, just to make you one more bit in their marketing database. It's why my current business cards only have my name and website on them. From there you have to jump through a few hoops to get ahold of me. My work speaks for itself, and I'd like to think that if you are really interested in working together, you will go through an extra two minutes of thinking to get ahold of me.</p>

<p>But, most people don't think this way. In the pursuit of the almighty dollar, the little things have been lost. The internet isn't a liberated medium of free expression anymore. It's been co-opted into a rapidly-centralizing mishmash of meaningless social media metrics (better get those likes, kids, before your Klout score slips one-half of a point and you are no longer relevant!), intrusive advertising, and infestations of the lowest common denominator. In other words, it's much like television, except you have the illusion of being able to talk back.</p>

<p>Listen, I know there's controls and filters and so forth. I use them extensively. However, with the breakdown of respect and courtesy online, people strike a pose to get through those filters, then it's a veritable spam rodeo.</p>

<p>I know at the end of the day, we're not going to return to the glory days of yore. They are gone, I can accept that. I also accept that two-thirds of the internet is now populated by spammers, snake-oil salesmen, and egocentric social media addicts. It's kind of why I established this little platform of mine. From top-to-bottom, from source to syndication, this is all under my control. Facebook, Twitter, Google, and Foursquare have no control over this platform unless I give it to them.</p>

<p>At the end of the day though, I hope there is some shred of decency left in us all, and we can kind of steer ourselves to a happy medium, where people can converse and share and conduct business, all without being unreasonably intrusive upon each other.</p>

<p>And yes, I know the irony is that I'm going to share this post on Facebook. I never said social networking was useless...</p>

<p>To quote my friend <a href="http://facebook.com/playgroundlouis">Louis Diaz</a> - <strong>"Have Some Class!"</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
