<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: canon | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/canon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-11-20T00:38:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More on the Canon 50 1.2 L]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/more-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T11:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/more-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/09/27//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QEfxiVggDY/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4c65b4c0087411e2bfbf22000a1e9be6_7.jpg' alt='Testing 50 1.2 L - insane. #bokeh #w210 #305 #brickell #designdistrict' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='289496019622822104_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I took a little drive around last night to further test and experiment with my new Canon 50 1.2 L.</p>

<p>This time, it was more to test the shallow depth-of-field characteristics at <em>f1.2</em>. Again, at that aperture, your zone of acceptable focus is quite shallow.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7868.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'E320 W210 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>As you can see here, the hood ornament on my W210 is only partially in focus. The central part of the left spoke is sharp, with the left circular part of the ornament fading into a rather pleasant blur. And the distant background exhibits the smooth bokeh this lens is known for.</p>

<p>Now, this was shot handheld with autofocus engaged. So, this shot is technically a little "off".</p>

<p>At such shallow depths-of-field, every movement counts. If you drift forwards or backwards even slightly, your zone of acceptable focus will change noticeably.</p>

<p>However, this is only noticeable to a great extent when one is doing closeup macro-style shots of objects. The tolerance is a little different at a longer range, as you can see here with this image I took of a <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car2Go Miami</a> Smart Fortwo in Brickell.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7865.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Car2Go Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Images like these, at a standoff range, can be done handheld, since the further away you are from your object, the less shallow your zone of critical focus becomes. You can do it handheld, that's for sure. That being said, sometimes it's not always practical to use a tripod. So, the best you can do in these situations is focus manually, and stay very still. Sounds simplistic, but in the case of street photography, you can't really overproduce a shot, in my mind.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7879.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Street Graffiti Design District Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>The advantage of digital, of course, is that you can take as many images as you need, to get the desired image. This photo below, I initially did with autofocus. Of course, the results were a little off. However, when I manually focused, crouched down, and took three shots in succession, I landed the one I wanted. Not "spray-and-pray" but a small three-frame burst to insure I got what I wanted. Of course the ultimate insurance would have been using my tripod, but at 3 AM in Miami's Design District, breaking out equipment at a grand scale isn't advisable.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof_rev-7894.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'W210 Design District Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Not out of any sense of danger really, but more out of a sense of "It's 3 in the morning and I don't want to rig up a tripod for a test photo..."</p>

<p>So, in a nutshell, if you are going to shoot with this at it's most shallow depth-of-field, I definitely recommend using a tripod, as well as focusing manually, if you are shooting your subject at close range. If you stand off a bit, it becomes less of a problem of course since your zone of acceptable focus becomes correspondingly wider.</p>

<p>But, with these characteristics in mind, the 50 1.2 L is definitely a worthwhile addition to any photographic arsenal. Everyone needs a solid 50mm prime lens, and this is the most solid one in it's class on the market.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some thoughts on the Canon 50 1.2 L lens.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24/some-thoughts-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l-lens/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T22:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24/some-thoughts-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l-lens</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/09/24//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/P-xQvYggJh/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/e540a00406b411e28a2c22000a1d0378_7.jpg' alt='Action @clubspacemiami w @djlouispuig @sharam @jhartlein @rzo4423 @brittanyviolin @pluckster more at http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/the-louis-puig-marathon' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='287884080866001505_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>Well, today was a bit contentious. But in a good way. My prior commentary on the <a href="http://edmsnob.com/">EDM Snob</a> revealing himself generated a fair amount of buzz, and also some direct emails to me. Some agreed with me, some didn't, but the magic was that they went through the trouble to email me and their replies were well-prepared and thought out. Even if you think I'm wrong, I always appreciate a well-crafted message. To quote my friend <a href="http://pingup.com/">Dade</a>, "It's the nuances I appreciate..."</p>

<p>That being said, I'm sure my benign lens review will generate far less controversy and commentary. I spew forth about the de-anonymizing of some guy in the dance music scene and it's game on. I post an educational piece and I get one reply.</p>

<p>Anyways, let's be an agalmic cowboy and balance out the karma bank a bit.</p>

<p>I recently decided to live a little and invest in a 50 1.2 L prime lens from Canon. This is currently the fastest lens that Canon currently produces. With a maximum aperture of 1.2, this lens can practically "see in the dark".</p>

<p>I'm not going to bore you guys with MTF charts and line pairs per mm comparisons. It's been done. This lens has been around for about a decade now, and the scientific reviews have been done and done again. Instead, I'm going to speak about my personal experience with this lens thus far.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lpm-7530.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Jordyn 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>I picked it up used from <a href="http://adorama.com/">Adorama</a> for a shade over $1200 US total. Adorama rated the condition as "E+" which basically means it was probably a floor demo or something to that effect. The date code has the construction of this specific copy of the lens of sometime in 2008. Now, according to most photo bloggers, the date code matters little, since typically high-priced pieces of glass sometimes can sit for years before they ship out to retailers, or in fact sit on the shelves of the retailers themselves for awhile. So, even though this copy is almost 5 years old, it arrived looking as fresh as the day Canon made it. Adorama of course inspected it and cleaned it, but you can still tell when a lens has been taken care of. Included was a front and rear cap, and even the lens hood, which is normally a separate item.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/09/21//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/P2XI_QAgFP/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/02677ac4042411e2bea81231381a404b_7.jpg' alt='L.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/hefe'>Hefe</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='285517399124476239_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>The build quality is consistent with the other L-series lenses by Canon. Metal housing and mount, and a great deal of weight. This isn't a light lens by any stretch. The main reason I bought this, other than the fast 1.2 maximum aperture, was the build. Shooting clubs and events can beat up your gear, so I don't like to take chances.</p>

<p>Case in point, a few years ago, I owned the Canon EF-S 17-55 2.8 IS lens. A wonderful piece of glass in it's own right, this was the "L" lens of the EF-S (crop body mount) lenses. However, it didn't have the build quality of a true L lens, and after about a year, the IS mechanism failed on it. Rather than repair it, I sold it to <a href="http://keh.com">KEH</a> and got a credit towards my current ultrawide angle champ, the 16-35 2.8 L, which has served me faithfully for over six years now.</p>

<p>If you shoot in any sort of environment that could be considered "rough", buy your glass accordingly. It might seem strange to pay $1200 for a fixed focal length lens, but the build quality will save you money in the long run.</p>

<p>However, all the build quality in the world matters not, if the lens itself does not perform.</p>

<p>And perform it does.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lpm-7442.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'DJ Louis Puig of Space Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>The color rendition is amazing. Vivid, though accurate, with very little chromatic aberration, which can be fixed in post if it bothers you that much. The sharpness is unrivaled by any other 50mm prime I've tried, whether it be the Canon 50mm 1.4, or any number of third-party primes in that class. L glass is simply in a class of it's own. At it's max aperture of 1.2 your subject is decently sharp. The sweet spot for this piece of glass is from around 2.8 and up to f8 in my experience. This is simply a superb piece of prime glass.</p>

<p>However, shooting with it can be a personal challenge. Unlike it's bulkier, more expensive cousin, the 85mm 1.2 L, the 50 1.2 L has a decent autofocus mechanism. Your AF will land all the time, every time, where you want it. This is dependent on your body though. The 5D MK II I use isn't known for having the best autofocus, but I have my ST-E2 with it's assist beam to help things along. I landed my AF almost every time. Now, with that being said, I was experimenting with shooting at the max aperture of 1.2 a lot of the time.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/roland-7199.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Roland at Gryphon 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Even at lesser ISOs than 6400, at 1.2 you are letting in a lot of light. Of course the tradeoff is that your depth of field is insanely shallow. Using a handy <a href="http://www.dofmaster.com/dofjs.html">depth-of-field</a> calculator, you can see that it is around <em>.07 feet</em> at the distance I took the above photo of Roland at. So, not much to work with. Some not used to this shallow DOF blame the lens. It's not the lens, it's you. It's just real challenging to shoot at that shallow depth of field and land your shot properly. You will need to take multiple images and also, if possible, advise your subject to stay as still as possible. If they move, your composition can be thrown off as your specific focus point can move out of the acceptable area of focus.</p>

<p>Though it is the challenge that makes it fun. While you might have a lot of throwaways at first, after time you will get used to the unique qualities of this amazing lens. I haven't used it consistently enough yet, but now that I own a copy, I know I will get better with it over time. I've already landed quite a few unique images because of this, and I know I will do more as I get acquainted with the properties of this lens. Having the capability to go that shallow with your depth of field can yield some amazing results, whether you are in a nightclub environment, or a controlled daytime situation.</p>

<p>Even with the challenges of shooting with it, I can definitely recommend this lens. You can save a lot of money by buying it's cheaper cousin, the 50 1.4, however, the faster aperture and superb build quality of the 50 1.2 L will make up for the savings over the course of time. L glass is for a lifetime, and investing in it is definitely worth the effort.</p>

<p>Check out my <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/the-louis-puig-marathon">last two</a> <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/roland-returns-to-gryphon">galleries</a> over at <a href="http://seenightlife.com/">See Nightlife</a> for more example images using this lens under real-world, less-than-ideal conditions. I will definitely be posting more examples of what this lens can do as time goes on, including on how this is ideal for video.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best camera is the one you have on you.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/the-best-camera-is-the-one-you-have-on-you/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T02:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/the-best-camera-is-the-one-you-have-on-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://gallery.photo.net/photo/1232337-md.jpg" width="766" height="504" title="'Miami 2000'" ></p>

<p>The above is one of my favorite images that I've taken. The gear used consisted of a $200 Pentax ZX-5n film SLR, a roll of $8 Fuji 400 film I bought in a drugstore, and an $80 chunk of Sigma glass with no special features other than a macro function. It shows the Metromover tracks near the original location of Club Space, looking south towards Brickell. This was prior to the AA Arena, the "Biscayne Wall" of condos such as Ten Museum Park, 900 Biscayne, The Everglades, and so on, as well as more recent additions like The Marquis. Almost a Miami of old at this point.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, I managed to capture the subtle tones of the sunrise and the remnants of the evening mixed with the street and track lighting. Kind of an early attempt at my current fascination with scenics, I guess.</p>

<p>Without my description, most would have guessed I captured this with a decent digital SLR, or if they had an eye for Miami and the time depicted, a fairly top-of-the-range film body and lens. The reality is, I grabbed this frame with less than $300 worth of equipment. On film. Most club photographers have never touched film. I still have to take action on this, but one of these weekends, I'm going to shoot a few rolls of film at Space for the hell of it.</p>

<p>A lot of photographers, professional and otherwise, are victims of gear lust. Sure, I am too, but since I got started, I always tried to hold true to the ethic of "The best camera is the one you have on you".</p>

<p>It's akin to what is taught in military academies around the country, "You go to war with the army you have, not the one you want". You are basically limited by your situation and your budget. Budget, obviously, because not every working professional can justify or afford a 1-series Canon body or a Nikon D4. And situationally, since it isn't always practical to carry around a large digital SLR and several lenses everywhere you go.</p>

<p>For the longest time, I shot with crop-frame mid-range digital SLRs. My work level and situation made stepping up to a full-frame body like the 5D MK II an unrealistic proposition. Maybe not so unrealistic, but more of me being cautious. My existing camera bodies generated superb images in my hands, and there was no pressing need to upgrade. I only finally upgraded to the 5D MK II when it made sense for me to do so, since several clients were asking for video work, and the 5D MK II made the most sense for my shooting style. And even then, the 5D MK II was a three year-old piece of hardware, which still generated superb images in the hands of an experienced shooter.</p>

<p>But regardless, due to the situation I was in at the time, I lacked independent transport. I took the bus everywhere. And I bought my SLR kit with me, out of necessity, since I'd often be on my way to or from a shoot. Even if I wasn't specifically shooting something, I always feared I'd get a call-up to shoot something right away, and my gear would be several bus rides or an expensive cab journey away, if I didn't have it on me. Very cumbersome way of conducting business. Obviously when I acquired my own independent transport, this became less of a problem as I could stow my gear in my trunk (a scary proposition in some areas), or keep it at home, but still be able to buzz back to base and snag it if the need arose.</p>

<p>However, the news or "that specific situation" doesn't always wait for me to rocket down I-95 at 100 MPH and skid over to my apartment to pick up my gear. So, the camera I may have on me at that moment is my iPhone 4s. The cameras inside phones have come a long way. The 4s is still, as of this writing, the undisputed champ in my mind, especially when coupled with decent photo apps from the App Store. One of my favorites is <a href="http://www.awesomize.com/"> Camera Awesome</a>. Developed by Smugmug, Camera Awesome has an ingenious system for focusing, exposure, as well as a basic suite of post-production tools, enabling you to crank out an acceptable JPEG in a hurry if the need arises. It also integrates with Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, and standard email.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ca.png" width="640" height="960" title="'Camera Awesome'" ></p>

<p>I've cranked out plenty of what I consider decent images using this little app. Several more exist, such as Hipstamatic and so forth, but Camera Awesome seems to be more geared towards those with a modicum of photo knowledge.</p>

<p>With this in mind, I actually don't freak out as much when I leave my MK II behind, like if I am going out to a purely social occasion somewhere and it's impractical or impolite to be carrying a giant bag of gear around, and maybe not the best idea in the world to leave it in the trunk of your vehicle. Since, I know I have my iPhone with a decent app close at hand, and know how to work with and around it's limitations. I won't be generating prize-winning work anytime soon with my iPhone, but I'm actually pretty impressed with the results. I work with the camera I have on me when the situation arises, I don't muck about wishing I bought my full-size rig. Though that being said, 95 percent of the time I do have my equipment within ten feet of me. It's the 5 percent of the rest of the time I've learned to calm down about and not worry about it. I know I can pop off a decent iPhone photo at any time if the situation demands it.</p>

<p>I'm of course not suggesting everyone ditch their SLRs for iPhones, but at the same time, don't be susceptible to gear lust. Sometimes you just need to make do with what you have. And actually, when you work with what you have, a lot of the time, the end results will surprise you.</p>

<p>FYI, if anyone is interested in seeing my attempts at iPhone photography, check out my Instacanvas gallery (prints of my Instagrams) at <a href="http://instacanv.as/pod_gram">instacanv.as/pod_gram</a>. It's cheap!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say, that's a nice camera...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/gearhead.jpg" width="960" height="203" title="'Go Pro on W210'" ></p>

<p>One of the most common questions that anyone in the photo or video industry gets asked, is, "<em>What sort of gear do you use?</em>"</p>

<p>Well, it's a reasonable question. The general public and professionals alike like to know that sort of thing, and it's a good conversation starter with anyone in the visual arts.</p>

<p>Me? What do I use?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My primary rig is a Canon 5D MK II full-frame DSLR for both still and video applications. Lenswise I have a 16-35 2.8 L, a 50 1.2 L, and a 70-200 2.8 L, all by Canon. And on the lighting end, a 580 EX flashgun (it goes pop and lights up things) and an ST-E2 wireless controller for the flash (so I can change the angle of light, etc...). And that's it, not counting a backup body. And of course some Macs for editing and heavy lifting.</p>

<p>It's a small assortment of gear, by no means a huge arsenal. Plus, when are in a more freeform situation such as an event or nightclub shoot, working with what you have on hand in a small satchel makes it far more interesting. This ethos is actually more and more common amongst professional photographers and videographers. Lenses and camera bodies aren't cheap, and it doesn't make sense to carry gear you don't use that often. So, a lot of pros on a budget and a lot who aren't, they simply rent.</p>

<p>The rise of photo gear rental house over the past decade has been phenomenal. All major cities have photo and video gear rental houses, such as <a href="http://aperturepro.com/"><strong>Aperture</strong></a> here in Miami, and online outlets such as <a href="http://lensrentals.com/"><strong>Lensrentals.com</strong></a> can ship just about any type of lens, camera body, lighting instrument, or accessory to your location overnight, and the rental rates are fiercely competitive. You can rent a $10,000 lens for a few hundred dollars a week. It's perfect for the one gig that requires it, or just plain old experimentation. I occasionally rent specialized lenses outside of my work just for experimentation. Sometimes I find a commercial use for it and end up purchasing it, as I did with the 50 1.2 L. I rented it repeatedly, and I ended up purchasing it as part of my permanent arsenal. It's also obviously a great way to audition gear you intend to buy.</p>

<p>And in the end, especially in these days when it's harder and harder for photographers and video pros to get a reasonable paycheck, every dollar saved counts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
