<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rants | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/rants/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-03T14:30:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How it was.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T12:24:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lynx.png" width="960" height="588" title="'Lynx'" ></p>

<p>Telnet, Gopher, Lynx.</p>

<p>This is how was way back when. The Web was in it's infancy, and the Internet was still largely the province of academia, the government, and disinterested large corporations.</p>

<p>And it was great.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Now, I'm not going to turn this into a rant of how awesome things were back in the day, even though they were. Don't get me wrong, the advancements in the technology of the internet have been amazing over the past twenty years. The sum of human knowledge can be accessed from a small device that fits in my pocket, regardless of whether I am at home, or 30,000 feet above the midwestern United States. I can transmit and receive photos, audio, and video in realtime from anywhere in the world. Through social networks, I can keep in touch with my friends easily, and even the technophobic can post media of their life events, easily. It's amazing if you think about it.</p>

<p>However, along the way, I think we've lost something. The internet used to have more of a community spirit to it. During the initial move from academia and big business providing access, to the period of time when the hometown ISP reigned supreme, there was an undeniable pioneer spirit online. People were developing technologies and doing things not just for the sake of a payout, but for the betterment of the community as a whole. You could post up a page of your thoughts and ideas and content, and not have to worry about monetizing it or gathering followers on someone else's social network. You ran "your thing" from top to bottom, and ideas and advice were just an email or forum posting away if you didn't know how to do it. Trade and barter were strongly encouraged. You would help someone figure out how to post an inline image on their website, and they in turn would help you post up an audio file on yours.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ns10.jpg" width="960" height="720" title="'NS'" ></p>

<p>It was all quite community-oriented, but we also knew that we needed to make a few bucks to put food on the table and that sort of thing. But the overriding spirit was very 'community', but not to the point of being in someone's business 24/7. You could ask for help if you needed it, but in general if you wanted to be left alone, you were.</p>

<p>I think they called it 'common courtesy' or manners. I think along the way since then, we've lost that. I'm not talking about the trolls really. Trolls have been with us since the early days, even before Goa Tse and rotten.com. Don't google those if you can help it. But, people generally kept out of your business, and didn't spam or otherwise harass you.</p>

<p>A good example happened to me this morning. I had a meeting with a friend of mine at his office in Downtown. When I arrived, he was madly typing away on his laptop, shaming in public as it were, one of his subordinates for spamming his Facebook wall. For reference, my friend is a marketing head for a major nightlife concern. What had happened was several of his promoters had posted promotions repeatedly on his wall, without regards for placement or realizing that there really was no need to do so, since he was the one who ordered the promoters to get to work. But, in my mind, it represented the long-term decline of common courtesy on the internet. Now, everyone's free to speak their mind. This is one of the hallmarks of the internet, you can speak your mind and reach millions with one gesture. However, with that power has come a simply staggering amount of noise. And most of that is simple discourtesy, greed, and hubris.</p>

<p>Everyone is free to make a buck. That's fine. I like to have some money in the bank myself. However, acquiring money at the expense of the ethos of the modern internet doesn't sit well with me. You can get your message out without resorting to underhanded spam tactics and outright data theft. Sadly, in nightlife and entertainment, people think nothing of hijacking other's contacts and private data, all in the name of making one more dollar. Promoters think nothing of co-opting your personal information, just to make you one more bit in their marketing database. It's why my current business cards only have my name and website on them. From there you have to jump through a few hoops to get ahold of me. My work speaks for itself, and I'd like to think that if you are really interested in working together, you will go through an extra two minutes of thinking to get ahold of me.</p>

<p>But, most people don't think this way. In the pursuit of the almighty dollar, the little things have been lost. The internet isn't a liberated medium of free expression anymore. It's been co-opted into a rapidly-centralizing mishmash of meaningless social media metrics (better get those likes, kids, before your Klout score slips one-half of a point and you are no longer relevant!), intrusive advertising, and infestations of the lowest common denominator. In other words, it's much like television, except you have the illusion of being able to talk back.</p>

<p>Listen, I know there's controls and filters and so forth. I use them extensively. However, with the breakdown of respect and courtesy online, people strike a pose to get through those filters, then it's a veritable spam rodeo.</p>

<p>I know at the end of the day, we're not going to return to the glory days of yore. They are gone, I can accept that. I also accept that two-thirds of the internet is now populated by spammers, snake-oil salesmen, and egocentric social media addicts. It's kind of why I established this little platform of mine. From top-to-bottom, from source to syndication, this is all under my control. Facebook, Twitter, Google, and Foursquare have no control over this platform unless I give it to them.</p>

<p>At the end of the day though, I hope there is some shred of decency left in us all, and we can kind of steer ourselves to a happy medium, where people can converse and share and conduct business, all without being unreasonably intrusive upon each other.</p>

<p>And yes, I know the irony is that I'm going to share this post on Facebook. I never said social networking was useless...</p>

<p>To quote my friend <a href="http://facebook.com/playgroundlouis">Louis Diaz</a> - <strong>"Have Some Class!"</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fear of photography?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/21/a-fear-of-photography/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T12:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/21/a-fear-of-photography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ferrer-2724.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'I can seeeeee you!'" ></p>

<p>Local photojournalist and all-around good guy <a href="http://www.pixiq.com/contributors/248">Carlos Miller</a> got me thinking recently after the last <a href="http://www.pixiq.com/article/four-cop-cars-get-called-on-us">photo protest</a> he staged in front of the Miami Herald building.</p>

<p>A lot of people have a fear of photography. And I really can't figure out why. Sure, for some people I can see it. They're doing something they probably shouldn't be, and there's scads of photographic recording devices around them, which may or may not be recording their actions. I encounter it out in the clubs from time to time. I like to shoot wide, as you can see above, and I may inadvertently capture someone doing something (or someone, ba-dum-ching...) they shouldn't be.</p>

<p>It certainly isn't deliberate on my part though. Whatever transgressions you may be committing, that's your problem and not mine. I'm not out to ruin your life, since it appears that you're quite capable of doing that on your own. And no, I won't delete it. You are a noisy red smear at the bottom of the frame. And you probably shouldn't be cheating on your pretty wife in front of thousands of people and about that many cameras.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>But, that's just with crackheads in nightclubs, which, fortunately, form a small minority of our population.</p>

<p>The real head-scratcher is the people who get worked up over photography in public places. If you can see it from a public location, you can shoot it, it's that simple. I don't buy the national security bit or anything of that nature. If I take a photo of the refinery near Fort Lauderdale airport, the photo, other than a creative piece, tells me nothing. It's a collection of pipes. It won't aid a terrorist in planning to blow it up. And, if a terrorist wants to blow up the refinery, a photo isn't going to hinder or help him or her too much. It's not like in the movies where they can deduce where the 2-meter wide exhaust vent is from a cell phone photo.</p>

<p>Even more puzzling are the ordinary citizens who bring it upon themselves to get worked up over photos in public places. The photo protest I mentioned is a perfect example. In a nutshell, the ordinary citizen was a security guard, who took it upon himself to misquote the law, leading to the situation described in Carlos' blog entry. Now, a few words on that.</p>

<p>A security guard is an ordinary citizen. He doesn't have police powers. As a matter of fact, he's even more restricted from certain actions in the course of his job than an ordinary citizen is. The industry's slogan is "Observe and Report". That's about all they can do. Plus, from a pragmatic perspective, the pay scale isn't high enough to justify more than that. If I was working the front desk at the Herald, I'd either ignore it and get back to my Youtube viewing, or just kick it upstairs and let the bureaucrats in facilities deal with it. Yes, I'm being totally lazy and "not dedicated", but for $12/hr and no benefits, you're only going to get so much out of me. I'd rather spend my effort on something more meaningful, ya know?</p>

<p>Getting worked up about people shooting photos in public places is a complete waste of one's energy. There's so much more out there to expend effort on. Plus, if you think about it, the camera is ubiquitous now. If something is not recorded, that is an unusual set of circumstances indeed. In a society such as ours, there's at least one camera recording the scene at all times in any given public location. The ethics of such ubiquitous recording? Well, that's another debate entirely.</p>

<p>But such recording shouldn't be feared. If you don't want it recorded, don't put it in a public location.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We can't make art from air.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T22:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/we-cant-make-art-from-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage8.instagram.com/5ba9a3d8e32611e1a4431231381407ca_7.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Gear and girl'" ></p>

<p>I got into a discussion just now over on <a href="http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=6&t=19857">Talk Nightlife</a> with James, founder of <a href="http://soulofmiami.org/">Soul of Miami</a> about some of the trials and tribulations of the photographers and photo editors in the Olympics. I linked on over to a <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/photographers-blog/2012/08/10/click-edit-crop-or-drop/">blog post on Reuters</a> about the workflow of their on-site photo team. James' comment was that it was fascinating, but essentially <strong>"It really does not seem like they could possibly be getting paid enough for that."</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
Sadly, that is the truth. However, most of us whom are into the photo and video industries aren't into it for a big payday. Sure, income is nice, but at the end of the day, a photo career is a lot of hard work, and is often times frustrating, and the income rarely is there.</p>

<p>Sure, every guy and girl behind the lens has fantasies of one day making that 'big score', and not having to work again, but in most cases, that never happens. They might make what would be equivalent to mid-to-high five figures on average per year, but most of that money gets eaten up in taxes, reinvesting in the business, and general expenses associated with running said business. It's why if you see a photographer with a bunch of fancy non-photo-related toys, chances are that he or she probably has a second source of money, whether it's a "real job", another business that pays real money, or comes from money and happens to have a "hobby". And yes, there's always the slight chance that they scored and are living quite well off of their photo incomes.</p>

<p>Since the digital revolution, the intrinsic monetary value of photography has gone down enormously. A lot of shooters struggle to stay afloat and often have to make concessions and do other things to make ends meet. I'm a perfect example. I earn money from photography and video, but I have to tinker with websites and take on odd tasks related to the web to make ends meet. I'm very frugal but things still cost money. Also, it is a bit more costly to obtain basic health insurance on your own, than it is if you are part of a standard corporate entity.</p>

<p>It's actually why I've come around a bit on the whole government-provided healthcare issue actually. I'm for small government, but I do think one of the duties of the government is to take care of it's taxpayers. I think that if we're taken care of on a basic level by state health insurance, that would actually free us, as a people, up to take more risks in business and our personal lives. I know a lot of people with big ideas and dreams, who don't want to leave their corporate gigs, because said gigs provide the benefit of health insurance. And, obviously those corporate gigs demand a fair share of one's time and energy. But the healthcare rant is another post entirely. Hey, it's my blog, I don't have to necessarily adhere to standard editorial guidelines.</p>

<p>But anyways, society as a whole has come to devalue the work of photographers. Now, at no point has a photography career ever been a sure path to untold riches or success. Whether the workflow was analog or digital, it's always been the rare person who made their millions off of photography. And if they did make their millions off of it, chances are they are dead or pretty close to it, and the value of their work has increased by virtue of that. Suffice to say, the quickest way to increase the value of your photography is to die, preferably in a dramatic fashion.</p>

<p>All jokes aside though, the value, and the respect of the art has been diminished somewhat over the past decade. And it has been a two-pronged assault, from without, and from within. From without, it's been clients seeking the cheap way out. Even the most professional organizations expect to be able to pay only a pittance for work. A campaign that might cost thousands on the part of the photographer to execute, the client might only be willing to pay a few hundred dollars for. Of course everyone wants to spend as little as possible, but there is a point where the client base does need to remember that 'they get what they pay for'. You only pay a few hundred dollars, well, that is about all the work you will get. Someone recently offered me $50 and a bucket of booze to shoot a party. I blew them off, it wasn't even worth a response. Everyone knows I like to have a drink or two, but I won't work for that sort of thing. I have bills to pay. And $50 would not cover my own nightly expenses, as the gig was on South Beach (no Car2Go), and of course my time in post and editing.
If you want to pay me $50, I'd expect a chauffeured ride to and from the venue, and I'll probably take three photos, steal your girlfriend, and not bother delivering the edit (1 photo) until sometime in 2025.</p>

<p>And that's just the problem from without. The problem from within is almost as bad. The digital revolution has put quality imaging tools into the hands of all. For $400 or less (say, a used Drebel kit), one can obtain a quality digital SLR with a basic lens. Under decent lighting conditions, this kit can objectively shoot great images, even in the hands of an amateur. And said images could conceivably be used for commercial purposes with the right editing and post production. So, now, businesses can hire "some guy they know", or "do it in-house" (though there's nothing wrong with an staff shooter in some instances, as long as rights and releases are fair), and attempt to save a buck or two, and have "some guy they know" fix any of the problems later, or leave the fixing to some beleaguered designer at a graphic design firm somewhere. Sidebar: graphic designers hate that.</p>

<p>When confronted, the businesses and the shooters themselves will often plead ignorance, or claim that "this is the way things are now, deal with it".
Understandably, the dynamics of the digital economy have changed things, but photographers and other visual professionals do need to have an income to survive and keep providing these services to clients. If all photography was cheap and/or free, eventually there would be no photographers to generate the images clients require and need. And computer rendering of realistic scenes is far more expensive (to do right) than booking the services of a photographer, so don't try to get me there!</p>

<p>What's even worse is the lack of understanding of licensing and rights, as well. Very few businesses understand this. They treat all photographic work for them as work-for-hire, with unlimited use. To them, once the photo is taken, it is theirs. It doesn't work that way. Licensing and sale is one of the only ways a photographer can stand a chance of making a reasonable living nowadays, especially in the situations I've described above. And very few photographers understand it as well as they should. It took me awhile to get a handle on it, but once one understands the ins and outs of it, it's easy to figure out.
In this case, Google is your friend. Search for "editorial photography rate guidelines" and go from there. I'm not being lazy, there is just a huge amount of information on pricing your work accordingly. FYI, it's why a decent-sized print of mine will run you a few hundred dollars or more at <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">my Fine Art America</a> page.</p>

<p>Again, we're in this because we love to do it, not because we're seeking a route to glorious riches and untold glory. All anyone behind the lens asks for is just compensation to cover the costs of doing business, and enjoy life while we're at it. I don't think there's many photographers out there whom are greedy and driven by dollar signs. Even we like to put the camera down sometimes and take a little vacation somewhere. With a smaller camera of course, we might see something interesting along the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the audacity of scooter riders.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/on-the-audacity-of-scooter-riders/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T16:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/on-the-audacity-of-scooter-riders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/scoot2.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Scoot'" ></p>

<p>One of my pet peeves since moving here ages ago has been the scooter rider.</p>

<p>Now, I recognize the utility of the scooter. It's light, efficient, and you can stow it almost
anywhere when not in use. Plus, you don't need insurance, and LEOs tend to leave you be.</p>

<p>It is probably the last one which makes scooter riders so obnoxious...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Before I acquired my current mode of personal transport, I would either take public transit, or on occasion, have
the use of a friend's scooter. They're fun to ride, and useful for getting around the Beach and the Downtown area.
However, being that there's nothing between you and the road but your clothes, I tended to ride cautiously, knowing that
I'm not as visible as I would be in a car or truck. It was up to me to watch where I was going.</p>

<p>However, most scooter riders do not. They ride like they own the road, and expect other motorists to watch out for them.
Now, realistically, that is fair since they have the lighter and less powerful vehicle. But fair only if they are obeying the
same rules of the road the rest of us try to do. For the most part, scooter riders around here tend to weave in and out of traffic
with abandon, often in packs. You see the 'pack' phenomenon on Memorial Day Weekend, when herds of tourists rent every available
scooter on the Beach and troll Washington Avenue in packs of twenty or more, as if they were some sort of mentally-challenged
chapter of the Hell's Angels.</p>

<p>Worse yet, your average scooter rider will blame you for any of their indiscretions on the road.</p>

<p>Case in point. Yesterday, I was leaving the Publix complex on Fifth and Alton. As I eased on to Lenox Avenue into the flow of traffic,
a kid, dare I say a <em>chmak</em>, on a Vespa was closing in on me rather fast. Now, the light ahead of me was red, so myself and the drivers in front of me clearly could not
move. The scooter rider, rather than stop and join the flow of traffic as he would have been required to do, swerved to the <em>right</em> of me and
the rest of the cars in the lane, choosing to wedge his noisy lawn-mower-sounding contraption between all of us and the sidewalk. My outraged
fellow car drivers honked in protest as he wedged through, only to be met by a stream of incoherent curses and curiously random gestures which
may have passed for obscene in some far-flung nation on the other side of the world. I suppose flailing your arms about and screaming could
be considered an obscene gesture, somewhere. There's a lot of people on this planet. All the while, this kid's conveyance was still in forward
motion.</p>

<p>Someone less kind than me could have taken exception to that, actually. This is Miami, after all. The kid on the Vespa is damn lucky in that
regard.</p>

<p>Scooter riders, scoot all you want, but realize it's a two-way street. You're on a motor vehicle too. It's a scooter, not a Hayabusa.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A year back in Miami.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/a-year-back-in-miami/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T14:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/a-year-back-in-miami</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/skyline-7023_blog.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Downtown Miami'" ></p>

<p><b>Support this site! Buy a print of the Miami Skyline pictured above over at my <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/downtown-miami-2012-dan-vidal.html">FAA Gallery</a>.</b></p>

<p>It's been a year since I've gotten back to Miami. I beat to death the <a href="http://dvdigital.tumblr.com/post/9305311687/miami-versus-vegas-since-ive-been-back-people">differences between Miami and Vegas</a>
over on my old Tumblr, so I won't get into it here all over again.</p>

<p>In a nutshell though, absence made the heart grow fonder, and despite the faults of Miami, I'm still glad I came back.</p>

<p>A lot of people rain on Miami's parade at any opportunity. The "lack of culture" and the lack of "real" opportunities outside of the world of
hospitality and tourism usually factor into most people's discussions about the downsides of living in this area.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>However, if you look closer, Miami is a very young city. Founded in 1896, it is the oldest municipality in South Florida. The area was settled prior to that, but no real development occurred until then. So, as it were, the city, and the area in general, have a scant 150 years of history to support it. Cultural meccas like Boston and New York have centuries of cultural development. Nonetheless, even with the relative age of our society here, certain things considered "cultural" have definitely taken hold. Gatherings and events like Art Walk and of course the almighty Art Basel Miami exemplify this. Along with our crop of homegrown musical talent, which spans way beyond the stereotypical "Latin" sound. Groups like ArtOfficial and Spam All-Stars are in the global music scene representing the 305, as it were.</p>

<p>Now, on the subject of opportunity. A lot of people bemoan the lack of "real" companies having branches or operations here. The fact is, they do. Most major corporations, ranging from heavyweights like Xerox and Canon, to more specialized outfits like Diageo (liquor) have their Latin American headquarters here. Along the same lines, the major South American banks are headquartered here for reasons of safety and stability, and proximity to their home countries. However, it's the lack of "corporatism" in where Miami can shine. A city like Miami is ripe for the spirit of self-employment and entrepreneurship. Even educated people who choose to locate here, often start their own business in any number of fields, including "Miami typical" ones like hospitality, entertainment, the arts, and music, or even unexpected fields like software development and engineering. I personally know several local talented software developers who work from home or small office spaces on projects that are headquartered around the globe.</p>

<p>It's actually people like these who represent the future of doing things. I see cities like Miami becoming immensely popular as a living location as self-employment and telecommuting become more and more accepted and popular. And why not? Most common tasks in any business environment don't require much more than a computer with an internet connection, with the office space being a mere formality and comforter for employers. Of course, for such things to take hold, a sea change in our attitudes towards work and employment need to happen. I'll leave that for another rant entirely.</p>

<p>However, it's this unconventional environment which drew me here, and drew me back home after my absence. The travel opportunities were fun, but there's definitely no place like home.</p>

<p>Besides, being unconventional is fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
