<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gear | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/gear/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-08-28T01:09:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best camera is the one you have on you.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/the-best-camera-is-the-one-you-have-on-you/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T02:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/the-best-camera-is-the-one-you-have-on-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://gallery.photo.net/photo/1232337-md.jpg" width="766" height="504" title="'Miami 2000'" ></p>

<p>The above is one of my favorite images that I've taken. The gear used consisted of a $200 Pentax ZX-5n film SLR, a roll of $8 Fuji 400 film I bought in a drugstore, and an $80 chunk of Sigma glass with no special features other than a macro function. It shows the Metromover tracks near the original location of Club Space, looking south towards Brickell. This was prior to the AA Arena, the "Biscayne Wall" of condos such as Ten Museum Park, 900 Biscayne, The Everglades, and so on, as well as more recent additions like The Marquis. Almost a Miami of old at this point.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, I managed to capture the subtle tones of the sunrise and the remnants of the evening mixed with the street and track lighting. Kind of an early attempt at my current fascination with scenics, I guess.</p>

<p>Without my description, most would have guessed I captured this with a decent digital SLR, or if they had an eye for Miami and the time depicted, a fairly top-of-the-range film body and lens. The reality is, I grabbed this frame with less than $300 worth of equipment. On film. Most club photographers have never touched film. I still have to take action on this, but one of these weekends, I'm going to shoot a few rolls of film at Space for the hell of it.</p>

<p>A lot of photographers, professional and otherwise, are victims of gear lust. Sure, I am too, but since I got started, I always tried to hold true to the ethic of "The best camera is the one you have on you".</p>

<p>It's akin to what is taught in military academies around the country, "You go to war with the army you have, not the one you want". You are basically limited by your situation and your budget. Budget, obviously, because not every working professional can justify or afford a 1-series Canon body or a Nikon D4. And situationally, since it isn't always practical to carry around a large digital SLR and several lenses everywhere you go.</p>

<p>For the longest time, I shot with crop-frame mid-range digital SLRs. My work level and situation made stepping up to a full-frame body like the 5D MK II an unrealistic proposition. Maybe not so unrealistic, but more of me being cautious. My existing camera bodies generated superb images in my hands, and there was no pressing need to upgrade. I only finally upgraded to the 5D MK II when it made sense for me to do so, since several clients were asking for video work, and the 5D MK II made the most sense for my shooting style. And even then, the 5D MK II was a three year-old piece of hardware, which still generated superb images in the hands of an experienced shooter.</p>

<p>But regardless, due to the situation I was in at the time, I lacked independent transport. I took the bus everywhere. And I bought my SLR kit with me, out of necessity, since I'd often be on my way to or from a shoot. Even if I wasn't specifically shooting something, I always feared I'd get a call-up to shoot something right away, and my gear would be several bus rides or an expensive cab journey away, if I didn't have it on me. Very cumbersome way of conducting business. Obviously when I acquired my own independent transport, this became less of a problem as I could stow my gear in my trunk (a scary proposition in some areas), or keep it at home, but still be able to buzz back to base and snag it if the need arose.</p>

<p>However, the news or "that specific situation" doesn't always wait for me to rocket down I-95 at 100 MPH and skid over to my apartment to pick up my gear. So, the camera I may have on me at that moment is my iPhone 4s. The cameras inside phones have come a long way. The 4s is still, as of this writing, the undisputed champ in my mind, especially when coupled with decent photo apps from the App Store. One of my favorites is <a href="http://www.awesomize.com/"> Camera Awesome</a>. Developed by Smugmug, Camera Awesome has an ingenious system for focusing, exposure, as well as a basic suite of post-production tools, enabling you to crank out an acceptable JPEG in a hurry if the need arises. It also integrates with Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, and standard email.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ca.png" width="640" height="960" title="'Camera Awesome'" ></p>

<p>I've cranked out plenty of what I consider decent images using this little app. Several more exist, such as Hipstamatic and so forth, but Camera Awesome seems to be more geared towards those with a modicum of photo knowledge.</p>

<p>With this in mind, I actually don't freak out as much when I leave my MK II behind, like if I am going out to a purely social occasion somewhere and it's impractical or impolite to be carrying a giant bag of gear around, and maybe not the best idea in the world to leave it in the trunk of your vehicle. Since, I know I have my iPhone with a decent app close at hand, and know how to work with and around it's limitations. I won't be generating prize-winning work anytime soon with my iPhone, but I'm actually pretty impressed with the results. I work with the camera I have on me when the situation arises, I don't muck about wishing I bought my full-size rig. Though that being said, 95 percent of the time I do have my equipment within ten feet of me. It's the 5 percent of the rest of the time I've learned to calm down about and not worry about it. I know I can pop off a decent iPhone photo at any time if the situation demands it.</p>

<p>I'm of course not suggesting everyone ditch their SLRs for iPhones, but at the same time, don't be susceptible to gear lust. Sometimes you just need to make do with what you have. And actually, when you work with what you have, a lot of the time, the end results will surprise you.</p>

<p>FYI, if anyone is interested in seeing my attempts at iPhone photography, check out my Instacanvas gallery (prints of my Instagrams) at <a href="http://instacanv.as/pod_gram">instacanv.as/pod_gram</a>. It's cheap!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Redrock Micro.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T12:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/11/the-redrock-micro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/redrock.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Redrock'" ></p>

<p>Yesterday, I had the fortunate opportunity to work with <a href="http://deepsleepstudio.com">Alex Martinez</a> and <a href="http://michaelraveney.com/">Michael Raveney</a> on the next spot for the upcoming <a href="http://ur1festival.com/">UR1 Festival</a>.</p>

<p>Alex, as some of my fans know, provides excellent graphic design work (including my own logo), and Michael is a prominent fashion and editorial photographer here in Miami.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>The project we were all working on was a spot for the forthcoming <strong>UR1 Festival</strong>. Produced by <strong>Emi Guerra</strong> and <strong>Alex Omes</strong>, the UR1 Festival takes place during Art Basel and will combine all genres of music and art into one helluva massive party. Count me in. I should "lean" on my good friend Emi and get some of my pieces featured therein.</p>

<p>But anyways, we were all tasked to film an upcoming piece promoting the festival. Alex and Michael conceptualized it, and my task was to be the "fly on the wall" and document the making of said piece. I was the documentarian. Excellent. However, I didn't relish the thought of hours of holding my MK II at arms length.</p>

<p>For all the pluses of using a DSLR for video, the one major flaw is that that the DSLR form factor is entirely wrong for shooting video. Holding a front-heavy body at arms length results in very unsteady compositions. So, on the way up to Michael's studio, I popped into <a href="http://aperturepro.com">Aperture</a>. After a brief consultation, I rented a <a href="http://redrockmicro.com/">Redrock Micro</a> mount for my MK II.</p>

<p>Without getting too much into the particulars, this definitely made my life easier. The weight distribution matched that of a traditional video camera, and made my handheld jitters that much more stable. I could glide my shots through the space with ease, and not worry about having to deal with stabilization in post.</p>

<p>Some may blanch at the pricing on Redrock's equipment though. From $350 to well over $1000 depending on the options, it's not cheap. Some suggest using the Chinese knock-off versions on eBay for $150 or less, but in my experience, the Chinese knockoffs are just that, knockoffs, and are prone to falling apart at the wrong time. Live a little, and spend for the Redrock. I know I will.</p>

<p>I'll be posting some of the results after we complete the edit of the video for UR1. We gotta keep it on the down-low, you know.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts1.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/bts2.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'UR1'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say, that's a nice camera...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/say</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/gearhead.jpg" width="960" height="203" title="'Go Pro on W210'" ></p>

<p>One of the most common questions that anyone in the photo or video industry gets asked, is, "<em>What sort of gear do you use?</em>"</p>

<p>Well, it's a reasonable question. The general public and professionals alike like to know that sort of thing, and it's a good conversation starter with anyone in the visual arts.</p>

<p>Me? What do I use?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My primary rig is a Canon 5D MK II full-frame DSLR for both still and video applications. Lenswise I have a 16-35 2.8 L, a 50 1.2 L, and a 70-200 2.8 L, all by Canon. And on the lighting end, a 580 EX flashgun (it goes pop and lights up things) and an ST-E2 wireless controller for the flash (so I can change the angle of light, etc...). And that's it, not counting a backup body. And of course some Macs for editing and heavy lifting.</p>

<p>It's a small assortment of gear, by no means a huge arsenal. Plus, when are in a more freeform situation such as an event or nightclub shoot, working with what you have on hand in a small satchel makes it far more interesting. This ethos is actually more and more common amongst professional photographers and videographers. Lenses and camera bodies aren't cheap, and it doesn't make sense to carry gear you don't use that often. So, a lot of pros on a budget and a lot who aren't, they simply rent.</p>

<p>The rise of photo gear rental house over the past decade has been phenomenal. All major cities have photo and video gear rental houses, such as <a href="http://aperturepro.com/"><strong>Aperture</strong></a> here in Miami, and online outlets such as <a href="http://lensrentals.com/"><strong>Lensrentals.com</strong></a> can ship just about any type of lens, camera body, lighting instrument, or accessory to your location overnight, and the rental rates are fiercely competitive. You can rent a $10,000 lens for a few hundred dollars a week. It's perfect for the one gig that requires it, or just plain old experimentation. I occasionally rent specialized lenses outside of my work just for experimentation. Sometimes I find a commercial use for it and end up purchasing it, as I did with the 50 1.2 L. I rented it repeatedly, and I ended up purchasing it as part of my permanent arsenal. It's also obviously a great way to audition gear you intend to buy.</p>

<p>And in the end, especially in these days when it's harder and harder for photographers and video pros to get a reasonable paycheck, every dollar saved counts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
