<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ramblings | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/ramblings/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T16:41:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Around Wynwood For Art Basel 2012...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/08/around-wynwood-for-art-basel-2012-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T21:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/08/around-wynwood-for-art-basel-2012-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood960.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>Proprietor of <a href="http://thevagabondmiami.com/" target="_blank">The Vagabond</a> and friend of mine, Carmel Ophir, had this to say about Basel...</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Take a walk, alone... Go into the small random galleries, warehouses, and storefronts. Pick any art fair and not worry about paying the admission fee. Walk around, and take in some of the most incredible creative works in the world. Don't fret about where your friends are and what they may be doing, or what's the cool/hip place to be.<br/>We are so lucky to have such a collection and gathering of the art world at our doorstep. Enjoy it...Immerse yourself in it.</p><footer><strong>Carmel Ophir</strong> <cite><a href='https://www.facebook.com/carmelophir/posts/10152329760025065'>On Art Basel Miami</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>So, with that in mind, I set out late this afternoon...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I had some shopping to do, so on the way home, I figured I'd pop into Wynwood, park somewhere, and just cruise.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9575.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>Finding a spot just west of Wynwood, I set out on foot from my parking spot and headed east to NW 2nd Avenue, which is the heart of the Wynwood scene. Upon my arrival at 5:30, it was already a traffic horror show. If not during Art Walk, at least during Art Basel, the city needs to block off from NW 27th to NW 20th Street and restrict it to pedestrian traffic only. It's a madhouse.</p>

<p>However, the scene was already in full swing. The artists were out decorating their buildings, and the numerous local bars and restaurants that have sprung up over the past few years were open for business, and crowded. Wynwood has "arrived". It's not the 'next big thing', it has arrived. South Beach is history and falling apart, the Design District is in it's cruise phase, Wynwood has just touched down. If you plan on establishing a presence there, it's going to be expensive. Just go west by I-95. It's cheap and on the way up.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9581.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9596.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>As it was dusk, I was capturing a great juxtaposition of a very colorful sky, with the bold schemes of the galleries in the neigborhood. Magic hour, as they say. I kept it wide and just concentrated on the photo and not wondering if I should switch to my 50 1.2, due to the decreasing light levels.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9609.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9614.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Car2Go Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>Along with the artists, galleries, and their work, the usual suspects turned up for branding opportunities. Heineken was very much in attendance, and I was glad to see Car2Go making a statement as well. I'm normally ambivalent to product launches and "activations", but if it's someone I can get behind like C2G, then go for it. Yes, I'm very petty and subjective. But at least I admit it.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9641.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9663.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9743.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>Of course, the usual party cruisers were out. I guess they are here to stay, and Art Basel Miami wouldn't be where it is today if it weren't for the hordes of people jumping from one booze-soaked hangout to another. But again, I wish they'd just be honest.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9752.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9687.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Wynwood Saturday Night December 8'" ></p>

<p>And, of course, there were plenty of street performers as well. I was glad to see Miami PD left them alone, and not pulling the Beach antics of hassling everyone for a permit and a fee. South Beach wonders why it's fading into generic obscurity, and part of that is the culture is being taxed to death by the government and the profiteering property owners who seemingly triple the rent at random.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood-9711.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Asif's Guns Wynwood'" ></p>

<p>I did my part, and checked out a lot of random little galleries and one-off events. My favorite by far was <a href="http://www.primaryprojectspace.com/artbasel/asifsguns" target="blank">Asif's Guns</a>. In a nutshell, Asif produced accurate cardboard models of popular firearms, including Walther, GLOCK, H&amp;K, and the ubiquitous AK-47. It was a riff on US gun culture, and a parody of a US gun store. While I might not see eye-to-eye with him on his gun politics (he calls for more controls, whereas I advocate better enforcement of existing statutes), it was really the highlight of my little run through Wynwood. A 400-square foot setup off to the side somewhere. Carmel's advice paid off. I even bought a T-shirt. I'm sure it will be a hit tomorrow morning...</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/12/08//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S_1kyNAgL9/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/492092a241a011e2984522000a1f8ad9_7.jpg' alt='New shirt #asifsguns #armedbasel #artbasel #igersmiami #instagood' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.800851,-80.19829'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.800851,-80.19829&markers=25.800851,-80.19829&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Asif's Guns' /></a><br/>Taken at Asif's Guns</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='342227720975024893_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obligatory Art Basel Miami Post...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/07/obligatory-art-basel-miami-post-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T23:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/12/07/obligatory-art-basel-miami-post-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wynwood.jpg" width="960" height="1280" title="'Wynwood this past Thursday'" ></p>

<p>It's the first week of December, and the Miami edition of Art Basel is in full swing. The official sister festival to the world-famous Art Basel that takes place in (duh!)Basel, Switzerland, Art Basel Miami (that's a lot of Basels in a row, sorry grammarians!) is currently in it's tenth year of operation. It's done wonders for the standing of Miami's art world, but like anything Miami-related, there's a huge layer of bullshit built in...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As a note of clarification, what most people consider "Art Basel" actually consists of the official <a href="http://artbasel.com/">Art Basel</a> fair at the Miami Beach Convention Center, along with several unrelated satellite fairs such as Design Miami, and the numerous galleries in the Design District and Wynwood neighborhoods in the City of Miami hosting their own affairs. Art Basel Miami basically spawned a whole ecosystem of unaffiliated satellite events, much like Winter Music Conference did. However, unlike WMC, Art Basel is not fighting a rearguard action (sorry Bill, it's true...) with regards to these events. Art Basel basically ignores them and does what they want.</p>

<p>However, most people don't distinguish the individual events per se and just say "Art Basel".</p>

<p>This year, 2012, has proven to be the biggest Basel yet. It's Friday night and I've already noticed a huge amount of traffic on all the Beach-bound bridges and causeways, and the Wynwood neighborhood is a complete traffic disaster. One would guess that after ten years of practice, the various municipalities would have managing this down to a science. At least close the streets to vehicle traffic in Wynwood.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/12/05//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S3xzCpggF2/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage6.s3.amazonaws.com/acbccdda3f2a11e2b12d22000a9e295b_7.jpg' alt='Arty. #artbasel #305 #igersmiami #instagood #miami #wynwood' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.810598384,-80.19685341'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.810598384,-80.19685341&markers=25.810598384,-80.19685341&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='LMNT Gallery' /></a><br/>Taken at LMNT Gallery</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='339959308705988982_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>And the source of that traffic is the crowds, of course. Most of which have no real interest or idea about the art on display, or the art world in general. For the record, I'm not a huge participant in the Miami art scene, even though I've sold a few pieces. I should get out more, to be blunt. However, it isn't too difficult to see that you have the masses of people who are just out for the see-and-be-seen scene, and of course the copious amounts of free booze. Then they can tweet to their friends that they are "Baseling", of course.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/baseling.png" width="322" height="446" title="'Twitter-Baseling'" ></p>

<p>I don't decry anyone making a lifestyle of it, I know several people whose social scene in general consists of cruising sponsored events, but for the art scene in particular, it can be problematic. Artists local and global have to deal with the "freeloaders" in order to get to the 2 percent of the people who may want to purchase their art. The official Art Basel fair actually recognizes this issue and the first two days of the fair are closed to the public and only accessible to well-heeled collectors who can afford a ticket or have the industry cred (i.e. they own a gallery, etc...) to actually be there to conduct business...</p>

<p>But the unfortunate side effect, the bullshit, is that the art generally plays second-fiddle to the social scene. The art is the excuse to go out and get banged up. Hey, if I want to get banged up, I can do that with little to no justification. I do feel though for the local Miami artists, who have to deal with this extraordinary amount of bullshit just to get their work out there. Miami struggles to be recognized as an "arts" city, and when Basel comes, it's all laid bare that 90 percent of the crowd is just treating it as a hipster version of Spring Break in December. With celebrities, who actually don't purchase any of the art, anywhere.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/12/05//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S4RWiGggER/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/318a60f63f5111e2a2ab22000a1fb84b_7.jpg' alt='Watching @keprock compose his latest #artbasel  #miami #igersmiami #305' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.799291,-80.207293'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.799291,-80.207293&markers=25.799291,-80.207293&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='GTC (ClubFlyers.com)' /></a><br/>Taken at GTC (ClubFlyers.com)</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='340098087102054673_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I feel for friends of mine, like KEPROCK, whose work is Instagrammed above, who struggle to produce great pieces, and they have to struggle further just to get heard.</p>

<p>Have I voluntarily recused myself from Basel? As a potential exhibitor? Yes. I've had "real life" happening, and haven't had the time to curate and produce my own exhibit. However, discussions have happened. I'm hoping to do something next year.</p>

<p>As someone going out to check out the scene? No. I've been out, just bouncing around basically. I've avoided the big-ticket fairs, the celebrity events, and the Beachside quagmire. I have scant desire to be crammed into any venue which is flush with people doing Instagram self-portraits (har har) and checking in so all their friends get to see how 'cultured' they are. So far I've done a few Wynwood runs, ended up at <a href="http://www.thecornermiami.com/">The Corner</a> three times in one night, and somehow ended up at the Vagabond. Oddly enough in these travels, I've seen more genuine art-related goings on than in any "art" themed event.</p>

<p>If you are here for Basel, welcome. Just don't bullshit a bullshitter, and be honest. You're only here for the (free) beer.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/wood.jpg" width="960" height="208" title="'Wood iPhone Pano'" ></p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/12/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S7NTA8AgJ6/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage10.s3.amazonaws.com/9e5bfee8403611e2a23c22000a1f9d66_7.jpg' alt='Max that sensor. Because fuck you that's why. #artbasel I don't do art and I do more art than art. #waltherp99 #armedbasel' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.801305255,-80.198858322'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.801305255,-80.198858322&markers=25.801305255,-80.198858322&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Wood Tavern' /></a><br/>Taken at Wood Tavern</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='340924678078071418_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/12/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S7Vb2EggN3/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/8d7aa23c404011e2b55e22000a9f09fb_7.jpg' alt='I shoulda learned to play them drums #artbasel #miami #igersmiami #instawtf' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.788130302,-80.193521976'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.788130302,-80.193521976&markers=25.788130302,-80.193521976&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='The Vagabond' /></a><br/>Taken at The Vagabond</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='340960469256897399_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/12/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/S7bPqqggAU/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage8.s3.amazonaws.com/a5017424404711e2925f22000a1fb71a_7.jpg' alt='Hahah at The Corner @stephencutrone' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784647698,-80.193843842'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784647698,-80.193843842&markers=25.784647698,-80.193843842&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='The Corner' /></a><br/>Taken at The Corner</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='340986020654874644_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>Oh and yes, all the prior images were shot with my iPhone. It's a fun challenge maxing out the sensor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
