<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: south florida | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/south-florida/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-24T15:57:10-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruising South Florida.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/25/cruising-south-florida/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-25T11:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/25/cruising-south-florida</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p>Apparently there's a hurricane on the way. Or a tropical storm at the most. It's the usual subdued panic in South Florida. Yes, I'm aware that even a tropical storm can cause damage, and it's always better to be safe than sorry, but if the news media is to be believed, Armageddon is upon us.</p>

<p>It made for a very low-key Friday night, that's for sure. And today is shaping up to be more of the same.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Which is actually OK with me. I like to kick back and relax and do what I want rather than what I need to do. And one of those things is cruising around and shooting the deserted streets at night. In my mind, it's similar, in a way, to the scenics and landscapes I've been shooting lately. There's definitely an interesting juxtaposition with the works of humanity in the photo, but humanity itself isn't present.</p>

<p>And last night made that easy. No one was out, anywhere. I ostensibly drove north on the express lanes in I-95 to try out a new set of tires I put on the W210 earlier in the day. Bridgestone RE970s if anyone is curious. And in the rain at cruising speed, they stuck to the road like glue, even at "autobahn" speeds of 130 kph...around 81 mph or so.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage5.instagram.com/e1e54fdeee6a11e1829522000a1e88aa_7.jpg" title="'I-95 NB Express'" ></p>

<p>Of course I had my gear on me, since I intended on getting off the beaten path and shooting some deserted streets. From Downtown Fort Lauderdale to Washington Avenue on South Beach to Wynwood in Miami, it was a quiet Friday night. There were small bursts of activity here and there, but it was definitely a slow night. Which suited me just fine. I captured some excellent deserted street scenes.</p>

<p>One of the challenges, of course, was keeping my camera dry. I kind of forgot about that. However, I improvised with a plastic bag from my trunk and a musty old t-shirt to wipe away any condensation. And even though I had my trusty Manfrotto tripod with me, I handheld all of my images from the past evening. ISO 3200 and 6400. Don't fear the noise.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3454.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3462.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3473.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3476.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p>Driving Washington Avenue was fun. I drove from 5th Street to Lincoln, and marveled at all the shuttered nightclub spaces. It's really the subject of another rant, but it's amazing to see the huge seasonal turnover in nightclubs on the Beach. You think these guys would realize there's only three big players in town and only so many people to go around.</p>

<p>Anyways, it was a successful street scene shooting session. This wasn't commercially motivated, it was all "just for me". I think in the quest to stay solvent, a lot of photographers forget to go out and shoot what they want in addition to what they need to shoot. Though a fortunate few can shoot what they want and it fills their needs quite nicely. Regardless, shooting what you want is definitely recommended. It's relaxing if anything. Strip your kit down to what you need (again, don't fear the noise), get out there, and press the shutter button.</p>

<p>Be safe out there, South Florida.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
