<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: agalmic | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/agalmic/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-12-08T22:03:28-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And I Think I Was Right...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/27/and-i-think-i-was-right-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-27T01:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/27/and-i-think-i-was-right-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/juno-8223.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'By The Pale Moonlight - Available Soon For Print'" ></p>

<p>I think I was right, the creative endeavor cannot be forced.</p>

<p>This past evening, I took the 210 out for a small check ride...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Every few months or so, it's a good idea to run fuel system cleaner through your car. Most car nuts agree the only kind worth a damn is <a href="http://techron.com/">Techron.</a> Yes, I know there's <a href="http://www.basf.com/group/corporate/en/brand/KEROPUR">Keropur</a> from BASF, but good luck getting that in anything besides a 55-gallon drum. You can go to any European car dealer, and they should have it, but they'll usually try to rope you in for "service" and flat out not sell you a bottle. And the indie mechanics don't have it since demand is low. So, Techron it is. Daimler actually approves of it, so it's OK.</p>

<p>Anyways, to use a fuel system cleaner, you run your tank low, and then dump a bottle into your tank, and then put 10-15 gallons of gas over that. So, on the way back from the beach today, I swung by the <a href="http://advanceautoparts.com/">Advance Auto Parts</a> shop on Alton, and picked up two bottles. Two because they're running a special - buy one at the normal price, get another for a dollar.</p>

<p>So, I went home, sorted out a few last-minute edits from the weekend, and drove out the last little bit of old gas. I dumped a bottle in, gassed up at the Chevron, and took off for the Turnpike. Why? Well, it might be a bit of a superstition, but M-B enthusiasts over at <a href="http://benzworld.org">Benzworld</a> generally suggest you give your car an "Italian Tuneup" after putting in Techron. Basically an Italian Tuneup is where you find a highway, and just go fast for a bit. Some suggest redlining even, but I'm not going to take that chance. I figured a nice cruise at autobahn speeds would suffice.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/11/26//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/ShC4zLggH0/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/a95b1cf6383a11e28a2c22000a9f15d9_7.jpg' alt='Field harmonics check. #nofilter #turnpike #florida #131kmh #w210' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=26.164295902,-80.225495204'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=26.164295902,-80.225495204&markers=26.164295902,-80.225495204&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Ali's Roti Shop' /></a><br/>Taken at Ali's Roti Shop</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='333560546739749364_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>So, I got out to the pike and turned it up to around 140 km/h and set the 210 for cruise. That's about 85-90 MPH. Yes, I'm using metric. Just because. It's my blog.</p>

<p>The cruise was great. I had my choice of music on, there was zero traffic, and the flow was smooth. No anomalies.</p>

<p>Eventually, I ended up somewhere near Indiantown Road in Palm Beach County.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/11/26//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/ShJHFzggN4/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage4.s3.amazonaws.com/42236888384211e2a95722000a9f09e9_7.jpg' alt='System check #w210 in some deserted parking lot. #florida #jupiter #moonlight #instagood #picoftheday #palmbeach' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=26.940890065,-80.194418032'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=26.940890065,-80.194418032&markers=26.940890065,-80.194418032&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Calvary Chapel Jupiter' /></a><br/>Taken at Calvary Chapel Jupiter</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='333587917089932152_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>After pulling over in a random Publix parking lot and sorting through some emails, I noticed there was a near-full Moon out. I had all my gear on me, so I figured, why not look for some shooting opportunities?</p>

<p>With that in mind, I meandered my way over to Juno Beach proper and onto A1A. The Moon was bright and the cloud cover was breaking up. I didn't intend on shooting anything, but the opportunity was presenting itself. The world fell in line, I may as well capture the results. So, I went out to the beach itself, and captured the wave action by the light of the Moon itself.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/juno-8225.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'By The Pale Moonlight Vertical - Available Soon For Print'" ></p>

<p>Autofocus and even accurate manual focus via the viewfinder was nigh-impossible. What I did was boosted the ISO to 12800, flipped on Live View, and focused on some waves manually in the distance. And then dropped down to a more reasonable ISO 640 for the actual exposure. The boost in Live View essentially allowed me to have "pseudo-night-vision" and I could gauge the focus on a wave. It worked. The image itself almost appears to be a painting.</p>

<p>Plus, it made me a fan of that specific stretch of Juno Beach. I should get a place up there. It's quiet, and has that sleepy beach-town feeling that I tend to get a kick out of. I like my beach towns to be well, beach towns. South Beach is so not that. It's so bourgeoise (so says the Benz addict, haha!) and overrun with tourists and chain stores. What unique charm it had left ages ago. I could have a bungalow in Juno Beach (or any other quiet beach town in South Florida - they still exist!) and my apt here in Miami. Hmm...</p>

<p>Nonetheless, I'm actually liking what I did tonight. And I didn't even intend on shooting anything. I didn't force the creative process. The world got in line and I captured it...I should stick to my own supposed tagline.</p>

<p>I've got some fine-tuning to do, but the two images featured in this post will be available for sale soon. In the meantime, why not <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">click here</a> and browse through what is currently for sale? It's the holidays, someone in your family will need a gift. And you can do a good deed and support my efforts...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Work with the light tech...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/13/work-with-the-light-tech-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T01:04:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/13/work-with-the-light-tech-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/mark-6094.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Mark Knight at Space November 2012 with light tech Dennis Perez'" ></p>

<p>One of my favorite DJ/Producers, <a href="http://www.djmarkknight.com/">Mark Knight</a>, stopped in at Space this past weekend for a little eight-hour set on the decks. He's got the idea of being a DJ down pat. He mixes in his own material and edits, with a good dose of anything that will make the crowd move. Throughout the night I heard everything from classic Underworld to even an INXS-inspired white label track. And he's always down for a wacky photo or two, like the one above. And, of course, I get asked 'how did I do that'?</p>

<p>In this case, it wasn't just a random happenstance of the lighting and the photo coming together...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it...</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Generally that is how I work. I wait for things to happen, as I've explained before, then I document it. However, in club life, an interesting 'counter' to my little tagline happens, in that the friendly local lighting techs will set up a specific cue, so I can capture the moment. So, I have to wonder, am I waiting for the world to fall in line if someone kind of knows what I would like to see?</p>

<p>I do appreciate the help, obviously, and it is actually not a hard feat for anyone to accomplish if they are out shooting nightlife. The trick here is, to get to know your light techs and the equipment they employ on a nightly basis.</p>

<p>When I first got started in this, I used to be a part-time light tech for my friend John's sound company. John and I, at the time, were both students over at UM, and to make ends meet, and also for the learning experience (his major was audio engineering), John ran a small sound and lighting company on the side. And I was his unofficial-official light tech, due to my experience with lighting in general, and also no one else in our crew knew the concepts. We didn't get paid much, but at the time, half the fun was just being able to get out there and do shows. We mostly did rock shows, but we also did a few dance-oriented events here and there. Nonetheless, I got to learn the basics of stage and nightclub lighting. As time went on, even after John moved back to Aspen to kick off his <a href="http://alchemyavcs.com/">massive production company</a>, I would stay current and always converse and on occasion, fill in as a tech for a lot of the local guys when they were sick, away or "otherwise indisposed". At this time (early to mid 2000s), lighting was moving from a "dedicated console" world, to a PC-driven sort of affair, especially in the nightclub industry. A $300 PC and $700 USB-DMX widget could take the place of a $20000 console in a nightclub setting. The most popular product was <a href="http://martinpro.com/product/product.asp?product=lightjockey">LightJockey</a> by Martin. In a nutshell, after you installed and connected all your fixtures, you used this piece of software and supplied USB-DMX widget, and could program and control your lightshow from any commodity PC. It is all very graphical.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/LJ.jpg" width="600" height="474" title="'Lightjockey 2.0'" ></p>

<p>There's several competing software packages out there nowadays, but Lightjockey is the most common one. The concepts are the same though.</p>

<p>And then, obviously, beyond the controller, is the entire world of the lighting fixtures themselves. Common manufacturers include <a href="http://martinpro.com/">Martin</a>, <a href="http://www.highend.com/">Highend</a>, <a href="http://www.elationlighting.com/">Elation</a>, <a href="http://claypaky.com/">Clay Paky</a>, and many more.</p>

<p>Entire blogs and sites are devoted to lighting. Obviously this one isn't. But, you don't have to be a light tech to speak the basics. The key, I've found, is to know what the fixtures are (spots, washes, scanners, strobes - all kind of self-explanatory), and the right terms for what the fixtures do (If you say 'CTO' you'll usually be taken a little bit more seriously) and what the colors and filters are, and also the basics of how a lighting scene is constructed. Also, if you don't know the tech, get to know him or her (yes, her - one of the best in the biz <a href="https://www.facebook.com/miss.allegra"> is a girl</a>.) and develop a rapport. If it's early in the night, the tech is usually just running through the motions, and will probably be up for a break in the routine. Use the opening DJ as a "practice target", and get some cues set up for yourself.</p>

<p>Now, this all kind of reeks of cheating. And, maybe it is. However, the way I can ethically justify it is now, in a lot of places, the tech will actually bring up "my" cues, without me even asking. At Space, I don't think I've asked Dennis or Gabriel for a specific cue in months. It just all falls into place. They know what will make for a great image, and more importantly, when to deploy those cues, for maximum effect on both the crowd and my image capture. We work together on it.</p>

<p>Plus, a good tech will know the flow and rhythm to the music and crowd, and having specific cues becomes less and less necessary, since the lighting will just happen. When a song peaks, you know there will be a sizable amount of strobing, for example. Or when there is a lull in the track, it could go dark, or a nice blue wash from the Platinum Beams will kick in.</p>

<p>Of course, the assumption being made here is that you are shooting in a venue that is equipped with a decent lighting rig, and, beyond that, a dedicated lighting technician. Some smaller venues still run their lighting systems on autopilot, or according to a preset schedule (Lightjockey allows for scheduled cues based on the time of day, even), depending on the needs of the venue. That being said, most places of that nature actually have a lot of practical lighting, or a good dose of ambient light. There's a lot of light out there if you know where to find it.</p>

<p>But, if the situation allows for it, definitely get to know and work with the light techs in a venue, the resultant images will be much more "meaningful" than your usual run-of-the-mill flash-and-dash captures.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm a social media sceptic and I have a blog...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/09/im-a-social-media-sceptic-and-i-have-a-blog-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-09T11:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/11/09/im-a-social-media-sceptic-and-i-have-a-blog-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/blog-5407.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'OCP'" ></p>

<p>This morning, when I woke up, a post on Facebook by <a href="http://helloimscott.com/">Scott Alexander</a> caught my eye.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>A good article for photographers and artists of any medium, really. While you're on Edin's site reading this, I highly recommend checking out the rest of his site. Great photographer with a superb eye.</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>Scott Alexander</strong> <cite>A Facebook Post</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The post linked to <a href="http://www.edinchavez.com/blog/why-should-i-start-a-blog/">an article by local photographer Edin Chavez</a>, on why a photographer should have a blog. The reasons are pretty obvious, ranging from showcasing your work to SEO, and, most importantly, <em>control</em>.</p>

<p>Now, maybe it sounds a little obsessive, but at the end of the day, having a slice of web property you control from top to bottom is important, especially if you are in the creative field. And, unfortunately, there's quite a large amount of creative types who don't have a web property that they explicitly have ownership of. I know more than a few working photographers who only use social media to showcase their works, for example. This can be dangerous.</p>

<p>I'm a "social media sceptic". I've been on the internet in one way or another since 1992, around the time the World Wide Web was born. And yes, there was an <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/08/22/how-it-was/">internet before then</a>. My dad was/is a network engineer, so we always had some form of basic online access. In general, we passed on the walled-garden online services of the day like AOL, Compu$erve, and so on. I actually preferred local dialup BBSes, which, in a way, were primitive social networks.</p>

<p>You could post up content, chat with other users, and transfer files around. It was basically a text-mode Facebook, if you think about it. However, after a few years, the era of the BBS faded, replaced by easy internet access and the rise of consumer usage of the WWW. Once people got situated and used to "dot com", soon after came the rise of user-provided content, i.e. the first blogs. Blogging was around before the term was coined (a lot of personal websites had a running journal of the owner's thoughts...), but with the advent of primitive <a href="http://www.movabletype.org/">CMS</a> systems, publishing content became a trivial point and shoot exercise. Then, of course, that was extended into social networking as we know it. Friendster kicked off the craze, then MySpace, then proceeding on to Twitter and Facebook, with of course Google constantly on the move to be "the" internet.</p>

<p>However, through all those trends and sea changes, the ability to host and publish your own content on your own web property has remained. I know a few "social media managers" (the title is largely meaningless), and their biggest challenge is keeping up with the trends in services and platforms. Today it is Facebook, tomorrow it could (hopefully) be <a href="http://join.app.net/">app.net</a>, or a move to the <a href="https://joindiaspora.com/">Diaspora</a> model of community-run distributed social networking. Nonetheless, it's a lot to digest and keep up with. It's the nature of the beast, as it were.</p>

<p>And therein lies the problem. I see a lot of people who rely and base their businesses on a specific form of social media. A few years ago, I knew people who made businesses based on doing MySpace profile templates, and they acted as if it was their gateway to untold riches. Now, you have companies building applications around Facebook, acting in much the same way. With the cyclical trendy nature of social media, most of these companies are destined to fail, or disappear, due to their reliance on someone else's platform for their business. It's akin to relying on General Motors cars exclusively for your delivery business, rather than any operational vehicle.</p>

<p>Now, one could drive themselves crazy keeping up with these social media trends. Every so often, you have to convert and repost your content. One bulwark against that, (to bring it all home!), is having your own web property. Now, <a href="http://www.edinchavez.com/blog/why-should-i-start-a-blog/">Edin espouses Wordpress and/or Blogger</a> as a publishing platform, and I of course champion <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, but that battle is more of a technical one than a political one.</p>

<p>The key is, hosting your content on your own systems, and using social media to drive people to those systems. I know with Octopress it will be a trivial matter to write a plug-in to support broadcasting to any future social network, due to it's open-source nature. And even though Wordpress is rather closed in comparison, some enterprising developer will link WP with whichever future social network becomes ascendent. But, at the end of the day, with having your own domain, own hosting, and own content, one can make themselves immune from the often-flaky, trendy, and chaotic world of social media.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The virtues of open-source...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/29/the-virtues-of-open-source-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T13:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/29/the-virtues-of-open-source-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ruby.png" width="679" height="410" title="'Coding'" ></p>

<p>Sorry about the dearth of updates over the past few days. The wedding edit took some time, as well as real-life things having to happen as well. And then Halloween. The biggest, most interesting challenge, however, was the selection and deployment of a web application to display the edited photos from Tal and Erick's wedding...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The edit itself went flawlessly. With my MacBook Air being a completely solid-state system, the actual rendering and editing took no time at all. Any time spent was purely on creative decisions. Protip - double-check that your sensor is clean. Cloudless blue skies make for wonderful wedding backdrops, but every little dust particle shows up. And the ultrasonic cleaner will not get them all. I spent a good amount of time spotting each photo. I usually check my sensor, but my MK II has the cleaning system, so I thought nothing of it. Wrong. Dust still adheres to the sensor surface.</p>

<p>I teased the bride and groom with little Instagram previews of my progress. It was a photo of a photo, but they got a kick out of it.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/23//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/RJTU0XAgCa/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage2.s3.amazonaws.com/ba2799ba1d7311e2959322000a1e9e0c_7.jpg' alt='Your turn in the render render @simply_sarah7' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='308863042945417370_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>Finally, I completed the edit, and then had to tackle the task of how best to display the photos.</p>

<p>Now, the obvious solution would have been to just use a canned solution like Flickr, or 500 px. While both services have their strong points, the fact that I don't have direct control over my content did give me cause for concern. Plus, with my recent forays into the world of building web applications and coding, I wanted to roll my own solution as much as possible.</p>

<p>Initially, I wanted to present the site via Octopress. I have experience in Octopress now, because of this blog, and several photo display plugins have been written for the platform.</p>

<p>I had done some research, and found that the web app <a href="http://fancyapps.com/fancybox">Fancybox</a> integrated somewhat smoothly with Octopress. Also, a fellow Octopress user, <a href="http://tritarget.org/blog/2012/05/07/integrating-photos-into-octopress-using-fancybox-and-plugin/">Tritarget</a> had written a pretty good plugin which made the display of photos even easier, since it utilized simple Markdown tags, rather than coding raw HTML.</p>

<p>To make things easy, and not interfere with the operation of this blog, I chose to spin up another instance on my <a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a> account. Heroku is the ideal choice for this and other projects of mine because I can spin up as many instances as I want, and only accrue charges for the total amount of resources (regardless of the number of apps) that I consume. After a little tweaking and adjustments, I got Fancybox and the plugin to play nice with Octopress.</p>

<p>Fancybox is probably the best-looking HTML-based photo display app out there. Slick transitions, a great UI, and easy implementation (mostly), make for a great quick-and-dirty display solution. However, the downside is, there is no practical way, that I found, to do a "gallery". And a gallery was needed since my final edit came to 530 photos.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/preview_collage.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'Previews'" ></p>

<p>And I certainly wasn't going to manually input the Markdown tags for 530 photos. So, with that in mind, I decided to divest my thoughts of using Octopress. I set out to find a dedicated photo display solution. Some enterprising individuals had written plugins which can read Flickr sets, but I didn't want to host on Flickr, for copyright and personal reasons. So, I googled around a bit and found several Rails-based photo gallery apps.</p>

<p>Now, some of you may ask, why wouldn't I just use the Rails-based photo gallery app that I had already, i.e. <a href="http://seenightlife.com/">See Nightlife</a>?</p>

<p>Well, to be honest, See Nightlife is broken. I can upload and display, but all organizational tools are offline. It's a "write once" solution as it stands. I can't even delete photos. Also, Ryan and I simply haven't had the time to fix it. Plus, the app it was based on, <a href="https://github.com/rapind/albumdy">Albumdy</a> is no longer being maintained.</p>

<p>As this was to display the wedding photos of two of my closest friends, something a little more reliable needed to be found. These are wedding photos, not a bunch of images of kids blindly worshipping some guy playing music off of his Mac.</p>

<p>So, with that in mind, I settled on a fairly popular Rails app called <a href="http://balderapp.com/">Balder.</a></p>

<p>Developed and maintained by Espen Antonsen out of Norway, Balder is a currently-maintained-and-produced Rails app for displaying photos in a collection/album format. And it fit my use case perfectly, as I wanted to host my photos on S3, and have the app live on Heroku. Heroku is more for running applications, and not storage. S3 is eminently more suited to storage, hence "Simple Storage Service" (S3). Espen himself uses this setup, and even provided a howto guide <a href="http://blog.inspired.no/rails-photo-gallery-balder-on-heroku-and-s3-726/">on his blog</a> on how to do it. In a nutshell, you provide Balder your S3 key, secret, and bucket name in a config file, commit to Heroku, and go from there. The one stumbling block I encountered is that the uploader itself tries to call an EXIF display module, which is dependent on a UNIX executable, which to my knowledge, cannot be installed on Heroku. So, even though the initial deployment was fast, the actual implementation wasn't.</p>

<p>Now, where the virtues of open source kick in is that I had the code for Balder on my local machine. Through Heroku's logging, I could see where the app was breaking uploads. I'm still a 'babe in the woods' when it comes to coding, but I can read what the code is doing. I saw where it was getting hung up, but had no idea on how to fix it, or comment it out, since I specifically didn't need EXIF data to be displayed. For those who may not be familiar, EXIF data is basically metadata contained in a JPEG file, which shows things like the camera type, exposure settings, and so on. You can see the EXIF data of a photo by doing the "File Info" function on your operating system of choice.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/exif.png" width="964" height="541" title="'Coding'" ></p>

<p>So, via the <a href="https://github.com/espen/balder">issues tracker in the Github repository for Balder</a>, I submitted a request for support from the developer. Now, since the app is free, and Espen derives no income from it, he was under zero obligation to respond to me. Since it was the weekend, I didn't expect much right away. But, by this morning, he had filed a response to my request:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Try commenting out "before_create :exif_read" in the photo model. I will look into this later but currently too busy with other work.</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>Espen Antonsen</strong> <cite><a href='https://github.com/espen/balder/issues/36'>HTML5 Uploader Generates HTTP Error</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I appreciated his honesty, that's for sure. Way more than I expected. Most free open-source projects are one-shot deals where the developer does the initial work, and then forgets about it. So, I was pleasantly surprised at a reply.</p>

<p>And fortunately, his solution worked. I commented out a call to the non-existent EXIF module, and successfully uploaded some photos as a test. After confidently seeing that they displayed and cycled according to my wishes, I then began to upload the wedding photos in earnest. Balder has an excellent organizational structure. I can create a collection, let's call it "Wedding", and then albums for each portion of the event. Very slick. Five stars. And wonderful support from someone whom isn't even obligated to do so.</p>

<p>Now, if this was a closed-source solution or a problem with a hosted service like Flickr, I would have had no way of figuring out what was wrong. I would have had to email their support, wait, and hope they could get to the issue in time. With open-source, I can peek under the hood, make some educated assessments as to what the issue is, and attempt a fix on my own. Or at the least, get concrete info that the developer understands so he or she can make a more effective fix. Plus, I got to learn a little more about just what makes a Rails-based web app tick.</p>

<p>Right now, the app is deployed to Heroku, and running smoothly. I plan on using Balder in general, from here on out and whenever possible for my hosting needs. Open source for the win, as they say.</p>

<ul>
<li>Sidebar: I'd love to show you guys the results of the wedding, but since it was a personal affair, I would rather receive clearance before I share the results with the public. Thanks for understanding, all.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting video wide open.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T12:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/shooting-video-wide-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/51143544" width="720" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/51143544">• 50 1.2 L video test wide open at 1.2 •</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>Shooting video using the 50 1.2 L is an interesting experience, to say the least...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>One of the biggest things cinematographers and videographers, such as <a href="http://watcha3.com/">Buster</a> over at A3, have conveyed to me, is the desire to shoot at the lowest ISO possible when shooting video, preferably below ISO 1000, though I have gotten great results at ISO 1600, and I'll go beyond that, if I know the video is going to be laden with effects in post.</p>

<p>That being said, the obvious requirement to shoot at a low ISO is, lots of light. And "lots of light" in the video world, means something a bit different than in the world of still photography, for a few reasons.</p>

<p>First off, due to the nature of video, you are limited to a shutter speed, at the low end, of 1/30 second. Though, for the best results, most videographers, including <a href="http://blog.vincentlaforet.com">Vincent Laforet</a>, recommend a shutter speed of 1/50 second, to mesh better with common monitor refresh rates. So, almost by default, you are limited in your light gathering ability, when shooting video.</p>

<p>At that point, your options are, crank the ISO, open up as fast as your lens can go, or dump a lot of light on the scene. Or any combination thereof.</p>

<p>As an experiment, I chose to shoot the sequence above at ISO 320, 1/50 second shutter speed, all wide open at f1.2. As you can see, Caroline drifts in and out of the zone of critical focus on numerous occasions. However, the video quality is amazing. At ISO 320, the 5D MK II generates superb results. In reality I could have stopped down a bit, since the lighting tech at Blue Martini was kind enough to have the system running at maximum intensity at the time.</p>

<p>I can definitely recommend the 50 1.2 L for video work. It's a very versatile prime, and the image quality is amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
