<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: agalmic | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/agalmic/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-20T03:23:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I handle noise in a photo.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/how-i-handle-noise-in-a-photo/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T02:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/how-i-handle-noise-in-a-photo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6346.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Space Crowd'" ></p>

<p>OK, like I said I'll try and pass on some know-how from time to time on here. I can document what I do, but it's up to any of you guys who use it to know when and where to use it.</p>

<p>But I'm not going to turn this into a lecture series or motivational speaker session. The world has enough of those.</p>

<p>Anyways, the biggest question I get is, <em>"How the hell do you shoot at a high ISO and manage the noise?"</em></p>

<p>Well, fact is, I don't manage it really...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Hmm, well, maybe I do sometimes.</p>

<p>Fact is, we've come a long way in terms of noise in digital imaging systems, and prior to that, the grain present in analog processes involving film. And even when there was noise and grain present, it was largely left alone or used as part of the composition as a whole. The important part was capturing the moment, and the noise was disregarded in favor of the subject as a whole. Which is what I tend to do. ISO 6400 isn't really that bad. It's actually less noisy/grainy than the ISO 400 film stock I "grew up" on.</p>

<p>But, when I do want to deal with or minimize the noise, I don't employ conventional noise reduction techniques as it were. Plugins are generally all over the place and time-consuming, and the built-in NR functions of popular imaging applications tends to make the end images too soft.</p>

<p>So, what I keep in mind is my end result and intent. Despite the fact I shoot with a camera which has a 22-megapixel sensor, most of my images are downsized to 960 x 640. At that resolution, noise is generally hard to pick out. The image at the lead of this article is actually quite noisy in some respects. However, you can't see much of it since it has been reduced in size by many multiples to be displayed on your monitor. And, unless you have a Retina display (and yes, you'll probably have to forget a lot of what I just told you in that regard), there is really not a huge amount of detail present in the above image.</p>

<p>Now, if that image were to go to print, I would usually insist on matte paper. Matte paper masks the noise wonderfully. The texture overrides a lot of the noisier characteristics of the image.</p>

<p>If I'm forced into a glossy presentation, I then usually move on to "plan B". Plan B doesn't involve a lot of work, and doesn't involve any noise reduction plugins or techniques. Note, this whole idea assumes you shot RAW. You are shooting RAW, right? Another assumption I'm making here is that I've probably already told you to use Lightroom. If not, the concepts carry over. Drop me a line if you need help in another package, maybe I can figure it out for you.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lr1.png" width="845" height="467" title="'LR'" ></p>

<p>Basically, I ask myself, <em>"Where does this noise exist in the color spectrum?"</em></p>

<p>In most cases, I find the noise exists in the red and magenta channels of the color spectrum. Which does make sense, since noise tends to be a function of heat and energy in a digital sensor system, and that energy conveys itself as a lower frequency "color" of sorts. Now, some people would suggest desaturating in the affected channels. Doesn't really work that way. If you do this, you are left with a muddled grey mess, which looks worse than the existing noise did.</p>

<p>So, what I do is I "cool" the image off a bit. I bring down the color temperature slider, sometimes as low as 4000K. Typically I'm only employing this technique in high-ISO nightclub images, which tend to not utilize flash and the skin tone of any human subjects in the frame is of little concern, i.e. they are already an odd color, so shifting it one way or the other won't destroy the idea of the image. Plus, in RAW you can adjust your other color bands to make up for any shift. Anyways, what I do is I bring our color temp down, until I see the "red" noise minimize itself somewhat.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lr2.png" width="444" height="230" title="'LR2'" ></p>

<p>And, if that is not sufficient for our needs, I'll turn down the luminance of the affected colors if possible. If this piece is really critical for something, I will actually do the above steps in Photoshop, rather than Lightroom, to allow for more fine control over segments of the image.</p>

<p>Basically, with these steps, I'm minimizing the noise by altering it's appearance and luminosity in the image, which does not destroy the overall sharpness and focus characteristics of the image. Plus, the saturation of desired colors and areas is left alone.</p>

<p>And that's actually kind of it, ya know? I'm not too big into noise reduction. Much like it says on the back of any piece of electronics you own, I just "accept interference from other sources" in my image, and keep moving on to get the photos I want.</p>

<p>Sidebar: Did you know your digital SLR is susceptible to the radio frequency noise present everywhere? And present in huge quantities in a nightclub? Think about it. There's giant speakers with giant magnets mere feet from your camera body. There's massive amounts of electrical energy flowing through poorly-shielded cables. There's hundreds of people, each one with a cell phone on them. There's security guys with radios. There's Wi-Fi network signals, the list goes on. There's a lot of noise pinging about in the club that makes it's way into your camera's guts. It's a miracle it even works sometimes. So yeah, my real advice is to disregard this entire article and just keep shooting. But if you insist on dealing with the noise, I hope this helped. Also, every successive generation of digital SLR technology deals with the noise more effectively. Pretty soon, ISO 6400 will look like ISO 400 does today.</p>

<p>Sidebar 2: I am not qualified in physics or electronic systems as of yet. I might be way off base on some of what is behind all this. I used some of the free knowledge available online to figure out the basics. However, my techniques produce the desired result. So there's that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On passing on knowledge...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/on-passing-on-knowledge-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/20/on-passing-on-knowledge-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/rs-6552.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Roger Sanchez - A real DJ at work'" ></p>

<p>A lot of people ask me about my photos, "How did you do that?"</p>

<p>Well, truth be told, it isn't a huge secret on how I, or any other working photographer, pulls off their images...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I was having a discussion with <a href="http://ryanalynporter.com">Ryan</a> the other day, in response to my prior posting about <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/15/some-of-us-are-more-than-that-guy-with-the-camera/">being more than the guy with the camera.</a></p>

<p>Ryan bought forth the term <em>agalmics</em> during our discussion. In a nutshell, agalmics is:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The study and practice of the production and allocation of non-scarce goods.</p><footer><strong>Robert Levin</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.openverse.com/~dtinker/agalmics.html'>Agalmics - the Marginalization of Scarcity</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And yes, that was an excuse to show off the shiny blockquote tag here in Octopress. Which actually ties into what I'm talking about here.</p>

<p>The internet has made knowledge of most subjects a non-scarce resource. From the implementation of the blockquote tag here on my blog, to just how the heck I composed that image of Roger that leads off the article, to the basic techniques Roger uses to mix music together in his DJ sets, the transfer of knowledge has definitely become a non-scarce resource. It's really not much of an exaggeration to say that the sum of human knowledge is online these days.</p>

<p>With a few exceptions, the directions on how to do just about anything have been documented online, and those directions are freely accessible. And if they are not freely accessible at first, some more searching will bring forth a free alternative on how to get something done. I mention that because some academic research is locked behind paywalls. However, similar research is often freely accessible, and the assiduous student can often come to the same conclusions the researchers hiding behind paywalls do.</p>

<p>But anyways, with regards to my photo work, I don't mind freely passing on the knowledge, even if I paid for it a long time ago. If I'm stingy with the knowledge, the person asking for it, if they are determined enough, will seek it out on their own, and undoubtedly discover it elsewhere. Ryan put it bluntly:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>An agalmic entrepreneur's currency is his reputation.</p><footer><strong>Ryan Porter</strong> <cite><a href='http://forum.talknightlife.com/viewtopic.php?f=3&amp;t=20149&amp;st=0&amp;sk=t&amp;sd=a'>EDM Is the Wimpiest Youth Movement Ever? - TNL Thread</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>My reputation (other than being a scandal!) tends to lie in the direction that I am in possession of a lot of knowledge, and I have no qualms about giving it away. It's a currency that can be spent and earned just like money nowadays. And simply because people have faith that the knowledge will benefit them. Much like the US Dollar is only worth something because the world believes it is worth something. We've assigned value to it, and it is no longer based on the reserves of a scarce material, i.e. gold.</p>

<p>But unlike gold, knowledge and information are no longer scarce. It's all out there, free for the taking. Even if you do not own your own computer or have your own internet connection, you can avail yourself of free resources to get online, and access the same information a guy on his iPad next to his pool on Star Island can.</p>

<p>So with that in mind, I tend to not object if someone sincerely asks how I manage to pull something off in the photographic realm. I get something out of it, myself, personally. I tend to be a miserable rat bastard about some things, like the political system, the popularity of dubstep, ravers, fluorescent lighting, BlackBerries, and American Idol. So I guess, subconsciously, to balance out that deficit in the karma bank, I kind of get a visceral thrill when I can pass on what I've learned. That, and when it comes to photo work at least, I can only pass on the parameters of what I've done, it's up to the person I'm teaching to implement it at the right time. It's like your parents can tell you how to drive a car, but eventually you have to get behind the wheel and do it yourself. And once you are behind the wheel, it's a lot different than when Mom told you not to stomp on the accelerator.</p>

<p>And as far as someone using that knowledge against me? Well, I don't see it as being used against me, since I really don't play that game. If someone takes what I've showed them and apes my style, and gets more work than I do, that's fine. Even if they don't acknowledge where they learned it from. Recognition and attribution are nice and "proper internet etiquette", but I don't expect it these days. I figure it is something they have to live with. And I'm really not in the recognition game, either. If what I do helps a friend or a client do well, I usually get taken along for the ride. There's a lot of things at play out in the world that are way more powerful than myself, and I figure it's easier to just ride the wave and catch a ride, rather than try to take on those forces directly. Either way, I end up doing alright for myself.</p>

<p>With that in mind, I do plan on passing on little bits and pieces of what I know in this here blog, kind of as a way to balance out some of the more ornery aspects of it, and also just for the sake of composing my thoughts on "paper". Sometimes it'll be about photographic and video techniques I know, other times it'll be about coding this here site, and maybe on occasion some bits and pieces on the fine art of Mercedes maintenance as I learn more about that.</p>

<p>I'm on a bit of a roll right now, let me kick off the first one. In the next post. Let's keep this somewhat organized.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
