<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: randomness | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/randomness/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-08-15T03:01:07-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best camera is the one you have on you.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/the-best-camera-is-the-one-you-have-on-you/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T02:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/15/the-best-camera-is-the-one-you-have-on-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://gallery.photo.net/photo/1232337-md.jpg" width="766" height="504" title="'Miami 2000'" ></p>

<p>The above is one of my favorite images that I've taken. The gear used consisted of a $200 Pentax ZX-5n film SLR, a roll of $8 Fuji 400 film I bought in a drugstore, and an $80 chunk of Sigma glass with no special features other than a macro function. It shows the Metromover tracks near the original location of Club Space, looking south towards Brickell. This was prior to the AA Arena, the "Biscayne Wall" of condos such as Ten Museum Park, 900 Biscayne, The Everglades, and so on, as well as more recent additions like The Marquis. Almost a Miami of old at this point.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>However, I managed to capture the subtle tones of the sunrise and the remnants of the evening mixed with the street and track lighting. Kind of an early attempt at my current fascination with scenics, I guess.</p>

<p>Without my description, most would have guessed I captured this with a decent digital SLR, or if they had an eye for Miami and the time depicted, a fairly top-of-the-range film body and lens. The reality is, I grabbed this frame with less than $300 worth of equipment. On film. Most club photographers have never touched film. I still have to take action on this, but one of these weekends, I'm going to shoot a few rolls of film at Space for the hell of it.</p>

<p>A lot of photographers, professional and otherwise, are victims of gear lust. Sure, I am too, but since I got started, I always tried to hold true to the ethic of "The best camera is the one you have on you".</p>

<p>It's akin to what is taught in military academies around the country, "You go to war with the army you have, not the one you want". You are basically limited by your situation and your budget. Budget, obviously, because not every working professional can justify or afford a 1-series Canon body or a Nikon D4. And situationally, since it isn't always practical to carry around a large digital SLR and several lenses everywhere you go.</p>

<p>For the longest time, I shot with crop-frame mid-range digital SLRs. My work level and situation made stepping up to a full-frame body like the 5D MK II an unrealistic proposition. Maybe not so unrealistic, but more of me being cautious. My existing camera bodies generated superb images in my hands, and there was no pressing need to upgrade. I only finally upgraded to the 5D MK II when it made sense for me to do so, since several clients were asking for video work, and the 5D MK II made the most sense for my shooting style. And even then, the 5D MK II was a three year-old piece of hardware, which still generated superb images in the hands of an experienced shooter.</p>

<p>But regardless, due to the situation I was in at the time, I lacked independent transport. I took the bus everywhere. And I bought my SLR kit with me, out of necessity, since I'd often be on my way to or from a shoot. Even if I wasn't specifically shooting something, I always feared I'd get a call-up to shoot something right away, and my gear would be several bus rides or an expensive cab journey away, if I didn't have it on me. Very cumbersome way of conducting business. Obviously when I acquired my own independent transport, this became less of a problem as I could stow my gear in my trunk (a scary proposition in some areas), or keep it at home, but still be able to buzz back to base and snag it if the need arose.</p>

<p>However, the news or "that specific situation" doesn't always wait for me to rocket down I-95 at 100 MPH and skid over to my apartment to pick up my gear. So, the camera I may have on me at that moment is my iPhone 4s. The cameras inside phones have come a long way. The 4s is still, as of this writing, the undisputed champ in my mind, especially when coupled with decent photo apps from the App Store. One of my favorites is <a href="http://www.awesomize.com/"> Camera Awesome</a>. Developed by Smugmug, Camera Awesome has an ingenious system for focusing, exposure, as well as a basic suite of post-production tools, enabling you to crank out an acceptable JPEG in a hurry if the need arises. It also integrates with Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, and standard email.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ca.png" width="640" height="960" title="'Camera Awesome'" ></p>

<p>I've cranked out plenty of what I consider decent images using this little app. Several more exist, such as Hipstamatic and so forth, but Camera Awesome seems to be more geared towards those with a modicum of photo knowledge.</p>

<p>With this in mind, I actually don't freak out as much when I leave my MK II behind, like if I am going out to a purely social occasion somewhere and it's impractical or impolite to be carrying a giant bag of gear around, and maybe not the best idea in the world to leave it in the trunk of your vehicle. Since, I know I have my iPhone with a decent app close at hand, and know how to work with and around it's limitations. I won't be generating prize-winning work anytime soon with my iPhone, but I'm actually pretty impressed with the results. I work with the camera I have on me when the situation arises, I don't muck about wishing I bought my full-size rig. Though that being said, 95 percent of the time I do have my equipment within ten feet of me. It's the 5 percent of the rest of the time I've learned to calm down about and not worry about it. I know I can pop off a decent iPhone photo at any time if the situation demands it.</p>

<p>I'm of course not suggesting everyone ditch their SLRs for iPhones, but at the same time, don't be susceptible to gear lust. Sometimes you just need to make do with what you have. And actually, when you work with what you have, a lot of the time, the end results will surprise you.</p>

<p>FYI, if anyone is interested in seeing my attempts at iPhone photography, check out my Instacanvas gallery (prints of my Instagrams) at <a href="http://instacanv.as/pod_gram">instacanv.as/pod_gram</a>. It's cheap!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Car2Go Cheaper Than a Cab.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/car2go-cheaper-than-a-cab/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T13:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/13/car2go-cheaper-than-a-cab</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/210smart.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'210 and Smart'" ></p>

<p>I love my current car. The W210 Mercedes-Benz E320 is a solid performer. A cruiser if you will, it's built for cruising the highways at speed. I'm not gonna beat an SLS off the line in acceleration, but I can easily cruise at 85+ MPH in the express lanes on I-95 without difficulty.</p>

<p>That being said, when I go out to shoot at a nightclub, I'm hesitant to take it out. Parking in a safe area is costly, and of course presents several safety concerns. No matter how 'secure' a lot is, there's still a fair amount of unmonitored traffic shuffling in and out of a lot during the course of a night, any of them whom could be a potential vandal or thief, looking for a score. Or even someone who just isn't looking where they are going and decides that it's time to bump into my vehicle.</p>

<p>So, when I go out to shoot, I usually take the cab, or the bus. Living just off of Biscayne Boulevard makes both options doable.</p>

<p>Both those options have negatives though.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p><strong>The Cab</strong> - The cab costs money. From my place to say, <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space</a>, for example, is $11 plus tip (you do remember to tip your driver, don't you?) on average. Also, cabs may not be immediately available during peak times, whether you stand outside or dial 305-888-8888.</p>

<p><strong>The Bus</strong> - The 3 bus, while cheap, only runs once a hour after 11 PM. And, the arrival time at your stop, though listed at say, 1:35 AM, can vary up to 20 minutes. Not fun when it's warm out and there's some of the local characters coming out of the Motel South Pacific. I'm not threatened by them, of course, but it can give one pause.</p>

<p>Those were my only two options aside from driving, until about a few weeks ago.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car 2 Go</a>. A brand of Daimler (Mercedes), Car 2 Go is a car-share service that's been successful in Europe for a few years now. They recently launched in Miami, dropping around 240 blue-and-white Smart Fortwos around town. Finding some previous press and a handy promo code, I decided to sign up. Since you only pay for what you use, just having the membership costs nothing. Other share services have monthly fees, apparently. Also, Car 2 Go is a "one way" service, you don't have to return the car to a lot, you can just leave it at any City of Miami-run parking meter.</p>

<p>So, with this in mind, I decided to try a little experiment.</p>

<p>I was schedule to shoot at Space this past Saturday, much like every other Saturday for the past decade or so. Usually, I would take a cab or the bus for the reasons I mentioned above. However, this time, I decided to try out my new C2G membership for a real task rather than just an excuse to test a Smart car out. Using C2G's handy iOS app, I found a car about a block from my apartment.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/c2g.png" width="640" height="960" title="'iOS Car 2 Go'" ></p>

<p>Yes, it was 3:40 in the morning. I had a friend's going-away party prior, so sue me.</p>

<p>As you can see, there was one 90 meters and change away from me. So, I slung my goodie bag onto my back, and walked to the vehicle.</p>

<p>After I boarded, I did the usual login procedures, and checked the time.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage0.instagram.com/6bd181b4e45111e1ae7122000a1e86bb_7.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Onboard Insta'" ></p>

<p>I drove down Biscayne Boulevard at a reasonable speed and arrived at an empty City parking spot a block from Space around 7 minutes later.</p>

<p>Car 2 Go charges you 38 cents a minute to drive. There's no membership fee or paying for parking or gas. If you need gas there's a Wright Fleet fuel card inside. I think they give you credits if you have to stop and put gas in, even. So, .38 x 7 = 2.66, give or take a minute or so.</p>

<p>A cab, like I mentioned, is $11.00 plus tip. The bus is $2.00 flat but you have to kind of estimate when it's going to show up.</p>

<p>So, for this situation, Car 2 Go was a clear winner.</p>

<p>Of course, this only works if you live in the City of Miami, and there's a vehicle near you. Also, for me it was a 1-way trip, since I left Space around 9 AM, and I had had a few drinks. Obviously with C2G, you have to obey all the normal rules of the road! A kind friend who works at Space was nice enough to drive me home, so my total transport bill for the evening was $2.66. Even if I took a cab home, I would have still come out ahead.</p>

<p>I can definitely recommend Car 2 Go. Besides, even though the Smart drives like an angry golf cart, it's kind of fun to drive when you flip it over to manual.</p>

<p>Check 'em out at <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">car2go.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the audacity of scooter riders.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/on-the-audacity-of-scooter-riders/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T16:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/09/on-the-audacity-of-scooter-riders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/scoot2.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Scoot'" ></p>

<p>One of my pet peeves since moving here ages ago has been the scooter rider.</p>

<p>Now, I recognize the utility of the scooter. It's light, efficient, and you can stow it almost
anywhere when not in use. Plus, you don't need insurance, and LEOs tend to leave you be.</p>

<p>It is probably the last one which makes scooter riders so obnoxious...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Before I acquired my current mode of personal transport, I would either take public transit, or on occasion, have
the use of a friend's scooter. They're fun to ride, and useful for getting around the Beach and the Downtown area.
However, being that there's nothing between you and the road but your clothes, I tended to ride cautiously, knowing that
I'm not as visible as I would be in a car or truck. It was up to me to watch where I was going.</p>

<p>However, most scooter riders do not. They ride like they own the road, and expect other motorists to watch out for them.
Now, realistically, that is fair since they have the lighter and less powerful vehicle. But fair only if they are obeying the
same rules of the road the rest of us try to do. For the most part, scooter riders around here tend to weave in and out of traffic
with abandon, often in packs. You see the 'pack' phenomenon on Memorial Day Weekend, when herds of tourists rent every available
scooter on the Beach and troll Washington Avenue in packs of twenty or more, as if they were some sort of mentally-challenged
chapter of the Hell's Angels.</p>

<p>Worse yet, your average scooter rider will blame you for any of their indiscretions on the road.</p>

<p>Case in point. Yesterday, I was leaving the Publix complex on Fifth and Alton. As I eased on to Lenox Avenue into the flow of traffic,
a kid, dare I say a <em>chmak</em>, on a Vespa was closing in on me rather fast. Now, the light ahead of me was red, so myself and the drivers in front of me clearly could not
move. The scooter rider, rather than stop and join the flow of traffic as he would have been required to do, swerved to the <em>right</em> of me and
the rest of the cars in the lane, choosing to wedge his noisy lawn-mower-sounding contraption between all of us and the sidewalk. My outraged
fellow car drivers honked in protest as he wedged through, only to be met by a stream of incoherent curses and curiously random gestures which
may have passed for obscene in some far-flung nation on the other side of the world. I suppose flailing your arms about and screaming could
be considered an obscene gesture, somewhere. There's a lot of people on this planet. All the while, this kid's conveyance was still in forward
motion.</p>

<p>Someone less kind than me could have taken exception to that, actually. This is Miami, after all. The kid on the Vespa is damn lucky in that
regard.</p>

<p>Scooter riders, scoot all you want, but realize it's a two-way street. You're on a motor vehicle too. It's a scooter, not a Hayabusa.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with the GoPro]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/i-fell-in-love-with-the-gopro/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T17:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/i-fell-in-love-with-the-gopro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I borrowed a Go Pro from my friend <a href="http://weekendweapons.com/">Travis Rogers</a> after I saw him using one at <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space.</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/46475090" width="960" height="540" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/46475090">GoPro Test</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dvdigital">Dan V</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>I wasn't really interested in it as a club tool, though I could see it being useful as a B-camera for some in-the-booth shots. Where I found the most thrill though, was mounting it to the bumper of my car, and driving around Miami. In the video above, you can see some of the results. I'm not the sharpest editor yet, but the footage speaks for itself, I think. The GoPro is great for what it costs, and will be even better when they roll the new "ProTune" firmware any day now and really pump the bitrate.</p>

<p>And yes, this is a blatant excuse to see if Vimeo embedding works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some words on my style]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/some-words-on-my-style/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T15:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/08/some-words-on-my-style</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tort-9921.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Jordyn Hartlein on the box at Space'" ></p>

<p>A lot of people ask me why I shoot like I do, when it comes to nightlife and concerts. Well, there's many reasons.</p>


<p>Nowadays, with the ubiquity of the 'nightlife photographer', or 'the guy with the blog' (yes, I'm well aware that I'm writing this on a blog platform), one has to strive to differentiate themselves in order to be unique, stand out, and get work. Even if your end goal isn't necessarily financially-oriented (and it shouldn't be, you aren't going to get rich shooting concerts and clubs, it's something you have to like to do), your job or vision is easier to pull off if you can develop a coherent style to call your own.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I've been working in clubs for about fifteen years now. I started by helping my friend John, now the owner of <a href="http://alchemyavcs.com/">Alchemy Audio Visual Systems</a> with lugging around his nascent rig of EAW speaker cabinets and Crown amplifiers, and doing double duty as his light tech. We provided reinforcement for local punk bands and some DJ shows as well. I was also majoring in motion picture production and fine art photography at the <a href="http://miami.edu/">University of Miami</a>, and working for their IT department as well.</p>

<p>Anyways, I managed to work my nighttime activities into legitimate coursework for my photography classes. I would shoot some of the bands and our lighting setups, when time permitted. Early on, one of the biggest "rules" of most venues, if they were cool with me shooting at all, was that flash photography was frowned upon or genuinely prohibited around the performers of the evening. Totally understandable, for two reasons. First off, if you are DJing or playing an instrument, a flash blowing off in your field of vision can be distracting, or even dangerous, if you are the sort of performer who tends to be very dynamic. Also, and this forms the basis of my style, the performers are usually well-lit, or can be at request.</p>

<p>Basically, there's a lot of light around if you know how to use it. Nightclubs and concert halls are generally regarded as being dark and dingy, but there is a lot of light within them. LED screens, flat panel displays, swirling intelligent lights, the glow from POS terminals, even candlelight. It can all be used to pull off an effective photo, while not having to resort to using flash photography. Now, there is nothing inherently wrong with flash photography. Used properly, it can provide a wonderful balance to a scene. Used improperly, the results can be substandard, and the act of taking the photo itself can be distracting. One of the keys to successful concert and nightclub photography in my mind is to blend in with the scenery. People tend to be themselves if they think you are one of the crowd, and not some guy with an SLR looking for attention, free entry, and cheap laughs. We all know that guy, he's not nice.</p>

<p>Of course, working with the light that is there presents some challenges. Invariably you are operating at a very shallow depth-of-field, a slow shutter speed, a high ISO, or all three. I won't get into it in this post, but all three can be compensated for, especially high ISO. High ISO is the easiest to compensate for, actually. Flat out accept the noise. It's there, use it and move on. ISO 6400 on a modern DSLR is actually more usable than ISO 1600 on a roll of Fujicolor from the 1990s, even without noise reduction.</p>

<p>So basically, my style is the result of the environment I generally shoot in, and my ethos of blending in with the crowd rather than being the focus of it.
<img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/tort-9712.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Work it.'" ></p>

<p>Use the light that's there, you might surprise yourself.</p>

<p>(Oh, and this is only a test - I'll add photos in a bit)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
