<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: randomness | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/randomness/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-10-13T02:36:45-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone summed it up eloquently...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T03:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/13/someone-summed-it-up-eloquently-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/jordyn-6643.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'It fell in line...'" ></p>

<p>While some tell me my strength lies in capturing images, I also have been told I can write well. However, in terms of writing, I do tend to ramble. Hence, this blog's tagline having the words "general ramblings"...</p>

<p>So, when someone asks for me to summarize something, it's nigh-impossible for me to do. So, if you asked me to sum up my own body of photographic work, I'd be at a loss to condense it to a sentence or two. I cringe at committing grammar crimes when I have to post to Twitter. The art of summary is lost to me.</p>

<p>However, someone summarized what I do so well for me just a few minutes ago...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it...</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And <em>boom</em>, that sums it up.</p>

<p>I could sit here for hours expounding on noise levels, a-to-d conversions, electric fields emanating from poorly-shielded cabling, the native ISO of a given sensor, and don't-point-your-lens-at-a-10-watt-laser-you-fool type of things and it wouldn't be a summary of how I manage to pull off a shot. It'd be the Book of Pod so to speak. Which, some people like, and some people don't.</p>

<p>It actually speaks volumes about having an outside opinion.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/13//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QtZ7SrAgIA/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/4906bc4c14f011e2bacf123138179cfe_7.jpg' alt='You can see the guy about to jump out.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.82752892,-80.187165969'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.82752892,-80.187165969&markers=25.82752892,-80.187165969&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='55th Street Station' /></a><br/>Taken at 55th Street Station</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='301010775764500992_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I had just come back from a nighttime run (yes Ryan, I do run around this neighborhood at 1 AM) and I picked up a text conversation where I had left it off earlier. My friend Adriana had just moved from the construction mess called Brickell, to a cozy new joint on Collins Avenue in "Condo Canyon" with her boyfriend. She was inviting me over for a little housewarming thing tomorrow, and she mentioned the last thing she had picked up from her old apt was a piece of mine that she purchased back in 2009:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/frances_2008.jpg" width="640" height="960" title="'Frances at Space - 2008'" ></p>

<p>I had done an exhibit of some of my "dancer photos" at the first <a href="http://lifeisart.org">Life Is Art</a> exhibit in Wynwood. Life is Art, by <a href="http://soulofmiami.org">Soul of Miami</a> founder James Echols, is a local organization that supports up-and-coming artists of all stripes. Since that first open show in 2009, they've come a long way and are quite renowned in the art community, especially amongst artists who may not be "hip" enough to warrant the attention of some of the more corporate art organizations in town. Adriana, at the time, was their treasurer, and had expressed an interest in obtaining a print of one of my images, specifically the one above. So, her mom took it upon herself to pull me aside and purchase it from me for her. As my exhibit was digital (I didn't have the budget to produce 20 prints of size), I took the "order" and contacted my print provider to generate a canvas-framed print for me of this piece. A few weeks later, it was delivered to Adriana, to much acclaim. Oddly enough it's the only "dancer" piece I have ever sold. Either I just haven't marketed them properly or people don't go for half-naked girls in smoky nightclubs as <em>objets d'art</em>.</p>

<p>Fast-forward to today. As pieces of art are often delicate, they are usually transported separately from other items in a moving adventure. Anyways, in a conversation about that piece tonight, Adriana was asking me about how I capture moments like that, and I did have a hard time summarizing it up. So, she put it into words that had previously escaped me:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>You have a vision and you wait for the world to fall in line and then you capture it...</p><footer><strong>Adriana D</strong> <cite>A Phone Conversation 12 October 2012</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>And yes, that's it. Minus the technical details, which, if anyone asks, I'll gladly explain, that's pretty much it. I see the image in my head, and I wait for the world to fall in line. Whether it's in a club or below a deserted bridge in Key West, that's it. If I had to sum it up into a Twitter-friendly sentence, that is it.</p>

<p>Now, if I can summarize this post, it would be, "A different perspective always helps..."</p>

<p>Oh, and Ade, thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On mental instability...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/on-mental-instability-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T02:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/10/on-mental-instability-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9070.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The crazy ones.'" ></p>

<p>An article in the New York Times caught my eye today, on the subject of <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&partner=rss&emc=rss&smid=tw-nytimes">medicating the children of our society</a> for a range of supposed mental illnesses.</p>

<p>Now, I don't condemn the benefits of modern medicine, and I also don't condemn the use of drugs recreationally. However, as odd as it may sound with this stance, I'm actually kind of against the overprescription of psychotropic medications.</p>

<p>For several reasons...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>We’ve decided as a society that it’s too expensive to modify the kid’s environment. So we have to modify the kid.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz interviews Dr Michael Anderson</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&amp;partner=rss&amp;emc=rss&amp;smid=tw-nytimes'>Attention Disorder or Not, Pills to Help in School</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I'm not an educational professional. I've been told I can convey knowledge rather effectively, but educational techniques are not in any of my various professional and non-professional job descriptions.</p>

<p>Be that as it may, I do pay attention to trends in society with regards to the educational methods being used to teach children today. And, frankly, the trend of medicating children this way scares me.</p>

<p>Objectively, it's lazy. The educators lack the patience to effectively deal with the children, so they fall back on a pharmaceutical solution. Now, I'll grant you that there may be children who genuinely need these medications just to function in daily life, but from the article above, it seems to reflect the now-obvious trend of seeing a pharmaceutical solution as a way out.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>On the Rocafort family’s kitchen shelf in Ball Ground, Ga., next to the peanut butter and chicken broth, sits a wire basket brimming with bottles of the children’s medications, prescribed by Dr. Anderson: Adderall for Alexis, 12; and Ethan, 9; Risperdal (an antipsychotic for mood stabilization) for Quintn and Perry, both 11; and Clonidine (a sleep aid to counteract the other medications) for all four, taken nightly.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&amp;partner=rss&amp;emc=rss&amp;smid=tw-nytimes'>www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I would call it a statistical norm if one of the children in the family described here required medicating, but when each and every child is on a spectrum of psychotropic drugs, there's clear evidence to suggest overprescription is at work here. Nevermind what Mom and Dad might be on.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>To help me focus on my school work, my homework, listening to Mom and Dad, and not doing what I used to do to my teachers, to make them mad,” he said. He described the week in the hospital and the effects of Risperdal: “If I don’t take my medicine I’d be having attitudes. I’d be disrespecting my parents. I wouldn’t be like this.</p><footer><strong>Alan Schwarz interviewing Quintn Rocafort, age 11</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/health/attention-disorder-or-not-children-prescribed-pills-to-help-in-school.html?_r=1&amp;partner=rss&amp;emc=rss&amp;smid=tw-nytimes'>www.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Listen, when I was 11, I was a disrespectful little shit. I regularly threw fits, pissed off my parents and teachers, and didn't have that many friends. Yeah, some things never change. However, I was usually lumped in, in terms of intelligence, with the "gifted" children, and the school (which was not well-funded!), sought out non-pharmaceutical solutions to my supposed problems. Now, this was the 1980s, so most of the drugs being prescribed to kids these days didn't exist, or if they did, it was never considered that they should be given to an 11 year-old child. Basically, the general gist in my case was "he'll grow out of it", or "If he keeps it up, someone will set him straight".</p>

<p>However, at no time were my supposed issues considered abnormal or irregular. If anything, the most my parents and teachers did was channel the energy into different areas where my spontaneity would be maximized. A child today who acted like I did, would be force-fed Adderall and told to get back to crunching away at math.</p>

<p>Joking and humor aside though, I managed to get through it and make the most of my mental attributes. I've never been to a therapist, and I've never been on a psychotropic regimen (I took Adderall once and it made me sick), and I manage to pay the bills, maintain a home, and have a social life inside and outside of my work. In other words, I'm in the ballpark with regards to most statistical norms in American society.</p>

<p>That being said, I do recognize my own mental quirks. I can't focus on something for more than ten or fifteen minutes at a time. My mind is always on fire in twenty different directions at once. Only if something truly engages me, can I get around this. For example, I can "zone out" and shoot for hours on end. I can write on subjects that interest me without deviating from the task. However, even with tasks I find pointless or uninteresting, if they need to get done, I'll get around to doing it by the time it needs to be completed. Usually.</p>

<p>I have a vague notion of time, and I question 95 percent of what crosses my path, so to speak. I'll deviate and spend an hour arguing with someone on how pointless something is. For example, a pet peeve of mine is people who take a hour to make a mundane decision, like, what to eat for lunch. My take on lunch or any meal is, "eat it and move on to the next thing...", since in my head, there's other things way more interesting than food. Give me a reasonably-healthy buffet or salad-bar style setup. I'd rather spend the time multitasking, i.e. I can eat and bang out a blog article, edit some photos, optimize some code, or be social. Food goes in one way, and it comes out another. Whoopee. I'm sure every foodie in town will want to kill me now.</p>

<p>I also have a hard time bringing people into my inner circle. I'm severely paranoid around new people. Though is it paranoia if they really are out to get you? But, with time, I'll bring people into the circle. Otherwise I'm pretty a pretty cold customer. Those who know me know the whole "sunglasses and 'I am smiling' " routine.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/09/30//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QNmbQuAgJE/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage0.s3.amazonaws.com/8b20b1280b3b11e2839c1231381b6c7e_7.jpg' alt='I am smiling.' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/lo-fi'>Lo-fi</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.849085,-80.15046864'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.849085,-80.15046864&markers=25.849085,-80.15046864&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Atlantic Broadband' /></a><br/>Taken at Atlantic Broadband</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='292058549993996868_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>Sidebar: I had to deviate from writing this article to derive the media_id of that Instagram photo. It took a minute or two since I saw something that caught my eye along the way. Which made me think of something else, a way of getting that ID without having to kick the Instagram API. Which brings me to my point.</p>

<p>My point is, is that my mental quirks make me who I am. I'm a paranoid, random sort of guy who can't focus on things for long periods of time and I'm always going off in twenty different directions at once. But, I believe it is those aspects of my personality which enable my creativity and ingenuity. If my parents, or later on, I myself, chose to medicate those quirks away, what would be left?</p>

<p>Basically another BlackBerry-wielding drone in the machine, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Listen, I'm no revolutionary. I fill out the forms when I have to, and I have "normal" things like bills and household chores and so forth. My life is actually pretty mundane sometimes. Though the point is, I was never medicated or told outright to stop acting a certain way. I figured it out as I went along, and I manage to maintain a semblance of a healthy existence, while still retaining the characteristics which make me who I am. All without the modifying effects of psychotropic medications.</p>

<p>And yes, I'm well aware that just about any substance consumed could be considered a mood-altering substance, but I'm certainly not dependent on any of them. I love my energy drinks but I don't require them to stay ahead. I'll get through the day. Comparing a Red Bull to an Adderall regimen is like comparing a 9mm round to a cluster bomb unit though. Same idea (boom), but a huge degree of difference in said boom.</p>

<p>Plus, beyond the poorly-understood detrimental health effects upon the children of our society caused by these substances, it's coaching society into a habit of medicating our mental quirks away. Already, there's generations of people my age and older who regularly medicate themselves to "stay ahead", and "stay competitive". And these habits are passed down to their children. In the pursuit of the almighty dollar, people drop a panoply of psychotropic medications on a scale to make the ghost of Elvis envious. College students deal in pharmaceuticals just to get that A on the final. Here's a clue on that, hotshot, the answers are usually found rather easily, and cheaper than scoring some of Merck's finest. Yes, I'm saying that you can pay off a TA to get the answer key, pretty much.</p>

<p>Now, don't get me wrong, I'm not condemning modern medicine. If I get shot or otherwise grievously injured, I want the best technology that the medical field can provide to patch me up and make me better. I'm just not so sure we should be medicating away our supposed mental quirks, since it seems that we, as a society, are bent on numbing and erasing the individual features of our psyche that make each and every one of us unique. Do we really all want to be on this statistical norm? Is the goal in life to tap away at Excel spreadsheets all day under the harsh glare of fluorescent lights? The paranoid part of me says that the overmedication of society is conditioning for just that. A pseudo-state of complacency found in pill form. Blissful ignorance, if you will.</p>

<p>Sure, society needs fiends tapping away at Excel and crunching numbers, but you know what? I've met people, whom I consider crazy, who legitimately get off on that sort of thing. Enough that even without medication, there's plenty of people who are motivated by their own personal thrill of solving a complex statistical problem in order to better optimize the interest rate on someone's savings account. There's enough "natural" accountants out there, is what I am getting at. I think we're all capable of harnessing our own mental quirks to our benefit, and neither we, nor our children, need to be doped up on Adderall all the time.</p>

<p>And, it's the crazy ones (yes, I know, I know, we've all seen the old Apple ads...) who are usually moving things forward for us as a society. Einstein wore the same outfit every day. Steve Jobs was a tyrant and yelled at people a lot, Leonardo was borderline anti-social, Van Gogh cut off his own ear. But these people left lasting positive impressions on society. If they had been medicated into submission, where would we be?</p>

<p>The long-term effects, beyond the physical, are that we are merely medicating away the effects of a sick society. We're not getting at the root causes of the pressure to use these medications, we're just merely masking the symptoms.</p>

<p>I'm not here to condemn anyone's use of any drug, legal or otherwise. It's your body, it's your choice. Just consider that you may be snuffing out what makes you unique in this world. I might be a whirlwind of random ramblings and crackpot schemes, but that's what makes me who I am. If I adhere to a statistical norm and toe the party line all the time, there's really no point in me, as a unique individual, in sticking around. And that, my dear small audience, is a fate worse than death.</p>

<p>Footnote: I'm not a medical professional, either. I'm just calling it like I see it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ramblings after the weekend...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08/ramblings-after-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T23:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/08/ramblings-after-the-weekend-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9386.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Still here at 9 AM?'" ></p>

<p>It was one of those random "on and off" weekends.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Much like any other mental factor, creativity seems to have a finite supply of sorts, and can be slow to replenish. Thursday, I shot a scenic I'm really proud of, the aptly-titled (yes, I'm totally being narcissistic here) "Where The Buses Don't Run".</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/outwhere_rev-8882.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'US 27 Northbound Broward County'" ></p>

<p>I did this on a Thursday night/Friday morning, and I did the editing and "mastering" work on Friday. When I intend to sell a print, I tend to nitpick. I'll obsess over minute color corrections, lens flares, and wish for things like my print provider accepting TIFF uploads on the off chance there's some minor compression artifacts which could be visible at a large enough print size.</p>

<p>Oh, and by the way, "Out Where The Buses Don't Run" is for sale on my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">Fine Art America</a> site, along with eight other pieces I consider potential sellers. I'm getting more and more into shooting nighttime scenics. Though I could do without the bugs in the Everglades. There was a mosquito in the 210 on my way home that night. The hardest part was concentrating on keeping steady at 130 km/h while hoping the little bastard would just go away. I did the "open all windows and go even faster" trick and that seemed to help.</p>

<p>That being said, I was fully intent on going back out to shoot more scenics on Friday, but that actually never panned out. I couldn't think of a location to scope out. I might try west this week, now that I think about it.</p>

<p>Saturday was my usual club night over at <a href="http://clubspace.com/">Space</a>. Two of my favorites, Chus + Ceballos, were on hand to provide an extended musical soundtrack to the evening. These guys "get it", they know they are there to keep the crowd moving, and they provide an excellent musical selection over the course of ten or more hours on the decks. Great guys in person, too. They're always game for the photo op, and they actually love to meet their fans. They <a href="http://www.dan-vidal.com/blog/2012/09/06/the-musical-ecosystem/">know their place in the musical ecosystem</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9091.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'That Nikon is like a periscope'" ></p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/08//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QiwaZHAgNP/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage3.s3.amazonaws.com/5be1081a11b011e2aeda22000a1de2e0_7.jpg' alt='Los Tios @chuslesteban @clubspacemiami @jhartlein @ppod @travisrogersmia More at http://seenightlife.com/users/pod/albums/chus-and-ceballos-return-to-space#5' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.784715407,-80.193181247'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.784715407,-80.193181247&markers=25.784715407,-80.193181247&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Club Space' /></a><br/>Taken at Club Space</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='298013445259920207_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>I still have to figure out how to derive that media_id without having to manually kick the Instagram API. If anyone knows how, let me know.</p>

<p>That being said, I definitely had "more creative energy" by that Saturday night. Some plans for early hours didn't materialize. I was supposed to attend a bachelor/bachelorette party at Scarlett's up in Hollywood, but the "confirmation" message never arrived that the people were actually gonna go. By then, it was 1:30 in the morning and I was already framing my mind from staring at desperate girls on the pole to actually doing something productive. So, I kind of said "the hell with it", jumped into a <a href="http://miami.car2go.com/">Car 2 Go</a>, and drove on over to Space.</p>

<p><p><a href='/blog/2012/10/07//' data-instagram-url='http://instagr.am/p/QeHL8FAgAh/' class='instagram-image'><img src='http://distilleryimage5.s3.amazonaws.com/88cd369e104511e2b7ea22000a1fc2ec_7.jpg' alt='Saddle up. @car2gomiami to @clubspacemiami' height='612' width='612' /></a><br/>Filtered with <a href='/blog/categories/normal'>Normal</a> through <a href='/blog/categories/instagram'>Instagram</a></p><!--more--><p><a href='http://maps.google.com?q=25.835181305,-80.182557106'><img border='0' src='http://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/staticmap?center=25.835181305,-80.182557106&markers=25.835181305,-80.182557106&zoom=14&size=612x200&sensor=false' alt='Talk Nightlife' /></a><br/>Taken at Talk Nightlife</p><p class='instagram-comment-holder'><a href='https://instagram.com/oauth/authorize/?client_id=082223ce4af44db2a4b0440fd98957c9&redirect_uri=http://www.dan-vidal.com/#access_token=31120127.082223c.33c03a5584f54c3494027e191a8d7b73&response_type=token&scope=likes+comments' id='296706232201379873_31120127' class='instagram-comment-link'>Sign in with Instagram to view Likes and Comments</a></p></p>

<p>Car 2 Go is saving me so much money in cab fare. It's amazing. Plus, they never thought of my use case until I told them. They posted on Facebook about using their service to get to the Brickell Oktoberfest party, and taking the safe way (a cab) home. Agalmic cowboy diplomacy.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9217.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Hi Jordyn'" ></p>

<p>Anyways, Space was the usual 'rock' of Miami nightlife this past weekend. Great atmosphere, an interesting crowd, and great music. It's not a trendy VIP club, and it doesn't aspire to be. In my mind it's the heart of Miami nightlife. It is one venue you can go to without even bothering to check their website to see who is playing. A friend of mine suggested that their marketing campaign should be "Space: We're fucking open."</p>

<p>I did my usual rounds at the venue, including switching out to the 50 1.2 L as the morning rolled on. It's a learning curve, but one I'm glad to participate in. It's a great lens and you can do amazing things with it wide open. Every Canon user should have it in their arsenal.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/lostios2012-9335.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Lucy I'm Home'" ></p>

<p>At 1.2, you will have throwaway images. Nature of the beast in a nightclub. Just keep shooting, but don't turn it into a Golden BB spray-and-pray affair. If the shot doesn't happen, it doesn't happen.</p>

<p>I left a little after 9 AM Sunday morning. I woke up Sunday afternoon, since I had a Keys trip planned, but the weather totally did not cooperate. I ended up turning around on the Turnpike Extension after a huge downpour kicked in, with more forecast for Monday. Though Monday turned out to be a rather nice day. Such is luck I guess.</p>

<p>I'll try to make it down again in the next few weeks. Maybe after Halloween Weekend.</p>

<p>Totally random weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Out Where The Buses Don't Run...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/05/out-where-the-buses-dont-run-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-05T15:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/10/05/out-where-the-buses-dont-run-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/outwhere_rev-8882.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'US 27 Northbound Broward County'" ></p>

<p>If you really want to get out into where it gets dark, you should probably head north and west along US 27 if you live or are shooting in the metropolitan Miami area...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It's definitely out where the buses don't run.</p>

<p><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/hIv-YaVBtA8 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>I miss Miami Vice.</p>

<p>You'll see a bit of the old South Florida when you get out that way. Before the sprawl and the overdevelopment.</p>

<p>This image was done with my 50 1.2 L. So far, so good. I'm definitely happy with the purchase. Prime lenses give you that extra five percent in overall image quality, and the 50 doesn't disappoint in this regard.</p>

<p>This is a 30 second exposure from the side of US 27 heading northbound just over the county line into Broward. There was a small amount of moonlight partially obscured by clouds. The rest is all ambient light, including airglow, the distant Miami city lights, and the lights of passing vehicles.</p>

<p>I'm sure the truckers were wondering what I was doing at 1:30 in the morning on the side of the road. Protip, bring a flashlight, and just point it at the ground when vehicles are coming close.</p>

<p>I'll be putting this one up for sale soon at my <a href="http://dan-vidal.fineartamerica.com/">FAA</a> site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I like Vimeo.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/i-like-vimeo/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T14:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/28/i-like-vimeo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="" height="" src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/46506653 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Vimeo is the superior video sharing platform, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Why?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It plays your content, and gets out of the way. Anything beyond that is up to you.</p>

<p>And yes, the plugin works.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
