<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: randomness | DV Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/categories/randomness/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-09-06T19:48:01-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dan Vidal - Pod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dan@dan-vidal.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the premise of exclusivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/on-the-premise-of-exclusivity/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T19:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/09/06/on-the-premise-of-exclusivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/ex.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'MK II overlooking Space'" ></p>

<p>Over the years, a lot of people have been under the mistaken assumption that I've been the "exclusive" photographer for venues and events I've worked with.</p>

<p>I don't enforce or expect exclusivity, and here's why...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>At the root of it all, I'm only one person. I can only be in so many places within a venue at once, especially if it's a large scale venue such as Space. I'll be upstairs on the Terrace, but the Loft might be uncovered, or the Ballroom. There isn't money in the budget to clone me.</p>

<p>Also, the fact that photographers prior to me didn't enforce exclusivity with their venue clients was an enormous boost to me being able to do what I do today. If they hadn't left that door open, I might not have been as far along as I am today. However, back when I got started, the position/gig of "club photographer" was a rare one indeed. More on that in a minute.</p>

<p>And, if I were a large-scale venue manager/owner, and I had it in the budget, I would definitely want multiple photographic perspectives on what was going on that evening. Each and every person who picks up a camera has their own thoughts and ideas on how an image should come out, and it is a definite advertising boon to have those multiple perspectives represented. And in the case of email-harvesting sites posing as photo sites, the venue gets multiple sources of data. I don't necessarily approve of the tactic, but it is what it is, and if I were a venue owner or manager, I would avail myself of a few of those sites.</p>

<p>Finally, to be honest, enforcing exclusivity and being "the guy" is a real <em>pain</em>. You're expected to be everywhere at once, cover the event exactly in the style the client wants, which may not be your style, and the task of club photographer rapidly turns from a fun profession to a "job", i.e. something you have to do to make money. And, frankly, I can think of many healthier activities that aren't fun to do at all, that would earn me the same money or more that I do documenting the nightclub scene. I do it primarily because I love to do it, and the financial benefits are just the icing on the cake. You don't see people clamoring to spend thousands of dollars on camera equipment just to take it into a smoke-filled room with loud music and sloppy drunk people because it's a job.</p>

<p>However, the situation today could be regarded as a little different. Since I got started, the position of club photographer has gone from a rare job description, to one of almost ubiquity. Often, the last thing a party would consider is booking a photographer to document an event. It was usually a "6 PM on the night of the event" request, if they thought about it at all. Of course the internet changed that.</p>

<p>Now, if you throw a party at a club, it's expected that you will have at least one or two guys on hand to document the event. However, some venues tend to go a little overboard, thinking any exposure is good, and let any guy with an SLR and an excuse into the venue. With the modern set of circumstances in mind, I'd at least require that the shooter have a full-fledged website (and not just a Facebook page or Flickr gallery) with which their images were to be posted. And, I'd probably cap the amount of shooters within a venue to a certain amount to avoid "shooting gallery" syndrome where there is, in fact, ten or more shooters in a venue. So, exclusivity on one person, not so much, but not overkill like some places are now. Especially if you add in everyone with their iPhones blazing away. But that's for another rant.</p>

<p>If you're in the club shooting world, keep shooting. Don't expect or enforce exclusivity though, it's not practical and definitely not in the spirit of things. There's enough subject matter for all (well, most) of us.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I guess I am becoming a car guy?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/31/i-guess-i-am-becoming-a-car-guy/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-31T15:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/31/i-guess-i-am-becoming-a-car-guy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/210hella960.jpg" width="960" height="360" title="'210 Hella'" ></p>

<p>I took my E320 "the 210" in for some service at the excellent locally-owned repair shop, <a href="http://masterclassauto.com/">Masterclass Automotive</a> this morning. I got the headlamp lenses swapped for spanking new Hellas and some odd DTC codes diagnosed.</p>

<p>A year or so ago, I didn't know what a DTC code was and I sure as hell didn't care. Am I becoming a 'car guy'?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Those who have known me for more than a few months know, that for the longest time, I was a dedicated bus rider/taxicab user. I had a monthly Metropass (superseded by the Easy Card) for over ten years. Not out of any sense of financial restriction (well OK at some points of time, yes...), but more out of a sense of convenience.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/thebus.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'The Bus'" ></p>

<p>However, during my temporary exile to Vegas, I was pretty much forced into getting a personal vehicle. Vegas has public transport, but it only covered about 30 percent of the valley, and even then only during daytime hours. Forget about nighttime buses.</p>

<p>At first, AMG was kind enough to provide me with a rental for the times I was actually on the ground in Vegas. It was a serviceable Ford Focus, and did the job as it were. But spending $2K+ a month to give me wheels didn't quite fit their budget, so after my Tiësto tour gig and prior to me running out the lease in Vegas, I had to acquire my own vehicle. A few options presented themselves, most notably of which was the vehicle I now own, the Mercedes E320.</p>

<p>Now, not being a car expert as it were, I had to call on some assistance to evaluate the purchase. So, I called on a friend of mine out there who owned a shop, to help me evaluate the Benz. In not so many words, it turned out to be a gem. It ran stable and was a good performer for the price, and he left it at "If you don't buy it, I will...". So, sold! I was suddenly a Mercedes owner.</p>

<p>However, as it is an older vehicle, I was advised to get it serviced and any minor repairs dealt with. I guess this is where my inherent geekiness kicked in. Whenever I purchase a new device, be it a camera, lens, phone, laptop, hard drive, or whatever, I research the hell out of it. I look for the obvious pros and cons, and also any tweaks, upgrades, hacks, and tricks to getting the most out of the device.</p>

<p>But, I guess I never considered a car as being a "device". Suddenly, this whole new world opened up to me. DTC codes, OBD-II ports, chassis numbers, ECU patches and upgrades, tire ratings, curb weights, bus voltages, optimal ranges for RPMs, fuel efficiency, horsepower, etc. It was like dissecting a computer component but there's moving parts and physics to call into account too. I guess I got hooked. And, from a pure tech perspective, it's great. I actually enjoy the research and the challenge of keeping the W210 up to spec and beyond.</p>

<p>Sidebar: Mercedes, like other manufacturers, typically assigns chassis numbers to certain classes of vehicles. For example, the W210 chassis encompasses the model years 1998-2002 and specifically the E320, E430, E300 turbodiesel, E55 AMG, and a few other models. Most enthusiasts of the brand refer to their cars by the chassis number in addition to the model number. Total geek thing.</p>

<p>But anyways, I guess my inherent need to break something down into it's components and see how it all works comes into play. I found out that the headlamp lenses could be replaced, for example. And yes, the more you know, the more you can save by doing things yourself or getting a good lead on what the mechanic will be doing. Each headlamp lens I had swapped in this morning was $85.00 as opposed to $300.00 for the entire housing if I just went with a dealer.</p>

<p>I also actually plan on getting an OBD-II dongle which interfaces with my iPhone. More stats and numbers to obsess over.</p>

<p>And I guess somewhere along the way I started becoming a "car guy". It's a fun diversion.</p>

<p>Now, of course I'm smart about it. I really only drive when I have to, and I still avail myself of public options when it's convenient or safe to do so, hence my retaining of my Easy Card and having a Car 2 Go membership. Keeping those options around (I switched my Easy Card to "refill when needed") doesn't cost any money unless you use it, so it's nice to have a "B" and "C" option, and a "too cheap to ride a cab and am going out for a drink or five" option too.</p>

<p>So, some of the "old Pod" still remains. Go figure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One of the things that makes it worthwhile.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/28/one-of-the-things-that-makes-it-worthwhile/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T21:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/28/one-of-the-things-that-makes-it-worthwhile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/thanx.png" width="258" height="280" title="'Thanks!'" ></p>

<p>Like I've stated before. I don't really do what I do with the end-goal of money in my sights. Having money is nice, and certainly has it's benefits in today's society, but I've found along the way that if your driving force is solely the acquisition of it, and the conspicuous consumption of it, it will corrupt. I've seen some really good people turn into <em>raging assholes</em> because of it. Or just plain old douchebags. Pardon my language.</p>

<p>I do what I do because I really love to do it. Photo work, video work, and the occasional web project keep me happy and put food on the table, and allow for a balance in my life to spend with friends and family. I don't expect any sort of accolade or reward.</p>

<p>But occasionally they do come in.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I tend to laugh off social networking as a diversion and, at the business level, a potential waste of resources. The most successful businesspeople in the world that I personally know and know of didn't build their empires by posting Facebook posts and ads, but they did it pretty much by turning out a good product or service. Yes, you gotta get the word out, but the business will come to you after that initial push.</p>

<p>But, anyways, I was talking about social networking, not business. Oh, by the way, I don't have much in the way of business acumen. I can tell you what camera or computer to buy, but beyond that, you're on your own.</p>

<p>Social networking, right. Yes, it's mostly a diversion and a front for large-scale data mining that would make the KGB envious, but sometimes it does have it's moments.</p>

<p>Like tonight. The person in the Facebook chat window above friend-requested me earlier this evening. Now, I didn't quite recognize this person off the bat, but we had enough mutual known friends for me to theorize that we had met at some point in the past. So, I figured I would "clear" this person and take it from there. If they proved to be a spammer or an unscrupulous promoter, it would take all of five seconds to screen them. Facebook does do things right on occasion.</p>

<p>About a few minutes later, the above message came through. I was out on a run and unfortunately the person was offline by the time I got back, so realtime communication wasn't possible. However, at the risk of being sappy, that did make my night. Again, I don't expect awards or accolades for my work, but when they come in completely unsolicited, it does make my day.</p>

<p>Thank you kind semi-stranger. You made my night.</p>

<p>OK, back to my scheduled ranting and raving.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So much for Isaac.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/28/so-much-for-isaac/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T00:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/28/so-much-for-isaac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/isaacgram.jpg" width="612" height="612" title="'Isaac Weekend'" ></p>

<p>I think this past weekend was a good example of what I've heard some people refer to as a "South Florida Snow Day"...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As I alluded to in the last post, Tropical Storm (and potential future hurricane) Isaac popped up on the South Florida cultural radar this past week. The usual cautionary tales ensued, with speculation turning to preparation on Thursday and Friday. Friday, the rain started to show up, with Saturday becoming a complete washout.</p>

<p>By Saturday night though, it appeared Isaac would only be a low-grade tropical storm, and the worst of it was to miss South Florida entirely, and veer through the Keys and out into the Gulf. But, the machinery of closures was already in motion. It definitely reminded me of the snow days growing up...</p>

<p>I grew up in the Northeast. As such, we had snow days when I was in school. If a storm happened, often the roads would be rendered dangerous, and as we were a walking/drive-your-kids-to-and-from-school district (only the special needs kids got buses), it was considered a liability to have kids out and about going to and from school in the event of a snow emergency. So, early in the morning of the day of the storm, the powers that be over at the school district HQ, would decide to declare a snow day, or not. They sometimes erred on the side of caution, choosing to close the district even if the accumulation wasn't that bad. So, there'd be three inches of snow on the ground (a laughable amount), and school would be closed.</p>

<p>Much like yesterday (Monday) with regards to Isaac. I woke up Monday morning, and was surprised to see the sun was out. However, the day prior, Sunday, was a complete rain event, as they say, and the governments and major businesses had already called off their Monday operations. I guess in the case of government, it's hard to recall a shutdown. However, it did rain a lot Monday afternoon, and I think it was a much-needed day off for a lot of people, personally. Though with remote work capabilities and telecommuting, the economy probably didn't suffer too much.</p>

<p>I think it was as close to a perfect situation in terms of disruption as you can get though. Enough rain came around to cause government and big business to shut down, but not so much as to engender widespread devastation and chaos. In practical matters, people got time off, and South Florida's party machine kicked into action over the weekend. It was "slow", of course, but most bars and nightclubs had enough business to justify staying open. I wonder what that says for society when we'll go through hell and high water to get drunk? Probably that we spend too much time at work, personally. But, that's another blog rant.</p>

<p>The party machine around was definitely active, with the events I attended at Chalk on South Beach, and of course Space in Downtown Miami, being heavily attended.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/classics-3797.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Space Classics'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/fuji-3505.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'Chalk'" ></p>

<p>I've been through a few rain events and hurricanes, and despite the threat of damage and destruction, I've always kind of liked the atmosphere at hurricane parties. Plus, nothing beats exiting a venue and realizing, rather dimly, that you probably should get home and see about getting things situated in case the storm really does come. I remember when Hurricane Wilma, the last storm of any significance to come through South Florida directly, came through in October of 2005. I was living on Normandy Isle in the northern part of Miami Beach at the time in a fairly rattletrap (Sorry Su, it's true...but we had fun!) apartment building, and I got around via public transport or taxis. I had shot an event with Sander Kleinenberg at Space earlier, and made my usual late exit from the venue that Sunday morning. Of course, I had heard reports that this pesky storm might just come for us, but didn't give it much thought. I had gotten home, checked a few reports, most of which centered on "Yes, it's coming for Miami, but at what strength we don't know...", and passed out to sleep. I woke up about eight hours later to the sounds of my roommate and his friend stocking up for the storm. Apparently it was close, as we lost power a few hours later. Fortunately we had enough random provisions to get through the next few days, but for a minute it was kind of tense as we had no "real" food.</p>

<p>I'm a little more responsible nowadays, I think. I have a few gallons of water on hand and a FIVESTAR account with hotels.com. And I keep an eye on my iPhone during potential hurricane periods. If things look ugly, I'll prebook a hotel inland and north and get out of town. Might not be the most entertaining course of action, but fortunately I'm mobile. I can fit everything important to me (gear, data, and some clothes) into my trunk. And if the storm is a non-event, I can come back home.</p>

<p>It might not work for you though. Don't blame me if it doesn't.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruising South Florida.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/25/cruising-south-florida/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-25T11:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dan-vidal.com//blog/2012/08/25/cruising-south-florida</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets.jpg" width="960" height="960" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p>Apparently there's a hurricane on the way. Or a tropical storm at the most. It's the usual subdued panic in South Florida. Yes, I'm aware that even a tropical storm can cause damage, and it's always better to be safe than sorry, but if the news media is to be believed, Armageddon is upon us.</p>

<p>It made for a very low-key Friday night, that's for sure. And today is shaping up to be more of the same.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Which is actually OK with me. I like to kick back and relax and do what I want rather than what I need to do. And one of those things is cruising around and shooting the deserted streets at night. In my mind, it's similar, in a way, to the scenics and landscapes I've been shooting lately. There's definitely an interesting juxtaposition with the works of humanity in the photo, but humanity itself isn't present.</p>

<p>And last night made that easy. No one was out, anywhere. I ostensibly drove north on the express lanes in I-95 to try out a new set of tires I put on the W210 earlier in the day. Bridgestone RE970s if anyone is curious. And in the rain at cruising speed, they stuck to the road like glue, even at "autobahn" speeds of 130 kph...around 81 mph or so.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://distilleryimage5.instagram.com/e1e54fdeee6a11e1829522000a1e88aa_7.jpg" title="'I-95 NB Express'" ></p>

<p>Of course I had my gear on me, since I intended on getting off the beaten path and shooting some deserted streets. From Downtown Fort Lauderdale to Washington Avenue on South Beach to Wynwood in Miami, it was a quiet Friday night. There were small bursts of activity here and there, but it was definitely a slow night. Which suited me just fine. I captured some excellent deserted street scenes.</p>

<p>One of the challenges, of course, was keeping my camera dry. I kind of forgot about that. However, I improvised with a plastic bag from my trunk and a musty old t-shirt to wipe away any condensation. And even though I had my trusty Manfrotto tripod with me, I handheld all of my images from the past evening. ISO 3200 and 6400. Don't fear the noise.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3454.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3462.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3473.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/dvblog/streets-3476.jpg" width="960" height="640" title="'The Streets of SFL'" ></p>

<p>Driving Washington Avenue was fun. I drove from 5th Street to Lincoln, and marveled at all the shuttered nightclub spaces. It's really the subject of another rant, but it's amazing to see the huge seasonal turnover in nightclubs on the Beach. You think these guys would realize there's only three big players in town and only so many people to go around.</p>

<p>Anyways, it was a successful street scene shooting session. This wasn't commercially motivated, it was all "just for me". I think in the quest to stay solvent, a lot of photographers forget to go out and shoot what they want in addition to what they need to shoot. Though a fortunate few can shoot what they want and it fills their needs quite nicely. Regardless, shooting what you want is definitely recommended. It's relaxing if anything. Strip your kit down to what you need (again, don't fear the noise), get out there, and press the shutter button.</p>

<p>Be safe out there, South Florida.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
